[Music]
most entrepreneurs part of our life is a
spinning just pure panic and fear
and one of the things that I think
really propelled Thomas in the early
days was this story was so unique it was
really radical Tom's has now given away
over 80 million shoes to children around
the world we literally had created karma
by setting out to do something to help
people
first just trying to make money
[Applause]
well we're so glad to be here about 12
years ago myself and some friends here
in Los Angeles started this company
called Tom's and we make shoes and I
think some of you have received our
shoes before and we're gonna give you
some more shoes today and what makes our
business unique is every time we sell a
pair of shoes we also give a pair of
shoes we're excited to be here on your
very first day and let's have some fun
okay where are we going now we're gonna
get some shoes new shoes okay let's do
it I'm Blake I'm Blake I'm Blake do any
good new pair of shoes today so you take
these off and I'm gonna measure your
foot and then figure out what size I've
been on giving trips all of the world
Vanuatu Mala and Peru and Rwanda
throughout the United States and the
southeast and outside of New York City
have I've never actually done a giving
trip or a giving day in Los Angeles
where we started a company thank you sir
okay we're gonna try these new shoes on
LA best is an amazing organization that
we've been partnering with for quite
some time now
that's community based and you know I
think here being in LA is really great
and also again you know I'm powering
kids we had so much fun giving you shoes
and then really playing thank you for
being such amazing kids and we'll look
forward to the next time we get to come
play with you
[Music]
[Applause]
there was definitely an entrepreneurial
kind of gene in my body growing up but
it was more channeled into being a
competitive tennis player my whole kind
of life from age about eleven to
eighteen was focused on tax like I mean
I was just like obsessed
he has always she's done it on his own
when he was a little boy used to ride
his bike to the tennis court every day
after school and hit on the backboard
but I think after my freshman year in
college my dad was kinda like okay at
some point you gotta learn to work like
a tennis is great but I don't think
you're gonna be the next Andre Agassi he
said you got to get a summer job I was
talking to someone about this new kind
of frustration and whoever I was talking
to said well you know I would love for
you to teach my son tennis you know and
I'm happy to pay you something that we
pay at the local club or whatever and
that's kind of my first entrepreneurial
thing I ever did I basically went to
Kinko's made flyers and like within the
next week I was fully booked up and I
was making like you know hundreds of
dollars an hour to that multiple kids
paying $25 each and like far making
formal money ever would have waiting
tables and so my dad came home from work
that day and and he looked outside and I
was like out there my shirt off you know
like hitting balls the kids and stuff
and my mom was like baking cookies and
like giving the the parents like
refreshments and my dad's like what
happened to the summer job and she goes
yeah that's what that is a summer job
and he's like went and then I had this
discussion of my dad that night at
dinner and he couldn't argue with it
like and I think that's when you first
realized like I was gonna look at things
a little bit differently than the
traditional path if he picked something
he wanted to do he was gonna do whatever
necessary to make sure that you know he
did it well my sophomore year I had an
injury to my Achilles tendon
I had these crutches and very quickly I
realized that I literally couldn't do my
laundry and we were talking about this I
was like yeah I like Eric my roommate
was kind of you know give me a hard time
at all it's laundry everywhere and I was
telling his dad that there's no
workplace that does it and
that's it well you guys you know you
guys should start a laundry business but
a lot of kids assist me you don't want
to do mine and so the narak and I just
kind of took the idea and ran with him
and we started this thing called easy
laundry and we bought an old truck from
like a FedEx junkyard for like the 16
hundred bucks we only had maybe like 10
or 15 customers at first semester and so
we recognized that like we had to create
kind of this illusion that there were
more customers because no one wanted to
be first and so what we decided to do is
we basically every time we had to
deliver their laundry we basically
pretend we delivered it like six times
people think gosh see you guys
delivering laundry all time and I mean
we're being honest we weren't we were
delivering a laundry all the time we're
just living the same 15 people over and
over again then we started expanding it
to you know schools all across the
country I end up dropping out of school
because it was too much work to go to
school and doing this he is always doing
something but always looking to the
future of what the next big thing is
after three years I was just done I was
just exhausted I learned a lot it was
fun it was a great kind of
stepping-stone to everything else that I
went on to do but I was out so I sold my
50% of my partner and it still exists
today so I came out to Los Angeles you
know visit a friend that was I think
either going to UCLA or USC I forget and
I saw on the sides of buildings these
massive advertisements and every single
ad was either a TV show or a movie or
movie star and when I just being curious
I called one of the names of the
companies and I said you know I'm
curious like how much would it cost to
rent I kind of pretended like I had like
a startup and said yeah if I want to
rent for my company how much it cost to
rent one and they were saying something
like you know seventy thousand dollars a
month or something just crazy and I
thought how does this make sense and the
only way I could understand it or out my
it was all ego-driven so my kind of
hypothesis was is like where else in the
country could he have just big egos and
then again in kind of a specific
industry where this doesn't exist
and so I decided to move out to
Nashville because they didn't have this
type of advertising Nashville back then
was such a different town I mean it's
unrelatable to the town Nashville is now
national you knew everybody I mean some
new came to town you met him pretty
quick I spent you know about it almost a
year getting City Council to approve
this and ultimately the only way they
approved it was I called it country
music art you'd be driving down Broadway
and also knows this huge banner of the
Dixie Chicks right wow that's so cool
you know I was like promoting their new
album and those his idea who's ringing
the space on the sides of buildings and
using it to promote country music
artists oh and of course we all wanted
one once you saw that you're like oh I
wanna I want my picture up there one day
so when I was living in Nashville the
first season of Survivor came out and my
sister and I were successful show we
just thought it was like the coolest
competition and show and we both decided
to apply to Survivor and when we applied
to Survivor somehow and the millions of
tapes and stuff that they got a casting
director realized that we were brother
and sister both applying for Survivor
they couldn't put both of us on the show
but they had this new show called The
Amazing Race come out where they were
teams we were the youngest team on the
show I was 25 and Paige was 21 and after
31 days we lost the million dollars back
for minutes it was kind of crushing
defeat but at the same time it was one
of the best experience of my life and
something you have to do my sister and
brought us so close and and it kind of
opened my eyes not only to you know kind
of the world and some of the challenges
of the world and poverty and things that
I saw that I'd never seen before but it
also you know kind of introduced me to
Hollywood and Los Angeles
and as I was out here what was
fascinating to me is like people still
recognize us for quite a while after the
show is over and we would get like weird
invites like you know go to Will Smith's
kids birthday party because they were
fans of the show or something I mean
just like random stuff like that right
and so I at the same time I was watching
kind of the way culture was going and
these reality stars were becoming more
and more popular and so my idea was
pretty simple it's like okay let's take
like these people who are loving their
15 minutes of fame let's extend it and
let's like create like other content
around that and so I tried to start a
reality cable channel I ended up getting
a bunch of the winners of reality shows
to invest in it which was pretty awesome
so you know people who won survivor and
the guys who beat me on The Amazing Race
for writing the checks for hundreds of
thousands of dollars and it was an
incredible adventure I learned so much
unfortunately it was probably the worst
business financially I've ever done we
ended up losing all the money after
working on it for about three years and
largely just because we couldn't compete
with the big guys he's amazing at
course-correcting at being able to
recognize when something is not working
and people think these little lessons
along the way in a sense was my
education it was my MBA if you will or
my college education so when Tom's came
along and I had an opportunity that
looked really exciting I was able to
probably have less you know hit less
speed bumps less less wrong turns
because I've made so many already
[Music]
how many people seen The Amazing Race
raise your hand Oh lots of people time
people saw it when I was on it a long
time ago couple people okay when we were
closing down the reality Channel we're
having a barbecue we were there and one
of the women that I had worked for me
her son was like 15 years old and he was
there and I asked him I said what are
you doing this summer and he said oh man
I gotta do driver's education he's like
yeah he's like old lady teacher and the
cars suck and this that and so I was
just thinking like for a second as I was
talking to him this is just such a
mismatch of like what should be his
experience than the experience he's
having we created the first online
driver's education business just based
off that conversation like the next day
I called someone and found someone that
was in the in the in the classroom space
and said hey let's get you out of that
let's do this first thing we did is hire
all the Abercrombie & Fitch models when
they're not doing their modeling or
acting auditions to drive cars now a
sudden like every single kid in the
school wants to sign out so it was a
pretty interesting thing by changing one
little thing how we went from like not
even being a player to like the dominant
leader in LA and driver's education I
think when you first meet him it was
easy to sort of think oh well maybe this
is a guy who inherited a bunch of money
and this is a fun thing for him and he
just wants to you know sort of travel
around the world and sort of check stuff
out I had no idea what his background
was and how he'd become a self-starter
in his own right
in 2006 I ended up going down to
Argentina and at the reason I went to
Argentina was one we had been there on
The Amazing Race but to here in LA I had
started taking pole lessons and it was
something I'd always wanted to learn how
to do I grew up in Texas riding horses
so I'm and and I always thought it would
be like a fun like it looks like such as
like an intense exciting sport so I went
into Google I typed in polo camp comma
cheek because I didn't have much money
to spend on it but he came to my place
because we were the cheapest so he came
to sustain in the place by the polo
fields and we every day playing polo to
innocence and having fun and they had a
very Argentine nonchalant like hey we'll
play when you want to play well lunch to
anyone would take lots of naps I felt so
connected from the first moment we were
like we could do something together and
enjoying and every time I were thinking
something he was thinking kind of the
same about two or three weeks into my
trip I was in this cafe in Buenos Aires
kind of wine bar and I was by myself and
I heard some women at the bar talking in
English which was nice because most
people were speaking Spanish and I
didn't expand I kind of pulled up a bar
stool and you know and kind of introduce
myself and they told me that they were
doing volunteer work where they were
going around different parts of the
wealthier parts of points I was
collecting shoes from people and they
were taking him to this area outside of
Buenos Aires were me and the kids needed
shoes and so you know I always like new
experiences and and and so I kind of
invited myself along said hey I'm happy
to help you guys just should be the
shoes and if you know can I come with
you and they said great yeah sure met
back there like I don't know three or
four days later and they were going to
this one little area where this amazing
woman margarita had taken in all these
kids who had no one looking after them
and so I just spent the day you know
putting shoes on kids feet
than playing with him even to this day I
can close my eyes and remember that
first time and just like just how
ridiculously excited they were how
thankful their parents were I mean he is
a big thinking person but he's also
someone that you know likes to get his
hands dirty and that night when I got
back to the polo camp and I was telling
my teacher Alejo about it I was doing so
with great enthusiasm and but it was
interesting because he asked me a
question that night I say to him well
you know the brownie is like who's gonna
give him the next better so what we have
to do to continue doing this and and I
recognized that question that the that
was the problem with this kind of
nonprofit charitable giving model at
least in this situation was these women
has been weeks getting enough shoes it
would last these kids for a few months
like who's gonna give him the next pair
and I was there on the farm journaling
about my experience and about Elena's
question when I had the idea that led to
Tom's and that was really simple it was
like look what if I sold these really
cool shoes that I had only seen in
Argentina to my friends back in
California and every time I sold a pair
I would also make another pair to give
to one of these kids it just seemed like
the simplest idea in the world I mean in
some ways it was really more of like
this is just the easiest way to keep
track of this you know like instead of a
percentage or this or that it's like
look you can't mess this up you buy a
pair I give a pair I can keep track of
humpers I sell and I can keep track of
how many pairs you know we give and I
was gonna call tomorrow shoes but I
couldn't fit it there so I shortened it
to Tom's
Lake comes to this work from a
completely authentic place and what I
really admire about him is that he
decided at the very beginning this one
for one model this was just gonna be how
he built this business you know we were
in the shoe business before I have no
idea how to make sure it was all about
fashion
this guy Jose Torres was our original
manufacturer I guess you can call him or
craftsman and we convinced him to make
these shoes we made 250 pairs put them
in a couple duffel bags we bought it
like the Argentine footlocker I think
how they picked a flake on the chicken
taking the big bag that we bought in the
store with the 250 pairs of shoes to
ship they're actually back on American
Airlines and just try to start selling
them to friends and family and at that
time I don't think I could fully grasp
or anyone could Philippe grasp what
Tom's was
I had this dinner party in my apartment
about two weeks after I was back and I
invited basically kind of all the girls
I knew around Venice and to get their
thoughts about these shoes to find out
like what stores they think I could sell
a man lake you know was he was a serial
entrepreneur he you know he started all
these businesses but he didn't know
anything about fashion I mean it was
like so comical now that I think about
it like I had my duffel bag you know
walked in like I wanted to sell you
shoes so actually I I got like the
stone-cold deny not even even the
conversation in like five or six of the
stores that this girl had given me on
her list an American rag was the last
one he just brought up a few samples
that he had and I mean it was it's
really straightforward you know so it
just sounded like Hades or cool shoes
it's a great cause why not
she sold 80 something pairs of the 250
so that was a pretty big amount of my
inventory so I was pretty excited couple
days there I get a call from a writer at
the LA Times and she's like I'm gonna
write a little story about you and the
next Saturday were on the cover of the
calendar section in the LA Times we sell
twenty-two hundred pairs eighty five
thousand dollars and I only have 60
pairs in my apartment
I remember like taking a cab straight
from Buenos Aires to Jose's you know
house where he was like making them you
know one at a time in the garage and I
walked in with the article and I was
like the little Spanish I know I was
like muchos zapatos rapido and they
looked at me like what the first couple
of days I was in a customer service role
really calling back customers because we
had this crazy waitlist and crazy
interest in the product the funny thing
was is when I got back two days later I
get a call from Anna Wintour's office
Vogue magazine wanting to have me come
to New York to talk about Tom's and here
we were this small start-up with three
full-time employees if you count blake
in his apartment just trying to manage
all of the interest everyone you know
who read that article especially buyers
assumes we started getting calls from
you know Bloomingdale's Urban Outfitters
and Macy's and Barney's and all these
places even Bergdorf Goodman coming to I
mean it's crazy you have a great thing
called the shoe drop yes so what
happened was as an October we went back
we sold 10,000 pairs went back to
Argentina and we gave 10,000 children
shoes who've never had them the first
giving trip was I mean one of the
life-changing experience that mugen have
and so he asked a small group of friends
and family to go on this first giving
trip down to Argentina the Argentine's
the Americans get on this on this on
this crazy Greyhound buses that we
rented and so we would put the shoes and
the cargo components below the bus and
then we would literally driving even
sleep on the bus many nights from town
to town it was amazing I mean it was
super emotional and exciting and and we
didn't know we were doing but it just
felt so like Wild West and it was
yes and it was great to probably best
trip of my life Lily the first day I
walked into the surf shop door opens and
in luckily my now wife was working
behind the counter
[Music]
[Applause]
you know when I started tongs it was to
help a small group of people in a
village in Argentina I didn't have big
ideas or business plans it was just a
very simple idea the desire to help you
know one of the things that I think
really propelled toms in the early days
was the story was so unique it was
really radical so much my job was
travelling around the country just
telling the story universities and and I
would go do talks at Nordstrom and you
know we had an Airstream we traveled in
and like it was literally just like get
the story out there and that was like
job number one he's the man behind TOMS
shoes and call him a shoe CEO with a
soul and he is the chief shoe giver so
in 2009 I heard that I could sell the
rights to a book and get some
significant money
[Music]
and so I sold my my story in my book to
Random House and got a huge advance
which I used to fund the business but
then proceeded not to write the book
because that's too busy running the
business by the time of June 2010 came
along they gave me an ultimatum either
had to give back the money basically or
turn in a book by Labor Day and I'm
thinking I want to go somewhere where I
don't know anyone and I can just write
all day long and get this thing done and
so I went to Montauk New York and this
is before Montauk was like as popular as
it is now kind of a you know a little
bit sleepier town outside the Hamptons
great surfing which I loved
so that was my plan and the first day I
walked into the surf shop to get some
wax from my board and my now wife was
working behind the counter I remember I
was on Tom's website and I was like I
love this what this mission is about
companies about I have the shoes I went
to fi T I have a degree in advertising
marketing communications and it's like
how can I get a job at Tom's the next
morning I had to open up the surf shop
and first thing door opens and in walks
Blake and so I went up through the cash
register and she said you think I
started Tom's and she said I literally
was just on the website because I want
to move to California and I was gonna
apply for a job and so I was like this
is my Inn so I was like yeah I mean I
could probably help you with that I got
the job obviously and moved to
California and she worked at Tom's a few
more years until we got engaged and
today she still has a active involvement
with his toms animal program she helped
start it's proving to be a great like
conversational piece with our consumer
and to really get them engaged in a
level of awareness for the endangered
species
you know we're done that down in Mexico
just you know having fun and sorry
friend and he's like you know I really
think it's time to start another one for
one product we're about to introduce the
next one for one product which is inside
this great mystery box and we start
talking about it and you know he was
like what about eyewear and I said you
know Jonathan would you would you think
he designs sunglasses I mean design
amazing clothes you know and no Tom's
that I trust your aesthetic I definitely
saw the value in and we started started
talking about it and obviously the need
on
you know sight is huge my extreme
pleasure today introduced Tom's eyewear
with every pair purchased TOMS will help
give sight to a person in need
one for one you know giving someone a
pair of shoes is one thing but giving
site is as another thing it was crazy to
me to think here Here I am in Los
Angeles California doing my day to day
job and I am impacting someone's life in
a mountainside in the Himalayans and
this person is going to be able to see
their children for the first time we're
seeing that even though we started in
shoes and moved to eyewear that our
customers are excited about being able
to make a difference with their morning
cup of joe as we wanted to create more
economic development opportunities in
the countries we give in like Guatemala
Honduras he Opia Malawi we realized that
one of the biggest industries there was
coffee for every cup of coffee of a day
of cleaned out or for someone and we
literally had created karma if you will
by you know really setting out to do
something to help people first just
trying to make money
[Music]
you know I couldn't woke up in early
2014 and largely just felt overwhelmed
lonely and super stressed because now
went from being super fun like startup
environment so we have a half a billion
dollar business people are depending on
us now I take my hat off to him to
understand the business had reached a
certain place and then it now needed
needed a bit more than what he was even
capable he would say was capable of
doing on his own I spend a lot of time
talking to a lot of private equity firms
ultimately did a deal with Bain Capital
I sold 50% of the business which is a
very unique number actually in that type
of deal making when the investment came
in that was so sizable he already knew
what to do he knew in his heart and soul
what to do and he and Heather together
have been building a real understanding
about what it means to be very
successful for him to make the decision
that he was ready was really brave of
him and it was the right choice lake has
this ability to always see the glass
half-full and somehow it always is when
we had this big liquidity event I talked
to my wife as I look we're never gonna
spend all this money so let's take half
of it and and dedicate it to investing
in social entrepreneurs and if we make
good investments then that fund will get
bigger and bigger and then long after
we're gone this will exist to help you
know social entrepreneurs for a very
long time as more and more young
entrepreneurs want to integrate purpose
at the beginning of their
entrepreneurial journey they look up to
Blake as somebody who is a pioneer in
that it's fun to see these early-stage
entrepreneurs
have been somewhat inspired by Tom's
when to create businesses aren't just
there to make money but to really have
social benefit and and that's something
I think I'll do the rest of my life
[Music]
you