for the next 40 days, for 20 minutes in
the morning and 20 minutes in the
evening, you're going to set a timer and
you're going to take your fingers and
your thumbs and you're going to close
your eyes and you're going to say, "I'm
enough. I've always been enough. I am
enough. I've always been." And you're
going to do that. And after 40 days,
we're going to check in and I have a
feeling you're going to feel totally
different.
>> Wait, when's the last time I saw you? A
couple years, huh?
>> It has been a long time and a hell of a
journey for me.
Yeah. So, well, Blake, welcome to the
show.
>> Thanks.
>> I am notorious for um starting
conversations with no point, especially
with people that I have met. And [music]
I I've uh I'm trying to, you know, start
that. So, I have to admit, so I I think
I met you what, 8 10 years ago, maybe?
>> Yeah. 10 years ago.
>> Okay.
>> In the pool.
>> In the pool. Great place to meet. you
know, you're everybody's vulnerable and
you're in your bathing suits and uh at
that time. Well, maybe you can just
share because I think leading people up
a little bit to this to your journey.
>> Yeah.
>> Um to to your your not your your enough
project that you're working on now is is
fascinating because obviously in doing
homework I didn't realize that uh before
Tom's you know you you were do you're
like a serial entrepreneur even from
college. So maybe you could just share
your just your journey.
>> I was an athlete growing up. I wanted to
be a professional tennis player. I lived
at one of the tennismies where you get
you go where you basically train all day
long and just do a little bit of school.
Um I went to SMU on tennis scholarship
was a you know top 20 uh in you know
division one school for tennis. I had an
injury my sophomore year that really
changed my life. Um, I hurt my Achilles
tendon and I was told that I wouldn't be
able to play for about six months. Um,
and my whole life was tennis. I mean, I
played, you know, all day every day
since I was 10 years old. And um, it was
interesting because because of that
injury, I um had this problem with my
laundry and which is sounds kind of
random, but what happened was is the
laundry facility was at the bottom of
the dorm. And in order to get it to the
bottom, I had to be able to carry it.
And because I was on crutches, I
couldn't carry my laundry. And so my
laundry was piling up and piling up in
the room. And my roommate was a little
annoyed because it was a mess. And we
were at home at Thanksgiving with his
dad. And his dad was an entrepreneur, a
word I did not know the definition of at
the time. And we were talking about how
I couldn't do my laundry and how just
doing laundry in general was a pain. and
his dad knew that we went to a private
school where people had disposable
income. And he said, "You guys should
start a laundry business and do
everyone's laundry."
And we kind of looked at each other and
we that's kind of interesting. And we
asked his dad some questions about
entrepreneurship and next thing you
know, we scraped together 1,500 bucks.
We bought an old FedEx FedEx truck and
we painted on the side easy laundry. and
I came back and started a laundry
business.
>> Your parents, I mean what what's cuz I
think you know and you know this having
children it's like you realize also how
how much of us are are sort of born a
certain way and if you if you're unsure
um either you know have children or you
know just look at a couple people you
know and you go you know they shouldn't
have come out of that environment. How
how did your parents take that? You
know, the laundry business at first was
I just kind of a side project while I
was still doing school. So that was fine
then.
>> And then after about six months, it
caught on like wildfire at our school
and every kid was like, "Why am I doing
my laundry?" And we started getting
calls and started having to hire people.
We had to buy a second truck. And so at
the end of that semester, I called my
dad who was a doctor, you know, went to,
you know, you know, very well educated
medical school. Um, and I said, "Hey,
Dad. Um, I think I'm gonna take a year
off college to grow this laundry
business because I'm having a lot of fun
and we have tons of customers and
there's no way I can go to school and do
this. And at the same time, I'd already
talked to my tennis coach and basically
said like and then he was really
encouraging because I was like the last
guy on the team. I mean, even though I
was a great junior player, I wasn't good
enough to be, you know, a top player in
college. And he said, "I think this is a
great idea." like I mean what an
opportunity for you to you know do
something and he was very
entrepreneurial as well. So I had his
support called my dad and that was one
of the defining moments in my life. I
really expected my dad to be like what
the hell like you know like you're at
this great university you know and he
said I think it's a great idea. He's
like take a year off have fun do it like
let's see what happens. And it was like
one of those moments that I hope that I
have those conversations with my kids
and they have a similar story on a
podcast someday because I'm so proud of
him and I'm so grateful and I think
that's been a big part of my belief in
myself as an entrepreneur is that you
know he had that response which most you
know very well educated doctors their
firstborn would probably not have.
>> Yeah. Firstborn son no less.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's funny because you and
your sister are both um entrepreneurs.
So, it's Yeah, it's
>> it's pretty fascinating to see that. So,
how I was thinking about what it would
be like to be in a college town and then
have been on a tennis team, which is
like a pseudo family, and then part of
the student body, and then saying,
"Okay, I'm I'm not going to do that
anymore."
Did it taking that time off and working,
did it make you feel sort of like, oh, I
want to put my teeth into life? Did it
make you feel outside of things? What
was that sort of unusual space that
happened pretty quickly?
>> Well, it was it was interesting because
I wasn't in school, but I was picking up
and delivering people's [laughter]
laundry every day. So, I was like I
mean, you know, um you know, it was it
was interesting. I was still going to
the bars at night and I was still being
social. It just instead of class I was
doing laundry while my friends were
doing class and all the, you know, kids
from SMU or a lot of them are or come
from, you know, kind of pretty wellto-d
do families. And so they were kind of
like, what the hell are you doing? Why
do you want to do people's laundry? Like
this is like they just did not get it.
But I was bit with the entrepreneurial
bug. I think it was very similar to my
training in tennis because it was
competitive. You know, I had to work
hard. It was I was, you know, I had I
had a partner, but I was, you know,
still the two of us were pretty, you
know, on our own. And I just loved it. I
mean, I think I was born to be an
entrepreneur. I mean, I started six
companies and I'm in the process of
starting three more right now. So, um,
you know, like I I think that was just
like, you know, what I was made to do.
And once I clicked into it, I loved it.
And it didn't matter that my fraternity
brothers made fun of me or that the
girls were concerned in the sorority
that I was seeing their panties or
whatever. Like it I just I was just like
I'm doing this and I'm making money. I
mean that was fun. I'd never made money
before. So because I never had time for
a job because I was always training in
tennis, you know, you know, and so it
was a great experience. And then it led
to other businesses, you know, some
successful, some not, you know, you
know, and I started five companies
before I started Tom Shoes. And I was
what 29 when I started Tom Shoes. But I
had already been an entrepreneur for 11
years.
>> What about the identity part now do you
because it's so interesting when people
come from sports you know that is ends
up being such a heavy duty identity but
you switched over pretty quickly to put
you know to focus on something else. Do
you think it was less about the identity
and more about having a place to like
you said earlier like oh I have to work
hard I have to be strategic I need to um
you know I have deadlines there's
pressure I'm wondering if that
transition made it a lot easier for you
because you had been doing tennis for so
long
>> I think two things I do think it was
switching one identity for another
>> and I think as we'll get in later to
some of the challenges I've had in my
life and some of the suffering I've had.
>> I actually now look back at it and see
that I was really craving that external
validation that comes from having a
public identity because for all my life
I was known as the great tennis player
and then I was known as the young
entrepreneur. Like everyone, you know,
the business school knew about me. There
was articles in the paper, you know,
there was all that. like even though my
fraternity brothers didn't think it was
cool, a lot of people thought it was
pretty remarkable that I had built this
business and you know when I was 18
years old. So I think a lot of it was
chasing that external validation. It's
so interesting. They don't talk to I
mean I think people do talk to their
kids about trying to figure out that
relationship with ourselves and letting
that be the governing. And I just think
it's it's really hard for most of us to
avoid
um until until we're adults, you know,
to really go, wait a second, why am I
really doing this? So, and and yours got
prolonged because you crushed it. So you
do Tomms um and and do that and it's not
only is it the success the success of
the business but it's also you know
people celebrating
what's behind the business and like
you're a good guy and you know kind of
all that part of it that's like even I
think
>> at least for me it would be I mean for
some people they'd be like yeah you know
keep your compliments I'll take the
money but I I think for someone like you
who from what little I know you feel
very sensitive to to me that it was like
that might have been maybe as powerful
as selling your company.
>> Oh, way more powerful. And that's why I
suffered so much after I sold it because
it was never about the money. None of
the businesses were about the money. It
was about doing something, you know, and
then it was about helping people with
Tom's. I mean, we gave a hundred million
children shoes in almost every country
in the world. And so every day I I
created the perfect It's interesting
like I I literally created for someone
who has a core wound of not feeling
enough. I created the perfect cocktail
to numb that wound, you know, because it
wasn't just the business accolades and
being on the cover of Inc. magazine or
Fortune magazine. It was, you know,
getting recognized at the White House
for being a public servant, you know,
and and then it was the beautiful
children in Guatemala that like lit up
when we gave him shoes. So I, you know,
I mean, you know, whatever side of our
psyches or however we want to describe
it psychologically, I adapted really
well to, you know, pacify this this
wound for a long time.
>> Do you like when you're in the moment?
cuz I mean listen I've had imposttor
syndrome you know even playing sports or
just other things where uh you know
every I think most people experience it
on some level when you were at Tom's I'm
so curious like were you were you able
to witness kind of you know when you
step outside of yourself and you go oh
you know I'm I'm getting this other this
attention because it's so interesting to
get a lot of attention for doing good.
Yeah.
>> And that's what people don't realize.
Like you think that that would be easy,
but there is something really tricky in
there.
>> So, one of the lowest moments of my life
was when I got one of the biggest awards
of my life. It was Nelson Mandela's
family gave me an award and their
father's name in front of a lot of
people. And I went home and just cried.
I didn't want it. I didn't want the I
mean, I must get emotional now. Like, I
did not want the award. I did not feel
worthy. I was like, you know, yes, we
help a lot of people, but I'm an
entrepreneur and this is a man, you
know, you know, it's just like what? Why
am I getting this? And that that
actually was kind of the beginning of me
detaching from even wanting to be
involved in Tom's. You know, long before
I sold the company, I started pulling
back because I was like, I got put on a
pedestal that was impossible. like no
one I was treated like this saint and I
was still making lots of money and
running a business and doing these
things and yeah I remember there were
some moments but that was the one that I
really think of. I can remember exactly
what I was wearing. I can remember being
backstage. and mirror being like not
wanting it and then getting it and then
everyone wanting to take pictures with
me and their I mean it was just and that
was like I think that's the last time I
did any accepted any awards or did any
public speaking for like four years like
it was and that was kind of the
beginning of the you know the onset of
the depression.
>> Yeah. Did you h did you have anyone to
talk to even at that time? Like did you
have a friend that you could go, "Hey,
it's so funny. I'm I'm I'm grateful and
I'm experiencing this other weird thing
that is hard on me." Or did you just
pack it all inside? I just packed it in.
It's I had great friends. That's the
interesting thing. Like I One of the
things I'm most proud of is my guy
friend group. I started this group
called the Rugged Adventure Club with 12
other guys in 2007.
and we text every day and and we go on
trips and but back then that was like
2013 or 14. the group was still young
still, you know, the group's much more
se now. We've all had kids. We've all
gone through crisises. We've all some of
us gotten divorced once or twice. I
mean, like, you know, like we've gone
through some [\h__\h] So now, and like when
I did struggle with the depression, I
had that group, but back then I still
had those guys, but I didn't have the
vocabulary to explain what I was
feeling. Like imposttor syndrome I had
in a way. And I also just had this this
feeling of kind of dread when I had to
tell my story over and over and over
again because it started not feel real.
Started to feel like a performance
>> and I knew when people were going to
cry, you know, and I gave the story of
giving shoes and it was like what the
hell and so I I kind of suffered
silently those years. Um, it wasn't
until later that I started really, you
know, and was forced to learn a lot
about mental health that I started
realizing the importance of talking to a
therapist or to friends [music] and and
opening up. This podcast is brought to
you by One Skin. Now, I first learned
about One Skin. It was given to me as a
gift from my friend Heidi. I got the
face product, then I got the eye
product, then I got the body. I used the
sunblock. And I've even been using their
body moisturizer after training. I don't
know about you, but I'm really trying to
focus on my health, my internal health,
but the idea of taking care of my skin
from a scientific point of view is very,
very important to me. So, let's talk
about our New Year's resolution for a
second. I think it's all about kind of
doing that inventory, looking at, hey,
what's not working and getting rid of
that and doubling down on the things
that work. and One Skin is definitely
one of the products that I double down
on and it stays in my bathroom on my
counter and I just keep adding their new
products. What I love about this brand
is that at the core it is their patented
OS1 peptide. So, it's the first
ingredient proven to target scinesscent
cells. These are the root causes of
things like wrinkles, crepiness, and a
loss of elasticity. These are all key
signs of skin aging. And these results
have been validated in five different
clinical studies. So it's not just like
something you throw on your skin. These
people have been looking at ingredients
to support your skin, but also at the
cellular level. Certified safe for
sensitive skin. So one skin products are
free from over 1,500 harsh or irritating
ingredients. They're tested by
dermatologist and they have gotten over
10,000 five-star reviews. Like I said,
I've been a customer for a long time.
I've given it to friends and I noticed
the difference. So, born from over 10
years of longevity research, One Skin's
OS1 peptide is proven to target the
cells that cause the visible signs of
aging, helping you unlock your
healthiest skin now and as you age. For
a limited time, One Skin is making it
even easier to stay consistent with up
to 30% off your first three subscription
orders. That's right, 30% off when you
use the code Gabby Reese, one word at
onskin.co/gaby
ree. That's up to 30% off with the code
gaby ree gabbby y reece ce. After you
purchase, they'll ask, "Hey, where'd you
hear about us?" Please support the show
and let them know. That's one.co/gaby
ree.
I know just a few years ago you you
[music] sort of really had
it was a a very difficult time, but I'm
wondering if you now if there would be
anything that you could direct young you
in that moment that that could have
supported you in a real way because I
think a lot of people go through their
own versions of this where they're at a
crossroads.
>> They don't have the tools.
For you personally in that scenario, is
there something or someone or a series
of a couple of practices that you could
have implemented that maybe would have
helped you through that time and then to
navigate
um life beyond that?
>> Well, I think I think therapy is great.
Um I am a big proponent of that. I think
if I would have had a therapist to say,
"Hey, this is what's coming up for me.
This is what I'm thinking." And they
could have been like, Blake, this is
imposter syndrome or this is, you know,
whatever. Like they could have named the
kind of psychological challenge I was
dealing with and tell me that other
people feel this way too and that I am
enough just as I am and I don't need the
external validation and actually the
external validation in that case I was
getting was warranted. like I did a
really great thing. Like I should have
been able to feel that like you know I
think I could have I could have accepted
the compliment, accepted the award and
like today if I would get that award I
would you know I would say okay like
this is beautiful like how cool is what
we've done being recognized and I and I
feel worthy of it. But
>> I didn't then. So I think therapy or
having a really good friend that has I
mean young people have such a much
better understanding of mental health
now. Like I think like I think that's a
great one of the good things is, you
know, one of the bad things is we have
more people struggling than ever before.
One of the good things is like I just
went back to my high school and gave a
speech like these kids are talking about
this stuff. They're aware of this stuff.
They're aware of the signs, you know.
Um, so I also think besides, you know, a
good therapist or having someone to talk
to, I I I think it kind of goes back to
what I'm kind of pouring my heart into
now is like just, you know, having um a
stronger sense of worthiness outside of
my external accomplishments. So, I
wasn't so dependent on what people
thought or the award I got or what I
did. It's so it's so interesting because
the whole world is really set up for was
that good? Good job. You know, like
here's a grade, here's a check, here's a
it's so interesting because the whole
thing is set up to be so loud that we
don't get that time within our within
ourselves. So, you sell you sell to
Tomms. You have a family. Um, you know,
you're very successful
and uh and and then you have a I guess
what what would you call it? I'm not
going to label it. What
>> Sure. Well, it it didn't happen all at
once. So, no one prepared me for what
was going to happen when I sold Toms.
Now, I had I love snowboarding and
surfing and pretty much any day that I
stand sideways, I'm happy. Um, so, um,
when I sold the company, I had the
opportunity to move to the mountains and
snowboard, you know, 150 days a year or
however many days. And that was my
dream. And so, I sold the company. I
moved to Jackson Hole, Wyoming. Now,
three things happened that I wasn't
prepared for that I think was kind of
the onset of the depression. Number one
is I woke up and I had no purpose
anymore. Like, even though I was having
a hard time at Tom's, I was still having
purpose. Second thing is even though I
sold the company and left, all my
friends still work there, you know. So
all my community, all my best friends
were all people or most of them were
people at Tom's. They were still in Los
Angeles. I was now in the mountains in
my big dream house, but I didn't have my
community. And then the third thing, and
I think this is really relevant, is it
started getting dark at 5:00 p.m. You
know, I had lived in Los Angeles for 17
years at this point, and now it's
getting dark at 5:00 p.m. And that
really, I think, I was not prepared for.
And so those things started what was the
beginning of a 7-year, what I would call
seasonal depression. So, it wasn't a
full-on depression. I didn't see a
psychiatrist. I didn't get on any meds.
I didn't freak out really, but I just
didn't feel like myself the for the
first 42 years. I I I did not feel the
same energy. Um especially in the winter
months, I felt depression and I did what
I think a lot of people would do in this
case and that is I started looking to
every external thing in the world to
feel better. So, and I had all this
money, right? And so, you know, built
the dream house, got super into very
dangerous extreme sports, you know,
racing cars, climbing mountains, you
know, surfing big waves that I had never
surfed before. I mean, I did everything
I can to feel something, you know,
because I was I had lost that that the
the the the purpose. And so it was it
got bad, you know, usually in the
holiday time in the winter, then I'd
kind of bounce out of it because I'd go
on a great surf trip or heli ski trip or
whatever and then I would feel better
and then it but that all that whole
cycle and that caused a lot of strain on
my marriage. Um ultimately ended up
getting divorced. Um and then that was a
whole another set of challenges um and
really difficult.
>> Um and that kind of went on for six or
seven years. years. I ended up moving to
Costa Rica with a family and trying to
do it there and thinking that would
solve things. That didn't. Um it worked
for a little while for a year or two. I
got to surf almost every day and that
and got a lot of sunshine and that felt
good. But it all came to kind of an end
when we decided to move back to the
United States and moved up to the Bay
Area. And now I didn't have my surfing
as a crutch. Um I didn't have my Costa
Rica community. I was living in a city
where I didn't know anyone. It was once
again getting dark earlier, you know, in
the winter months. And that's when
it got really, really bad. I mean,
that's when
>> I unfortunately started having suicidal
thoughts like all day long. And to say
it out loud now is like crazy. Like I it
can't it's like a bad movie that I was
in. Um,
>> and cuz it seems so hard to believe cuz
I always always been like I think one of
the most optimistic and positive people
in the room, but I just felt so trapped,
so lost, so hopeless. I didn't feel any
confidence. I didn't feel like I was a
good dad. I didn't feel like I was a
good friend. I mean, I just it just
every sign you hear about was severe
depression was happening. And um and
then on top of that, I got put on a
bunch of pharmaceuticals that made it
worse.
>> Yeah. And then that I think also created
the suicidality.
And then finally after trying lots of
different things I mean I got my brain
stimulated. I did silent retreats. I did
other retreat. I mean I did everything.
I hooked up with a great psychiatrist
um who also I think is just a great
therapist. And he said the first thing
we got to do is get you off these meds,
you know. And so I went through a long
tapering process to get off the meds. I
ended up going to a treatment facility
in Arizona that was amazing called
Alternative to Meds Center and all they
do is help people get off meds. I'd sat
in a sauna for two hours a day at 180
degrees. I mean, took more NAC and well,
I forget the other ones that cause you
to nascin just sweating the [\h__\h] out of
it out. And I got all the [\h__\h] out of my
system. And there getting clear with my
help of my therapist and an amazing
community, you know, I made some big
life changes. I simplified. I got out of
a relationship. I did a lot of things
that I needed to do. I repaired things
with my with my ex-wife. um reconnected
with my kids and but the biggest thing
that had the biggest difference in all
of it was, you know, with this
psychiatrist and doing a lot of therapy,
I recognized this this what now I know
is a core wound. And my core wound was
that I never felt that I was enough. And
I was able to see how that wound had
been driving pretty much every decision
in my life. You know, from the tennis
days of being just maniacally focused on
being the best to the early business
days to then now the toms. It was all a
desperate attempt of something inside of
me to feel enough. And we ended up one
of the most simplest things in the
world, but had the most transformative
effect on my mental health and I believe
kind of saved my life was he gave me
this 40-day challenge. And what it was
is he said, "Your subconscious
is repaying this this story in your mind
that you're not enough. And we've got to
rewire your neural pathways." And so for
the next 40 days, for 20 minutes in the
morning and 20 minutes in the evening,
you're going to set a timer and you're
going to take your fingers and your
thumbs and you're going to close your
eyes and you're going to say, "I'm
enough. I've always been enough. I am
enough. I've always been enough." And
you're going to do that. and after 40
days we're gonna check in and I have a
feeling you're going to feel totally
different. Now I was like come on like
I've tried all these different things
like you know and this is hard if you've
I mean I meditated some but like doing a
mantra for 20 minutes that simple right
>> that's what I was thinking when you said
that I thought oh man I don't know if I
could do that for 20 minutes top and
bottom of the day [laughter]
>> it was it was the hard one of the
hardest things at first that I've ever
done and I was like angry I mean Gabby I
was like this is stupid I was texting I
was like this is not working I feel
worse like I mean it was and this was
just you know, last year in December.
So, you know, a year ago today,
basically, I mean, I'm doing this mantra
and um and and I just kept at it because
I was so I was so desperate to feel
better and I trusted this guy a lot and
he helped me get off the meds and so I
was like, "Okay, I'm going to do this."
>> And it was almost like a magical thing
happened at day 28. So, I don't know
why, but on day 28, I was doing it. I'll
never forget. I was in the morning and
like the 20 minutes went by like in two
minutes. It felt like like the timer
went off and I was like looked at it
like
>> and I got up and I just felt different.
It was weird. Like my body like it was
like a switch. And then that night when
I went to go do it, I was like excited
to do it. And then on day 29, I felt
better. And day 30, I was telling my
friends like, "Hey, this is the coolest
thing. Not going to believe this. It's
actually I'm I feel different. I don't
feel anx I'm not waking up with anxiety
in the morning." And I'm not worried if
like, you know, my ex-wife, you know,
says something not nice about me or I'm
not a good dad or whatever. I mean, it
doesn't matter. Like, I was just like,
"Wow, like I I think I feel enough." And
so, I did this did this. I get to day 40
and I'm feeling great now. Before all
this happened, six months before, I
signed up to go to this really intense
kind of personal spiritual retreat in
India because I was told by a friend who
was also suicidal that he went and it
saved his life. So, I'm like, I'm it.
And I got, you know, you know, coverage
with the kids. And so I was going to do
this and so I'm feeling great now but
I've already signed up for India. I like
I might as well go. And so I go to India
and I don't know what day it was but I
was sitting we did like lots of
meditation. Holy cow. I mean all kinds
of meditations in this ashram. It was
beautiful beautiful program. And all of
a sudden kind of like what happened with
Tom shoes
I just had this voice and it was like
you're not the only person that
struggles with this feeling.
>> Yeah. This is a cultural sickness and
your experience and everything you've
gone through was so that you could help
others and you need to go home when you
finish here and help figure out a way to
help other people feel enough. And I was
like I mean I just like lit up. I didn't
know what I was going to do but I like
the message was so clear. So I got my
journal. I wrote it down. I finished the
India program. I came home and I have
dinner with my best friend John who was
also one of my, you know, best mentors
at Tom's and helped design our eyewear
and and I'm telling him and I'm like,
"Oh, maybe I should do shoes again or
should this like what can I do to, you
know, help people, you know, feel
enough?" And he's like, "It's a
bracelet." And I'm like, "A bracelet?"
And he's like, "Yeah." He said, "Blake,
ever since I've known you, you've always
worn bracelets. Like, I've always I
mean, even back in the day before Yeah.
Right. You know,
And so he said, "I think you need a
daily reminder that you're enough. I
think you should create enough bracelet
and I think you should sell it." And
then I was like, "Okay." And I was like,
"And I don't thankfully need to make
money anymore." So I was like, "A
[snorts] 100% of the profits will go to
mental health organizations." So like,
you know, that is easy to do. And he and
so literally talk to someone in
production back to India and we make the
bracelets in India. These beautiful
women hand make them. there. I'll show
you one here. I don't know if this is on
video or not, but Okay, it is great. So,
it's a hand beaded bracelet.
>> Yeah.
>> And I started wearing it and it was a
great little tool for me. And then, you
know, I gave some to some friends and it
was this and that. And then the my
favorite part about the whole project
besides the fact that we could commit to
100% of profits going to these
organizations because of the financial
freedom I'd already created. The
favorite part came when we thought about
power of wearing it is one thing but the
power of giving it is another.
>> Yeah.
>> So how there's always someone in our
life that either a might really need
this message or b is the reason we feel
enough like they they gave you that
self-conscious like my dad on that phone
call. And so we created this I'll show
you this little box here.
>> And so when you buy it it comes in this
box and then inside there's not one but
two bracelets.
>> Oh. So, one for you and one to give. And
so, the idea is that when you wear one,
what you like it?
>> Well, and it's that back to one for you
and one to give.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> So, so that's what came. Yeah.
>> No, you said the idea you were going to
I cut you off. I'm sorry.
>> So, so the idea is is that when you
commit to wearing one as a reminder
yourself, you also get the joy of giving
one. And so like with Tom's like you
bought a pair of shoes we gave a pair of
shoes on your behalf. Now with this one
for one it's you know when you're buying
one you get to do the giving and and so
we got so excited about that me and it's
a very small team here at Enough and and
then my assistant said this is so
beautiful. I'm so excited. But like
Blake, I'm not so good like being
vulnerable with people like and if I'm
giving this enough bracelet to my mom or
to my friend or whatever, like I don't
know what I would say like how I would
communicate because I don't want them to
feel that they're not enough and like I
don't know. And so we thought about it
and I have a really good friend. I don't
know if you know him. You might. He
lives in LA. In Q the poet in Q.
>> I know who he is. I don't actually know
him myself. Okay. He's an amazing man.
His name is Adam. Real name Adam. And I
went to Adam and I was like, I need you.
You're the best person I've ever, you
know, heard words from. I need you to
figure out a way that something that we
could write that in the packaging we
could hand with the bracelet that would
tell someone why they're getting it. And
so inside the box is this poem that he
wrote. And I'll I'll read it to you real
quick. Um, and then there's also an
envelope that you can give to someone
with a bracelet. So the ritual is when
you get them is you ask someone to open
their palms and then you slide it on and
then you read them this poem. So I'll
read it to you. Dear Gabby, I see you.
The you behind the you. Not for anything
you've done or anything you're going to
do. I don't stop to say it enough, but I
believe in you. And if you could see
yourself from my view, you'd believe it,
too. That's why I'm giving you the gift
that I'm receiving, too. A message to
remind you when you're lost or feeling
blue. A mantra to repeat when times are
tough. Because no matter who we are, we
are always enough.
>> It's a silent prayer I'm sending for the
world's mental health. I wear wear this
symbol for myself and now as a bond to
someone else. It's a blessing and a
gentle push to never give up because no
matter who you are, you are enough.
Isn't that great?
>> Yeah. Gorgeous.
>> Yeah. He did such a good job. I mean,
he's just such a master. This podcast
[music] is brought to you by Timeline. I
love Timeline. I have been using their
uroliththna products for over 5 years.
I'm excited to share with you their
January 2026 incredible offer and
wonderful new product, their Mitapure
gummies. These are the first ever
longevity gummies that support your
cellular energy so you feel strong,
clear, and vibrant all year long. It's
January. I know you're motivated. I'm
motivated. So whether we're kicking off
or we're keep going, these are for you.
These are the only clinically proven
uriththna gummy that helps renew your
cell's powerhouses, your mitochondria.
So you can show up your best no matter
what decade you're in. Believe me, I
know. I just had a birthday. So it helps
with general wellness, your fitness. You
know, you can't always out train
sluggish energy. So this gives you
better recovery. And that starts at the
cellular level for longevity. That
doesn't always have to be so
complicated. It can just start with one
daily habit. So let's talk about
cellular energy because that's what this
is really about. It gives your cells
more power to fuel your day. supports
steady, sustained energy. Helps your
body turn stress into usable energy. Who
doesn't need that? And even strength. It
is clinically shown to support muscle
strength and function. So, really good
for healthy aging. And it is the number
one doctor recommended urolithna
supplement out on the market. They're
vegan, gluten-free, non-GMO, sugarf
free, and allergen free. They're clean
label project and NSF certified. So,
they thought about it all. So easy to
use. I keep mine on the counter. It's
not another pill to take. I just pop a
gummy and I'm good to go. So, you can
think of this as charging your internal
batteries, but every day. So, it's just
a fact of science. As you get older,
it's harder to keep muscle. This
supports that and your body does make
less energy. So, if you're looking for
this, they have an incredible offer.
Don't let it go. Not another year going
feeling less than your best. Grab 35%
off your one month subscription of
Mitaper Gummies at timeline.com/gaby35.
That's timeline.com/gaby35.
t i m e l i ne.com/gaby35
while the offer still lasts. I think a
lot of people experience versions of
what you're talking about. But obviously
it can show up differently for
everybody. But what if I was just
thinking about like if I was in a
partnership with somebody that was going
through this. If someone's listening to
this and maybe it's not them directly,
but they are with somebody or they have
a friend, what does anything show up for
you that is a way that they could be
supportive? Because listen, we can't
save anyone, right? Like it's on us to
do it. But it you definitely like I'll
give you an example. I'm hyper I'm hyper
vigilant. Like I I've really mellowed
out. I mean, you know, it's you know
when you you start learning lessons um
and you think and now I'm like I'll be
you know 56 in, you know, a couple weeks
and I'm like you know maybe a couple
years ago I thought to myself, you know,
all these lessons like if they're not in
play now, like I'm not really sure when
they're going to be in play. And so I I
really uh learned to to chill out
because hyper vigilance was a reaction
to my childhood, right? And so
>> one thing that Lar and Lar is a good
partner for me because he has a lot of
faith. He it he's not scared in the ways
that I have things. And um he'll say to
me sometimes, you know, Gabby um
everything's going to be okay. And he's
like, and it is okay. M
>> and it puts me back into yeah,
>> you know, like Byron Katy calls it past
futureing. I, you know, I love that,
>> you know, stop doing that. And and for
other people, it's like, hey, be present
and don't react to what's happened and
all those things, but sometimes it's a
hand on my arm and it's like, hey,
Gabby, you know, everything's going to
be okay. And it is okay. It it would
there be something based on what you
experienced that I know going to the
therapist was helpful in going through
that process.
>> Sure. that someone could have shown up
for you and it's not a blame game
because we only get educated when we go
through it.
>> Sure.
>> That could have been like, "Hey, you
know, Blake, I love you and I I'm here
for you while you go through this, but
like would there have been a way to
really show up for you?" I I think that,
you know, now knowing what I know, I
think
someone could have said to me, Blake,
you're enough. It's good.
>> I kind of like what Lar says to you.
>> It's already okay. Like, stop chasing,
you know, stop trying to achieve the
next thing. Like, you've done enough.
you are enough and and and you're a good
enough dad and you're a good enough
partner and and and and
it would encourage me to do the inner
work to feel and to learn how to feel
that myself, you know, cuz I think if
someone could have directed me more
internally, then I wouldn't have
maybe made such a mess of my personal
life and other life just trying to do
things externally to feel better. You
know, I think I think that's one of the
great gifts we can give each other when
we see someone struggling is to, you
know, recognize it in a way that doesn't
make them feel bad or shameful, you
know, and and to also to to normalize it
like this human journey. I mean, this is
part of it, you know, and some of us
maybe experience it in greater extremes,
but my life has always been extreme. So,
it's not it's actually not surprising
that the low is as low as it got because
I've also had some incredible highs. And
not everyone's going to have that
extreme. But, I think I love doing this
now. I I now that I'm so aware of this
and this is my life's work, I love
getting to talk to someone and just
really say, "When when was the last time
you did not feel enough?" and and what
what caused that? What triggered that?
Was that a person? Was that a situation?
Because then you start looking at these
patterns.
And once you recognize the patterns,
like every time I'm with Sally, I don't
feel enough. Well, then maybe you don't
spend so much time with Sally, you know,
or you know, every time that, you know,
I, you know, something with work. Well,
is that the right job to be in? Is that
the healthiest environment? I mean,
sometimes you have to make hard changes
in your life if if if if something is
continually triggering you this this
potential wound. And so, I like to sit
with people and really do kind of like
um a life inventory of, you know, if
they are struggling with this um or even
if they're not struggling with not
feeling enough, they're just struggling,
you know, being depressed or feeling
stuck. You know, I really love sitting
with people and just holding space for
them and just saying, "Okay, let's talk
about the the five closest people to
you. Let's talk about how you spend most
of your time. Let's talk, you know, and
just these basic things." Because
sometimes we just don't slow down to
look at things that are the most
obvious,
>> right? And you you mentioned earlier
like it feels and I mean obviously it's
so easy to point to technology as um
okay so there's more discussion around
mental health. Um,
I I'm in this weird middle place
sometimes where I'm like, "Hey, life is
hard. Being a human has a lot of
biological
um mismatches in the way that we live."
And so instead of telling people like I
always think we sell people a bill of
goods like, "Oh, you're supposed to feel
good and happy." I'm like actually I
think by nature we don't feel good and
it's our job to work to figure out the
environments, the people, all the things
that we need to feel pretty good now and
again.
>> I think we when someone it's like
nothing's wrong with you when you feel
bad. You're actually just a human being
and like it's this job uh you know to
get out of bed and go all right what's
my strategy to like feel pretty good
today right?
>> Totally. And and I think sometimes
people go, "Something's wrong with me."
It's like, "Actually, no, there's
nothing wrong with you." Um, so I float
between that and I'm I'm glad young
people, you know, I have three
daughters. My youngest daughter is 17.
So
>> Oh, man. I can't believe that. Like last
time I was at the pool, they were like
little kids.
>> Oh yeah. No.
>> I mean, oh my gosh.
>> These are these are these are these are
young women now.
>> Yeah. Wow. I mean, I'm almost 50, so
yeah. Like that's it's a lot's changed.
>> Yeah. And and it's interesting because I
then have been informed through their
generation about words like trauma,
trigger, all this stuff where I'm like,
"Hey everybody, let's not get so crazy."
>> Yeah.
>> Because life is hard. You know this.
You've been in a competitive environment
in sport, in work. And in a way,
>> it's like how do we bridge Yes. It's
great. Let's talk this. I like um with
this also is just kind of the hard part
of of life. We sometimes when you talk
to people is there conversation around
kind of helping people hold space for
both ideas?
>> Uh for sure. And I'm so glad you brought
that up because as an athlete and you
know as an entrepreneur I mean I had
many many setbacks. I had many, many
lonely, you know, freaking out nights
making cash flow. And I mean that life
is hard. Starting a business is hard.
Being married is hard. I mean, those are
those are all just real parts of life.
And that is separate, I think, than when
someone is waking up at 3:00 a.m. every
day with chronic anxiety or, you know,
they're having very scary thoughts or
they go from loving surfing to not even
enjoying, you know, Kelly Slater's wave
poolool. Like, I mean, that happened to
me. Like, I mean, literally, that I
think is one of the greatest places on
the planet. I'm in a barrel, I pull out,
and I'm emotionally flat. I mean, that's
when I knew I was like, I have to get
real help, you know, but I mean, my
point is is I think it's important to
differentiate and I'm so glad you
brought that up.
>> Um, and it's, you know, it's a little
bit different for everyone and, um,
that's why, you know, we, you know, are
supporting all these amazing mental
health organizations because it takes,
you know, it takes some different
resources that we didn't have to to help
people with this. And, you know, you
mentioned technology. It's interesting.
During my depression, I was completely
off social media. I didn't have any
interest. Um, and I didn't do social, I
think, for over three years, maybe four
years. And then once I started feeling
better and really started some things
started clicking, you know, well before
launching enough, I was like, I I kind
of feel like I owe it to people to share
what happened and what I learned and and
that's why, you know, I'm getting ready
to launch a podcast myself called No
Magic Pill that's all about mental
wellness and and but I I bring this up
about technology because I have found
like I know social media gets such a bad
But I have found that it has been a part
of my healing journey being able to
share with people, hear people's stories
back, you know, feeling a sense of, you
know, community. And I think it is a I
think it can be a real community when
done with intentionality and done in
moderation. And so everyone says like,
"Oh my gosh, social media is causing all
this mental health issues." I think
that's partially true. And I believe
that technology and social media used
the right way can can help encourage
each other and hold each other
accountable and and things like that.
So, um because I've been on social media
now for what maybe six months and it has
been helpful. Like I had a really really
hard day the other day that actually
felt like I was slipping back into the
depression. It was so weird. And I woke
up and I was just not good. And it was
like all these like these insecure
thoughts and anxiety and you know felt
so tired I couldn't work and and I just
was really honest about it and I got the
most incredible responses and support
from people that I know some people that
I don't know and what was so cool is the
next day I felt great and I realized it
wasn't because of the comments. It was
actually I had horrible jet lag. And jet
lag for someone who's gone through that
is kind of if you've never been through
depression, think of the worst jet lag
ever. And that's kind of what every day
feels like when you're depressed,
>> right?
>> And so the jet lag created a PTSD
response of, "Oh my god, you're going to
be depressed again." But because I
experienced that and I figured it out,
the next day I went on social and posted
what I learned. And so many people were
like, "Wow, like that makes so much
sense. like I have had some of my worst
experiences after traveling and it's
really scary if you've had mental
illness in the past. So, so I think
social media and technology can really
help um if done if used properly. Do you
think, and I know it's still new, but do
you feel
that uh it's like I have friends, you
know, that have recovered from cancer
and then, you know, something comes up
and their first thought is like, uh, you
know, oh no. And
>> oh no. Yeah.
>> Are have you been able to release
yourself from the idea? Because
sometimes maybe when you could go
through something like this, it would be
easy to kind of think, well, that's what
kind of person I am.
>> Um, versus, oh, I I have gone through
that. I have healed myself. I have tools
now. Are you able to to sort of, you
know, kind of re label or actually
non-label yourself now?
>> Yes and no. I would say 90% of the time
I if I start feeling anxious or start
feeling discomfort or start feeling a
little something that reminds me of that
time, I tell myself what you just said
and that is life is hard. It makes sense
that you're anxious. Blake, you're
starting this new mental health
nonprofit. You've invested millions of
dollars in this to help people. You have
no idea if anyone's going to buy the
damn bracelet. Like anxiety is normal,
you know? Um sleepless nights are
normal. like don't freak out. So, I'm
actually It's the funny thing that you
brought that up. I'm actually giving
myself the talk of like Blake, this is
life. This is not depression or anxiety
a lot now because it is just I'm in a
really kind of exciting but stressful
time period right now. You know, my my
kids are 11 and 8 and there's a lot of
effort and work and energy and I'm
exhausted and that's not me getting
depressed. That's just me being
exhausted. Um so so yes so I am now
there's 10% of the time or maybe even
5%. Where like what happened with the
jet lag where it feels acute
or I wake up in the middle of the night
and can't go back to sleep and I
remember all those nights that I stayed
up all night long
>> and I'm like oh [\h__\h] And then I and
then I go to the serious tools like I go
get my cold plunge. That's been one of
the things that has helped me a lot just
kind of reset my nervous system. I'll,
you know, if if it's in the middle of
the night, I'll just go do push-ups and
sit up like do something physical to get
going. That helps. Um, if it's still
lasting in the morning, I call my best
friends. I mean, I have a whole series
of things that I do. Um, so yeah. So I I
feel like I have healed this, but I also
feel like, you know, maybe the same way
that someone is a recovering from
alcohol or drugs or something. I do
think when you have that severe
depression, you're going to kind of
probably always be in some level in
recovery. I don't identify with it like
I'm a I'm a person that struggles with
depression anymore. I think actually I'm
one of the most optimistic, positive
people in the world and I experience
depression just like someone experiences
a broken leg. and I healed it. And my
leg is frankly I feel like my leg or my
brain in this analogy is stronger than
ever. But I'm humble enough to know that
if I don't do the things, if I don't
stay connected to those I love, if I'm
not really hyperly viligent about who I
surround with, if I don't have purpose,
if I don't do all these things, it could
come back.
>> Yeah, I think that's really wise. Do you
you know, it's funny. I I think um you
know in our in our house uh we we talk
about like the smaller I am in certain
ways
the better I am
>> right like there is so there is
something much greater than I am I am
>> I'm here to you know yes I have personal
things that I want to accomplish and
experience but I'm also um equally as of
service to my family and to my friends
and in whichever way I can contribute
and that really It's funny how that is.
It's like, okay, I can stay small, but
then somehow that makes me also feel
better about myself,
>> right? Like that enough part.
>> Yeah.
>> Gets really satisfied by being small.
>> Yeah. I'm so it's well and also I don't
know if this is the case for you as an
athlete but this is pretty fascinating
around that smallalness or that
enoughness actually being um a uh a
gateway to to kind of freedom and peace
because um there's one of our adviserss
at enough is a woman named Kristen Nef I
don't know if you know her work she
wrote a book called self-compassion
that's amazing okay good so she's a
great researcher University of Texas and
so she did a study with the NCAA
athletes about self-compassion or
wholeness or enoughness as I would call
it. And she took half the group and let
them just operate as they do and they're
hard charging. They're really hard on
themselves and they lose a game. They
they work twice as hard if if if
something's not working on the court,
you know, etc. And they kind of have an
inner critic, if you will. So, she
replaced the inner critic with what she
calls the inner coach. And the inner
coach had these positive affirmations
like with you miss a shot say in
volleyball I'm not defined by that
unforced error you know I am much
greater than how I performed on the
court today and so what and so basically
I am enough as I am what she found was
over time those athletes started way
outperforming the ones with the hard
driving pressure inner critic. Now the
reason that is which is fascinating I
think is by reducing that pressure by me
feeling enough I have less pressure
which allows me to enter a flow state
and all the science around flow state is
when an athlete or a business person or
even a mom performs their best because
they're not they're not they're in the
flow and so one of my really important
messages around enough especially when I
speak to student athletes is this is not
soft. This is not for mediocre or
settling. This is a performance hack.
Like if you want to be the best, the
more you can feel enough outside of your
results, the more the pressure goes down
and the more you'll perform. And and and
that's a really important part of this
message as well because I think some
people might It's funny. I was telling
someone, they go, I don't want to be
enough. I want to be more than enough.
And I'm like, I don't know. Let me back
up the science behind this. And so yeah.
>> Yeah. Because I think that in a way
being enough like we just talked about
it swings both ways. So this humility
creates an opportunity
>> to really love yourself.
>> Yeah.
>> Just you not
>> oh I'm Blake. I do this. I've made this.
I'm you know it's like
>> it's just me. Just this spirit of me.
And I think to your point it also makes
all the transitions and you're not as
attached to outcome. People like you
don't like you. You know it's like all
of that stuff gets so much easier. I
have to tell you something really funny
since I I have been around you a couple
of times. At the time, it's so funny. It
feels very different to me now. That's
why I c I can say it to you.
>> Um your sort of reluctance, you had a
reluctance,
>> you know, it like to interact you you
would because you're polite.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> but because whatever reason and it was
always that that is one of the I rather
someone who's like in my face and even
like whoa when someone's like reluctant
I'm like what's going on like what's
happening you know
>> and it's so interesting because when I
was going to talk to you today I thought
oh that's so interesting because I I
personally experienced that
>> and then seeing I I had you know getting
ready for this conversation I I thought
oh Blake is is is a little bit
different. Yeah, I feel I mean totally
different like I think that reluctance
and that kind of you know was I I didn't
feel secure in myself like like I needed
you to like me. I hope you like me but I
don't need you to like me you know and
and it's so it's there's just a a it's a
it's it's a it's I say a confidence with
a lot of humility that comes from
suffering. So yeah.
>> Yeah. And I just I bring that up because
I think times a lot of times people if
they come into to situations where they
hope someone likes them, it it's so
important to not care about that because
>> you're not going to control that. And
people are always really going to just
like you, the ones that you want to
know.
>> Yeah.
>> For being you.
>> Yeah. I mean, that's the I mean, look,
if you think about it, like, and that's
I think why this message has been so
important for me with my kids. Yeah,
like I think there's been like this has
been the coolest experience with my kids
over this journey. I mean I I it's been
so hard for them seeing me suffering and
and how hard it was that time. I mean
that breaks my heart and
>> and there's been a lot of healing around
that. But for me to be able to explain
why I'm feeling better now and that I
finally realize that I'm enough and
they're enough. We do this thing at at
dinner every night where we hold hands
and our prayer is we look at each other
in the eye one at a time and we say I am
enough. We look at each other both and
then we say point to each other say you
are enough and then we say we are enough
and it's been the coolest thing. I feel
like there's like a lot like the even if
like because if you don't feel enough
yourself then you're going to probably
make other people around you not feel
enough like even if it's subconscious
and while I never felt like I was doing
that I feel now my kids are much more
relaxed around me and and they're more
confident in a way um because I tell
them I'm like it you know you are enough
no matter what you do no matter what
sport you play no matter what grade you
have you know and and I think It's just
I I'm excited. You know, it was
interesting when I went to my high
school. Um I I hadn't been there in 30
years and so I took some of the bracelet
boxes and some bracelets and this is,
you know, before we launched and I
shared it with the kids and and we
talked about it and it was really
beautiful and and then they went around
they said who they were going to give
their bracelet to, you know, and most of
them were my best friend or there's this
person I know in this class. I think
they're struggling or you know, you
know, this person always makes me feel
enough and so we're going to wear this
like a friendship bracelet.
>> And this one girl said, I'm going to
give it to my dad. I think my dad has
been not feeling well for a very long
time and I think he needs to know he's
enough.
>> Yeah.
>> And I was like, wow. Like that parent to
adult or adultto parent relationship I
think is this message is so powerful for
Yeah, because well her gen her her dad's
generation was you know you got to be
stoic especially if you're male on top
of
>> in Texas
>> in Texas right like three layers deep
already. Um
>> so ble my last question and then we'll
direct everybody to all the places that
if they it'd be an incredible Christmas
gift.
>> Yeah. again getting ready for this
conversation I thought to I had all the
thoughts you know and one of the
thoughts was here's a guy who has
everything and more than everything
right and I know that you you've sort of
discussed um you know wanting less you
know kind of simplifying
>> and wanting less but I think for a lot
of people if they they look at someone
and they go well what are they what are
they what's their deal like oh it's
you're not enough
>> no because
Never never mind for you. I'm just kind
of looking at the message from all the
directions,
>> but there might be people experiencing
this, right? Like, well, what you know,
I I I you know, whatever the million
things that we we say are mean success
in this world, like, oh, I have a good
job or I'm attractive or I'm I have a
good family or whatever, you know, how
do you how do you talk about that part?
Because I think that that's where it's
it's really important.
Um because I think sometimes with people
they can get distracted with those types
of thoughts.
>> Sure. So I think the first thing is is
to not feel shame if you have success or
you've accomplished all this and you
don't feel good. Like I actually think
it's almost designed so that that
happens. I don't know very many people
who've achieved the, you know, their
greatest dreams or got the job or became
the CEO or even became a mom and dad.
They thought kids was going to be the
thing. There's always going to be a let
down. And I think it's designed by, you
want to call it, God, the universe,
whatever. For me, it's God because that
causes us to go inward. And when you go
inward, that's the beginning of the
greatest journey of all.
>> I really appreciate that. I I can tell
you a really quick confession. So when I
I grew up I didn't for about five years
I didn't live with uh my parents and my
dad died when I was five right and so
coming up [clears throat]
>> I I when I started working and and
meeting people that were successful
>> and then as you know like living in
California you meet the most successful
and and I thought okay real attention
big attention big cash the collateral
damage to the family seems pretty
radical. So I weirdly for the longest
time was striving to be successful but
not too successful.
>> Oh wow.
>> Because I thought and I didn't know it
was like a subconscious thing. It was
almost like a natural break because I
thought the most important thing for me
are my relationships and my family. And
so I want to be, you know, mobile and be
able to help, you know, help people but
not too much
>> because it seems like it trashes like
your real life.
>> Yeah. And then I it's like I had to
almost redefine that and go yeah okay
take it like you're in charge of
>> you know how you're responding but I I
think you're right. I think it is set up
and and now you can just take it as a
cue of like oh I I I can go to my
practice I can go back inside do
inventory check in and uh and then get
back out there.
>> Yeah absolutely. So Blake, direct people
uh where where they can where they can
find the program, if they want to
connect with you, if they want to buy
the the bracelets.
>> Great. Okay. So our website is we are
enough.org.
Um and so we are enough.org has the
bracelets, has hoodies, t-shirts, all
kinds of fun things. Uh and like I said,
100% of the profits will go to these
mental health organizations that are
really transforming and even saving
lives every day. Um, I'm at Blake
Mikoski on Instagram. That's where I
spend, you know, whenever I do post on
social, it's usually there and I love
sharing with people and connecting with
people. So, that's Blake Mikoski on
Instagram. And I think that's it. And
also, I don't know when it's going to
air, um, but I do have a podcast coming
out, uh, called No Magic Pill, which I'm
going to talk to you about being on my
podcast next. Um, and that's going to
come out in May. So, um Oh, great. Yeah.
Why are you taking so long?
>> I had this idea with this is to enjoy
the process of recording a bunch of
episodes and then almost like releasing
it like a season. Um versus having the
pressure of you know every week or every
other week having to do it. So I I I
it's kind of I look at the podcast a
little bit as an art like an art
project. Like I mean my main focus right
now
>> like your pictures you had been taking
photographs. Yeah. It's it's very much
like that. So I'm enjoying doing it. I'm
doing it in a relax whenever I'm in the
right city with the right person. Like
I'm not really pushing hard. And then I
figured I'd launch it during mental
health awareness month in May because
it's all about that. And then we'll see
if people like it. If they do, I'll do
some more. If not, then it was a fun
project.
>> That's exciting. It, you know, there's
nothing better than talking to people
and learning from them.
>> Oh, I've had a couple great interviews
and so fun.
>> Blake Mosski, thank you so much. Good to
see you. Congratulations.
>> Thank you, Gabby.