i mean i was a single guy like 29 years
old loved argentina i love going down i
love argentina right and so i thought
like okay this is cool once a year right
before school i'll go down there i'll
give a couple hundred kids shoes and
then i'll come back at christmas give
them all shoes make it sustainable and
it'll be like my cool little project
like that was the idea yeah and now
we've given 88 million children wow
[Music]
welcome everyone to the school of
greatness podcast we have the legendary
blake mykoski in the house going to see
man how are you doing that's a nice
introduction
you don't wish my wife would say that
when i when i walk into the into the
kitchen
we have like i don't know probably a
couple hundred mutual friends probably
in this kind of for sure i think every
single book here yeah as a book i've
read and i know the author i was looking
at your instagram page
recently and i saw you know jesse itzler
was doing a video for you and we were
talking about scott harrison and
so many mutual friends who are
entrepreneurs probably adam braun you
probably know and all these guys so a
lot of people been on here a lot of
people have recommended having you on
here so i'm glad you're finally i'm so
glad to be here you uh are are well
known for creating tom's shoes which has
been kind of like the gold standard for
how to run a business with social good
behind it thank you and everyone uses
you as an example they're like well i'm
the tom's shoes of like sunglasses i'm
the tom's shoes of this
coconut oil
right yeah so everyone is kind of doing
this
you buy one and we give one model right
yeah what was your original inspiration
for for doing that and did you think it
would actually last 12 years
and grow or was it like
maybe we'll make it past a few years and
then
yeah a bunch of shoes i mean literally
we we it wasn't even a business we
launched it we called it the thomas
project it was you know um
and what's so interesting is that
there's been so many people that have
emulated this one for one model but we
didn't really think about like we were
creating a model we just wanted to keep
track of it like it's the easiest way to
keep track of this because you know i
was traveling in south america
specifically argentina um
i saw all these kids in the streets you
know street kids you know kind of
sniffing glue and kind of you know
really going through tough times and
none of them had shoes on and i asked
this woman
one day i was like you know why are
these kids not in school and she said
well one of the reasons they're not in
school is they have to have a school
uniform to go to school and part of that
uniform is a pair of shoes a black pair
of shoes actually and they can't afford
it and so if their families can't afford
the uniform the shoes then that they
don't go to school school and take an
education then they get into all kinds
of bad stuff and so um
you know when i think back to that
moment you know the idea i had was so
simple like i basically went and
volunteered with this organization for
the day who had gone and gotten donated
shoes so they went to wealthy families
in buenos aires collected these like
slightly used they weren't even new
shoes but used shoes they took them to
the kids before the school year and that
was their donation and i went and
volunteered and donated shoes and got
the joy of seeing kids get shoes and
that night i came home and i was talking
to my buddy
who was a polo teacher of all things his
name is alejo and i said alejo i said
this is what i did today it was amazing
like i felt so good like i felt like so
full of spirit you know and he said yeah
but what's going to happen when they
need their next pair of shoes
and it was like i went from like a 10 to
like a five and i was like oh like i
don't know and like maybe we didn't
actually do something good today maybe
we just like prolonged a future problem
and that's when i had the is like you
know i've never been in charity i've
never been in philanthropy but i'm an
entrepreneur i've started a few
businesses and what if you could start a
business where every time you sold a
pair of shoes you would give a pair away
and in that way it's really easy for the
customer to understand it's really easy
to keep track of it's not like oh five
percent or 10 or 30 of your sales go to
this non-profit and then how much
actually gets to the kids it was like
okay like you buy a pair we give a pair
that's simple we'll call it one for one
and that was it and it was just like you
know i mean at the time i mean i was
kind of running another company an
online education company that i started
this was like a side project we didn't
have like a business plan we didn't even
have a checking account like it was like
oh let's just do this and truthfully at
the time i mean i was a single guy like
29 years old loved argentina i love
going down i love argentina right and so
i thought like okay this is cool once a
year right before school i'll go down
there i'll give a couple hundred kids
shoes and then i'll come back at
christmas give them all shoes make it
sustainable yeah and it'll be like my
cool little project like that was the
idea yeah yeah and now we've given 88
million children wow man so amazing 88
million and it's it's been amazing and i
think you know the fact that there's
been so many other companies take this
one for one and actually call it a model
now and and emulate it has been one of
the things that i think i and people at
toms are most proud of like it's amazing
that when we read about companies that
are helping people with eyeglasses like
what warby parker's done or you look at
other companies that have done it in
everything from diapers to you know
mattresses i mean it's like there's
actually a really interesting way of
offering a product to someone that they
want to buy
and at the same time help someone who
has a need that would never be able to
afford it and so that's i think one of
the things we're most proud of is that
it has permeated business culture around
the globe how many of these one-for-one
models are out there there's biscuits
we've got thousands yeah i mean i go to
korea and they're they're like there and
it's just i guess it's just one it just
made sense to people like it's like okay
there's a lot of people that that want
something and there's a lot of people
that need something and you connect the
want and the need through commerce you
can actually um you can make it work and
so do you think this model would have
worked 30 40 years ago
for companies i think the i the reason
why i think it what the number one thing
that i say that if you really plot like
the growth of toms 2006 is when i
started it's also the year that facebook
was went off campus
and social media 2007 was the year that
youtube started wow you know so
literally you can apply it's probably
twitter yeah yeah so you can literally
plot our growth to the growth of social
media wow and so it's and and and i
think that the reason that is so
important is and this is why other
brands have emulated this both from a
giving perspective but also from just a
business perspective is that
it became about storytelling and that's
so much what you're about you know right
so it's like it's about like connecting
people to a story to the power to be
part of something bigger than themselves
and you could never do that through
advertising because it wouldn't be
authentic but what is authentic is when
you got your first pair of toms in 2007
and you watched a video of us giving
them to children in argentina you wanted
to post that on your facebook facebook
or myspace it's a big deal back then and
say like look i did this i actually am
wearing these shoes because it's helping
these kids get shoes right and so i
think that's a big part of why we were
able to grow and then the other part of
our growth that is really unique is i
had no investors you know went from zero
to half a billion in sales with no
investors in five years have a billion
in sales in five years six years six
years wow so so that's crazy yeah it's
nuts but these are like affordable shoes
these aren't like yeah 48 300 shoes 40
dollars a lot of money 48 to our boots
stuff like 150 yeah yeah but back then
yeah it's all 40 bucks 40 bucks yeah wow
half a billion in sales yeah but that's
because
of connecting
in a way that allowed the customer to be
the marketer they allowed the customer
to be the hero and the storyteller yeah
champion and so that's what i think is
so unique um and then frankly you know
we got to half a billion in six years
and over the last six years we haven't
grown hardly because it's been hard to
have that fresh story it's been hard to
have
a reason for someone to get as engaged
now people love our shoes and we still
you know sell a ton of shoes every year
and the business has been real
successful and we've helped you know
millions of kids every year get new
shoes so our mission has stayed great
but we haven't had that like
astronomical growth again because
so many people have emulated it that
it's like okay i like your shoes but i'm
not i have no need to go on to twitter
or facebook or you know snapchat or
whatever and tell all my friends i
bought a pair of shoes they'd actually
be weird like it'd be weird if you were
like guess what i got toms shoes today
and they helped give a pair to a child
of need all your your followers would be
like yeah like i knew that started 12
years ago yeah right so unfortunately
our
success and the number of kids that
we've helped around the world while it's
been incredibly gratifying um it hasn't
until recently had like another big
story to tell and so so that's what's
been it you know like any business you
have to kind of then you become more
focused on the fashion trends and
getting the styles right and we built a
great men's business over the last
couple years but that doesn't happen
overnight
do you do you think
a business can thrive off of one story
after 10 years i i don't think so i mean
i think you can i think you can maintain
um so i guess thriving is it's all
relative right like contain me to give
you the same amount of sales yeah like i
think you can maintain that base you
know we've maintained uh you know uh you
know basically a half a billion dollar
business a little bit less than that
over the past you know four or five
years because we have that base and
they're buying the shoes because they're
connected to the mission they respect
toms as a brand they like the style i
like the quality the quality all that
but in order to have you know kind of
another level of growth i think you need
to engage uh your customers in a new
story or in something that they feel
that when they move it makes a
difference and so that's that's been
something that you know is you can never
predict when that's going to happen or
how that's going to happen but i think
when you look at like i mean apple's a
great example of that you know if you
look at the different peaks and valleys
of apple over a 40-year period of time
you know patagonia is a great example of
that like i mean they had you know huge
rush with the original patagonia in the
late 80s i mean i don't know if you had
one when you were a kid but everyone i
knew had one and then they kind of came
down quite a bit and they plateaued and
then in the last five years they've
they've really grown again um so i think
it's you know vans is a great example in
the footwear space where in the 70s it
became the hottest thing then they
almost went bankrupt yeah and then and
then now they're four billion dollar
business or something it's crazy yeah so
wow yeah and how have you stayed
inspired by the same story yeah because
you've had every press coverage there is
possible the last decade sure you're in
every commercial for the first four or
five years yeah i think i remember
seeing like a chase bank commercial one
time yeah att commercial yeah a bunch of
them commercials that were promoted
which also helps sell shoes yeah when
you're doing this when other people are
talking about your story
of the story
um but yeah how do you stay inspired for
that long well it's been hard i mean
part of um what has inspired me a lot in
the last say four to five years as i say
going from being the athlete to the
coach you know like i was like the star
athlete for say the first six or seven
years you're tom brady yeah yeah that's
a nice call i'll take that i'll take
that compliment but but then i i the
only way to stay inspired was to move
more into a coach role and and not just
a coach for people at toms but um so
about four years ago i decided to sell
half the business and the reason i did
that is because at we had built it to
the size we had kind of plateaued we're
trying to figure out how to grow more
international retail things that i
didn't really know a lot about and i
just was lonely i had you know no board
of directors you know no like no no
partners no i mean and every time we
wrote like a 30 million dollar check it
was like my personal checking account
wow like if we want to place a big order
or try to do some new stores i mean it
literally was like the equivalent of
writing a personal check every single
time and so i ended up bringing in a
partner i sold 50 of the business we
brought in a great ceo an amazing guy
from starbucks jim allen who was there
with howard for many years and building
starbucks great servant leader and that
allowed me
a through having you know kind of less
pressure day-to-day to be running
everything but also a huge liquidity
event allowed me to start investing in
other social entrepreneurs so a big part
of what's inspired me the past four
years has not just been like
kind of being the spiritual guide of
toms but really helping other non you
know nonprofits get started other social
entrepreneurs get started and really
seeing them thrive like there's this
great organization i always loved
talking about because one of my very
first investments called art lifting and
it was this really smart uh young
entrepreneur from boston um and when she
was going to school every day as an
undergrad she would see homeless people
on the street um but they would be
trying to sell artwork that they could
create and she was like this if you took
this art and you put it in a gallery and
it wasn't had the stigma of someone
who's homeless you would pay a lot of
money for this right so she created the
first art gallery for profit to
represent you know homeless artists and
she's taken and she's now expanded all
over the world and so now you have all
these amazingly talented people who
unfortunately have had some negative
events in their life that ended up
getting them on the streets now they're
not only selling original pieces and
galleries but then they're licensing
them to like hotel groups like hilton
there's billabong you know board shorts
are buying you know so that's a perfect
example of what's inspired me is it's
called art lifting is is finding people
who are like okay i see a problem in the
world i have a entrepreneurial
for-profit solution and putting them
together and then usually they need some
capital and a little bit of mentorship
and that's where me and my wife have
spent a lot of time wow how many people
have you uh i think we've invested like
30 or 40 of these companies now um and
and and and you know not all of them
have worked out but a lot of them are
are actually thriving businesses now so
yeah it seems like the uh younger
generation wants to buy things that have
more social good behind them sure
there's more houses behind 100
i mean there's some people that are just
like just want the gucci or whatever the
the most fashionable thing but most
people i feel like are
are interested in learning about giving
in a certain way when they when they buy
something that is doing something good
in the world do you think if an
entrepreneur starts a new business today
that they can
grow and thrive without having a giving
back component or
are they more likely to fail without
giving back
you know it's a really good question
something i've thought a lot about and i
get that question a lot like when i
speak at universities and stuff um
i think that a company has to be
transparent
with their social purpose from the
beginning
um to to really connect with especially
gen z and millennial customers i don't
think they have to have a one for one
and i don't think they necessarily even
have to have a percentage of their sales
as going to this thing but i do think
they have to be very clear on why they
exist and it can't be just to make money
so like it could be their supply chain
like everlane is a great example a brand
that says look they just sponsored the
show actually really yeah it hasn't come
out yet but that's one of our sponsors
really great i just found out about it i
couldn't get more yeah that was like
that was not planned i was literally
just looking after the day because i'm
supposed to pick out some great outfits
and i was like this stuff looks really
good it's absolutely great yeah so um
that's a perfect example and everlane i
think is an example of an organization
that while they're not doing one for one
they've been inspired by toms to say
okay like our our mission is to have a
radically transparent supply chain to
provide quality apparel at a price that
is that that cuts out the middleman
right very similar to warby parker did
yeah um and so so everlane's a great
example where they're not giving back
but they're not giving back they're just
saying we're taking that money yeah and
making it making it more transparent and
so i think so to answer your question i
think smart that's what modern business
has to do um you have to have a purpose
bigger than just making money if your
purpose is just to sell a widget make
money i think it's very hard to attract
and retain young customers yeah unless
you're like a software that just has the
best solution for some problems yeah i
think in tech you can get away with it i
think you know in social you know social
media get away with it um you know
probably anything that is highly
addictive coffee
doesn't have a gift bag but but but if
it's something where there's a choice of
multiple brands and all things are equal
i think what you'll find is that um
customers would rather support an
organization that has a social purpose
and a powerful story behind that purpose
right yeah uh how easy is it to create a
social impact business
well i think it's one of the things
that's harder is is you have a
cost structure that's different than a
traditional business now the only way it
financially can make sense is if the
cost it takes to either
have a different supply chain or the
cost it takes to do giving like us
that that cost is not just seen as a
cost but as an investment in your
marketing customer loyalty that is
marketing especially actually so it is
because how many shoes do you give away
or 10 million shoes a year at 10 million
and how much does that cost yeah so
that's costing you know almost say 10
you know that's 50
50 to 70 million dollars a year 50
million a year on giving away products
so it's as opposed to running like
advertising targeting yeah totally but
what you find is is that because
you're doing this and it was more in the
early days than it is now is it is
connecting people to in a way to your
brand that advertising can't buy that's
the difference i think it's like it's
really hard now some brands can get away
with certain types of aspirational
advertising i think nike is a good
example of that where it's just part of
the culture like you know it's like
they create ads that really make you
feel a certain way about the brand which
then causes you to purchase it until you
tell great stories
but most brands if you want to have that
level of intimacy and connection with
your customer it's got to be deeper than
the surface level of advertising and
that's where i think giving is is is
really a unique opportunity or i say
giving meaning also something like the
supply chain of you know transparency to
everland giving back to you it's gonna
have a bigger purpose yeah interesting
if you were starting a business today
and you were starting from scratch yeah
what type of business would you create
that wasn't tom's or anything yeah
you're working on because like an
entrepreneur yeah starting from scratch
would it you know what industry would it
be in
yeah what give-back would it have or
component would it have or transparency
would it have
and why would you do that so i i've
thought about this and and i i have too
many other things going on to do this
business so maybe someone will take this
run with it and build something great
yeah but i really think in the clean
energy space you know i think one of the
biggest issues of our time is going to
be climate change it already is and i
think that there's more technology today
and every day it's like microprocessors
like solar wind like this stuff is
getting more and more affordable and
there's all different types of
incentives to get into these businesses
and i think what's happened is is the
incumbent is these big power companies
and so like it has every like every
check box for me of what is a great
entrepreneur opportunity it's got you
know the the the big guys are slow and
fat and happy there's it's a new
technology that is rapidly getting
better it is what young people really
care about because this environment they
need this earth they need to keep for a
while right um so so i you know if i was
starting from scratch i think there are
so many opportunities in the clean
energy space um that that entrepreneurs
of all different sizes uh could
capitalize on yeah you could you could
uh have an energy company and then with
the
the recycled energy you can give it to a
community
there's so many ways to do that you
could power like a thousand cities a
year or something you know what i mean
one of the biggest things problems we do
a lot of work um you know in places like
malawi or haiti or cambodia right all
these different places that that
oftentimes are you know or people are
living without running water and without
electricity and one of the biggest
health issues is is especially for kids
who are wanting to you know do their
homework and stuff at night it gets dark
very early in some of these communities
different times of the year and they're
inside these these huts or in these
dwellings and they're burning you know
um coal or something to you know have
light but they're breathing that smoke
and they get horrible lung diseases
right and so you know from a public
health perspective giving people solar
or some type of energy
is a game changer it's powerful yeah i'm
curious i remember hearing this maybe
like five years ago maybe it was
five six years ago
about all this negative backlash you
were getting tom shootings
like okay
i can't remember what the articles were
but it's something about like you're
giving the shoes you're not empowering
people to work or this and that right
uh how do you deal with the the critics
or the haters or the backlash of trying
to do good yeah your mission and
intention is to serve humanity yeah and
yet shame on you for trying to do it
right yeah you're hurting people here
you're screwing people out of jobs or
whatever it was yeah member specific
combination of those things combination
of things
how do you handle that type of
uh you know high and then low right
afterwards of the the negative effects
that people were talking about well the
first thing is you develop thick skin
yeah i mean like i remember like i look
at like myself you know six seven years
ago to today and my ability to deal with
critics or the kind of you know faceless
people online that can really can really
dig in on comments on social media or
whatever is tough but at the same time i
think one of the best lessons i learned
was to try to find
the
try to be curious enough to see where
it's coming from and to really see is
there a way to maybe not like get into a
debate with that group but to learn
enough to say like okay well maybe there
is some business opportunity here so one
of the most my favorite stories to tell
is like you know i think it was five six
years ago one of the biggest uh
critiques we were getting was you know
the kind of like you should teach a
person to fish not give them fish and i
was like yeah i agree like in a perfect
world i could teach people to become a
shoemaker they can have shoes for their
kids they can sell them like yes and
that's typically what i find with
critics is they're they're coming from
an idealized uh oftentimes you know even
kind of more um you know kind of
academic perspective and which is great
but but they're not like in real life
they're not like in the one of my
favorite quotes as theodore roosevelt
talks about they're in the arena right
they're not in the arena like they're
outside the arena and so like what you
have to get you have to do
is you have to recognize with empathy
that they're outside the arena
and you have to say okay well how can i
take this and potentially transform it
into something that works in the arena
and so what with this chris the
criticism we were getting around like
well we need to create more jobs like if
you really want to transform people out
of poverty you've got to create basic
needs which is you know food shelter
eyesight you know shoes you know that
education education and then you got to
create jobs and so the shoes pervade
provide education yeah which provides
jobs well right well the shoes can
provide education but i think that in
some level the critique about job
creation was a fair one sure especially
because we got to a scale where we could
by making some changes we could have
an impact on these communities so in
2000 god it's hard to believe 2013 i
said okay by
2016 we were going to create 25 of all
tom's giving shoes in the countries we
give them in that's powerful that's a
big statement we ended up going from 25
goal to 50 in two years wow and it made
us more money
so it was like the best and the reason
it made us more money was we were now
sourcing it like in india and kenya
ethiopia some of these places we were
making the shoes there so we didn't have
the paper shipping which is one of the
most important things or cost things and
we were able to use materials local
materials so we're now creating jobs
we're satisfying a ton of critics and
we're more cost efficient in getting the
shoes to the people that need the most
so the critics were actually a powerful
in that one little case it helped now
there was a lot of other you know
criticisms that probably weren't helpful
but in that case what i learned was
if you just immediately kind of fight
opposition with opposition
then you miss the ability to really you
know to really understand what an
adversary or someone is coming at
because if you understand them enough
then you can potentially use it to your
power and so what i realized was people
were not
critiquing us because they didn't
appreciate our giving model um it
sounded like they didn't appreciate it
but what they really were saying was a
company of your scale should be more
responsible with the supply chain and if
you can you should create you know more
economic stimulation so you know we've
we we've had some failures too like we
tried to do a factory in haiti and it
was that was the first factory we did
outside of our traditional supply chain
and everyone celebrated and president
clinton talked about how great it was it
was all this stuff two years later we
had to shut it down and it was super
painful because what we realized is we
were trying to do something to answer
the critics but we weren't really
thinking about what was good for the
business wow so then we went to india
and we said okay india actually has some
really great factories that by working
with them we can create more jobs in
these communities that desperately need
them and it can be sustainable and now
we make you know school shoes for kids
in india leather school shoes and it's
been great for the business and great
for the impact wow so it's just it's one
of those things where you kind of have
to take the criticism and you have to
look at it um you know with a curious
what i say a beginner's mind um but you
also always have to have in the back
your mind that you you it has to be
sustainable from a business perspective
it can't just be a a serving of critics
you need yeah but it's got to be smart
and that's that's interesting though
uh what would you say is the biggest
challenge you face personally right now
in your life man right now my schedule i
just on the way here my wife and i just
got into it i mean it was just
not not pretty i mean i have two kids i
have a four-year-old and a one-year-old
um you know we split our time between
wyoming and los angeles
um
you know the um i know we're going to
get to it but literally i went from kind
of semi-retired chairman of toms you
know maybe coming to the office you know
a couple times a month to now i've been
like working like i'm back in the
startup days and this is kind of
throwing my family through a tailspin so
wow so my biggest my biggest challenge
right now is i'm so passionate about
this new campaign that we're working on
with toms and i think it's potential
impact on american history
but at the same time
none of my family needs have changed and
my wife's like okay like who's taking
our son to snowboard lessons like you're
you know you know when was the last time
you got quality time with your daughter
when was the last time we had a date
night you know why are you on a plane
again so i think with a lot of people
who are entrepreneurs who love what they
do um one of the biggest challenges is
managing your time because it's it's
just every every thing that is an
opportunity to move your mission forward
is is something you want to waste time
right yeah it takes time yeah
so how do you manage it all then when
you're so so what i'm trying to think
about now because um you know i have
been is is really just um there's a
great book called essentialism if you're
ready yeah yeah yeah so i think that
book's great um and i'm really kind of
trying to go back to that book right now
and start each week with like okay what
are the things that only i can do like
literally like there might be the most
amazing person that wants to meet with
us on this new campaign we're working on
but
they absolutely have to have me in the
room or could they get 90 of what we
could get done if i'm not there but my
chief of staff is there or the head of
marketing or whatever's there and so i
think the biggest thing is just really
trying to
remove yourself from meetings because
that office and takes the most time only
i can do this right so this is what i
need to be spending my time is commit
you know communicating and meeting with
people um you know who have audiences of
engaged people that are or want to be
activated but i need to spend less time
saying yes to
you know meetings and that's and that's
good because i don't really like being
mean right
but it's so hard when you have people
who really have you know great ideas and
and and great opportunities for
partnership not just to say yes and the
next thing you know you have no time on
your calendar yeah i think it's i've
always tried to create the lists of like
all the things i'm doing right now
all the things that i don't need to be
doing that i am doing yeah and the
things that only i can do yeah and then
that third part so critical and try to
just focus on okay well here are two
other lists that
things i'm doing and things i don't need
to be doing but someone else can do like
when we got to start pushing that over
as fast as possible so i can focus more
on that one list of
key things like doing the interviews or
doing the phone calls with the new
introductions with people or the lunch
meetings whatever it made it be yeah
only you
yeah
i think the other thing is is
eliminating uh whenever you hear the
word should in your vocabulary that's
something you probably shouldn't do so
whenever you say i should do this it's
actually your guilt or your way that
you've been programmed to think you have
to do something that you really don't
have to do so i've i've found myself
whenever i catch myself and you know i
should go to that tonight or i should be
in that meeting then i actually know
that's a trigger of no actually you
shouldn't be because if the reason
you're going is because you have this
kind of guilt that you should be there
it's probably it's probably not
absolutely necessary interesting yeah
what do you think entrepreneurs struggle
with the most right now with
uh all the social media out there and
all the different opportunities and
building a team and hiring and managing
people what do you think is
that the biggest challenge
of all of it yeah
you know i think that
right now we're in a very unique time
where there is a lot of capital to a lot
of crappy ideas yeah like you know um
you know uh you know there's a lot of
venture capital getting thrown at
entrepreneurs that that really don't
have real businesses and so i think the
hard thing for entrepreneurs right now
is you know and i worry about
entrepreneurs you know wasting you know
five years of their life
you know chasing something that really
there's not a purpose for just because
they can access the capital and then
they're going to look back and then you
know who knows what's going to happen
with the economy and that capital is not
going to be there but the worst thing is
time because you could spend you know
there's so much capital available now to
mediocre companies and mediocre ideas
that it's not so much about losing that
capital that's going to happen but i
mean venture capitalists are big boys
and big girls and they expect that to
happen
but what worse is the loss of time and
so if you're if your peak time to start
something you know is in your kind of
mid 20s to mid 30s before you have a
family and all these other things and
you can just go focus and you waste that
time on something that's just kind of a
mediocre idea and you never get any
sales exactly
yeah you don't do it because you have so
much capital you can just keep you can
keep trying trying to make it perfect
yeah we always say we always say um uh
don't let it's progress not perfection
yeah and and and and some of the best
things i think that came out of you know
the last bust was the minimum viable
product you know really trying to get
launched it doesn't have to be perfect
try to get revenue try to get customers
so i think the biggest thing uh that i
worry about with the state of
entrepreneurship now is just that
there's just there's just too much
capital yeah i've never taken uh raise
money for anything i've always kind of
like just hustled my own last eight
years that's great and just reinvested
the money back yeah building the team
and everything
and i always get like
friends who are raising money and
they'll raise a few million here and
there
some of them works out someone what
doesn't yeah and they go start a new
thing and raise more money and i'm like
i don't know if i could live with myself
exactly if it didn't work out yeah i
didn't pay these people back yeah no
it's because you can just be like all
right it didn't work out i'm gonna get
you know sorry we took your money yeah
uh we're gonna try something else yeah
for me that
it's more of like the time is not a big
a deal for me it's like letting people
down that believed in me yeah and then i
said sorry i can't pay you back yeah but
i'm gonna go try something else and make
money here yeah i've got nothing to
worry about like yeah i know it's
nothing's on my back because you knew
the risk it's great that you had that
perspective because that's very rare you
know and that's unfortunately um i think
part of the reason that's rare is our
media meaning our financial media you
know has done a horrible job of
celebrating money raising not making
money right it's like this person just
raised this much money and then seven
years later they still haven't done
anything i'm not even going to say the
names of companies that like have like
eclipse tom sometimes in the media like
love and i'm like but they'd make no
money zero money like we've raised a ton
of money yeah and i was like and you
know i'm like isn't the purpose last
time i checked if you start a business
to make money and make it sooner than
later yeah you get this like false
belief around yourself like all the
press is talking about look what people
yeah six people invested in us we got
all these press hits but then three
months later no one talks about you and
you still haven't launched anything for
a year yeah and i just feel like that's
it's so enticing though because you can
have a a nice background or degree sure
yeah and like resume
and have a great pitch deck yeah and
have two or three like key people on
your team and say we've got this next
big idea give us five million bucks
crazy and then live off that for a few
years
and not have to execute yeah yeah
it's not going to last for a long much
longer so if you're an entrepreneur
watching this and you've got some money
i would i would advord it i'd really try
to get something launched i'd try to get
some revenue uh quick because i i think
we're unfortunately we're we're headed
in a direction where there's going to be
some challenges yeah that's tough now so
you took kind of a back seat the last
few years
you sold half of it
um you said you were in and out of the
office like a couple days a month
i'm assuming someone else was running it
yeah yeah yeah yeah someone else is
running it but you're still like the
face i guess the ambassador yeah
chairman and um
but something happened recently i guess
it's been happening for the last couple
of years where all these
uh shootings have been happening in
schools and clubs and bars and things
like that
and one happened here in los angeles
recently
and
what happened to you and your family
when when that happened
yeah so i mean a crazy statistic is you
know in the last
340 days of the year of the year this
year in 2018 we've had over 300 mass
shootings 300 300 what what's considered
a mass shooting more than four people
four people are shot or killed killed i
think yeah four people are killed wow
300 of those 300 in the united states
yeah
is that for real almost one a day yeah
no way do we do we just not hear about
some of these or are there you don't
hear about them um
it's actually communities of color it's
inner cities
yeah i mean this is where gun violence i
mean you know actually it may not be
like a terrorist thing no it's it's this
is plaguing these communities day in day
out the only ones you do hear about it
are the more you know mass shootings at
a club or a synagogue or a bar but
so
you know
what happened was is you know as as many
people we've read about you know
everything you read about what happened
in parkland and we read about you know
what happened just a few month and a
half ago in a synagogue and then you
read about having a yoga studio and
you know it's it
you you somehow you know kind of get a
little bit numb to it because it's
happening so often and you almost start
to expect that this is the new normal
until it happens to you plus or your
community that's that's the thing and
unfortunate i wish that was not the case
but you know in my case that was and it
is what it is but um yeah about a month
ago we had a shooting in thousand oaks
which is 15 minutes from my house um my
12 people were killed
my wife uh called me the next morning i
was actually on my way to tom's um back
of the uber um and i was just like
catching up on some emails and stuff and
she said you know i'm not going to take
our son to school today um and i'm
scared and you know this happened uh in
a synagogue just a couple weeks ago and
i read about a yoga studio and i just
don't know where we're safe anymore
because
thousand oaks is in in the news reports
that it's listed as one of the top 10
safest cities in america wow and so if
it can happen there it can happen
anywhere yeah it's not like it's in the
ghetto in la this is like a suburban
neighborhood suburban neighborhood north
of l.a yeah and so my wife it was
interesting she said you know um she
said someone has to do something about
this and and and i said i agree i agree
and and i said okay well i'll see you
and get home tonight you know she was
pretty emotional
and i got off the phone
and
you know i've told the story now a few
times it was it was as if
i mean if you whatever your religious
beliefs are like it was it was almost
like a divine moment for me where i
realized like she was saying
rhetorically someone has to do something
throwing her hands in the air but
everything in the universe and in my
brain said no that's you like you have a
platform you built a business to help
people like you've got millions of
customers you know you have the access
and you have the resources through tom's
success to you know take some of those
resources and do something and if you
don't do it who's going to do it like i
mean like and so i wrote a very
passionate email to our ceo and to my
partners and our board and i said look
guys like we've been talking about doing
other things for years you know we've
given shoes 88 million pairs we've given
hundreds of thousands of people their
eyesight back through our sunglass
program but we've always been talking
about the last couple years like how do
we have more of an impact on issues in
our country that are plaguing us like
how do we really
dig in right here locally and and really
have an impact beyond these basic needs
and we have been talking about this for
a couple years i said guys if we don't
do something now like this is like one
of the biggest issues of our time i
don't think we're ever going to do
anything besides give us shoes and i
wear and that's fine
and that's great but like if if i'm
really going to be engaged in in our
organization and really feel that we're
walking the walk and you know not just
talking the talk like we got to do
something with something now
and of course they were like whoa
well like come on bike i'd be like yeah
like we personally agree like you know
like this is you know this is really sad
and like you know we could make a
donation and and i and and i said no
guys i don't i really
you know i'm not gonna i can't force us
or want a forces or anything but i
really think this is the moment in time
where our country needs leadership and
needs leadership from the corporate side
and and if and if we don't use our voice
um you know then then then there's just
going to be more and more of this
happening and so we made a really bold
decision within three days we literally
made a commitment so you convinced them
all yeah it took three days three days
to like talk down like how many people
was just ten people five probably about
eight people probably about five people
in terms of my financial partners and
our ceo and then about 10 more people on
the leadership team and
calling them it's eating them it's like
get behind me it's calling them it's
emailing them it's begging them it's
late meetings it's like the most you
know i basically took every single ounce
of relationship capital and wow business
capital i had and said like we have to
do this and
so did you need 100
participation on this or was it no i
didn't i mean i kind of picked one
person off at a time and then over time
you know and the truth is is everyone i
talked to at the company
you know philosophy was like yes like
like we agree like
someone has to do something like this is
getting to epidemic you know proportions
like we personally feel that you know
there's real sensible gun legislation
that we could you know greatly reduce
gun violence but there but the main
thing was like you know you know do we
have you know is this right for our
brand you know are we going to alienate
a lot of customers because this is very
political yeah we might you know you
know and like like and and and and so
there was all this very real concern
about like how it was going to affect
our business
is this are we the right brand to do
this do we have credibility in this
space like all these things which were
very fair and and and something in my
gut and this is where i give a lot of
credit to my partners and our ceo i just
said that guys like i there's only a few
times in your life when you just know
something and i know i can't show you
the data i know i can't say but like i
know in my gut that like we are the ones
to do this wow so that's the type of
conversation that's amazing and so and
they you don't say that all you ever
said that in 10 years
you said that like 12 years ago pretty
quiet i mean there's been a lot of
decisions at tom's the last four or five
years that maybe i wouldn't have made
them exactly that way whether it's a
product thing or distribution thing or
giving strategy so when i spoke out this
strongly
it was a point where it's kind of like
okay
like
if we don't do this then that's gonna
like that's gonna have its own
implications yeah um he might be gone
forever yeah who knows i mean i didn't
never had to do an ultimatum it was
never that way yeah um but but the thing
was is i said guys like look like this
is a moment we built toms because we
believe in a better tomorrow we believe
business can be part of a better
tomorrow and so
this is an opportunity for us to truly
walk the walk to be super super bold and
i know because i know our customers i
built this company from the ground up i
know they'll be there with us wow they
might not agree 100 with us but they
will appreciate the fact that we're
putting it on the line and um so yeah
after three days uh convinced the team
and it was a herculean effort not just
with me but with as i got one or two
people then i you know i started like
cobbling them to everyone together uh
and then three days later we went on
jimmy fallon or i went on jimmy fallon
and so three days of convincing yeah and
then three days later you haven't
created anything yet no no well we were
kind of doing both like i kind of was
like convincing and having a small team
here guys training stuff just in case i
got the in-house startup yeah it was
totally an in-house startup and the
biggest thing we had to do is we created
a simple technology on our home page
which is the other reason why people
were nervous is this is right before the
biggest sales week of the year this is
black friday cyber monday you know all
that stuff wow which is our biggest i
mean riskier our whole year is based on
30 is that week exactly
so and i said i want to take down all
the shoes and put a technology there to
help people send a postcard to the
representatives urging them to pass
universal background checks on black
friday on black friday or two days
before black oh my gosh so that was also
kind of like you know part of the reason
why it was such a heightened like can we
wait a week later and that was a
question and i said no i said look if
you wait a week it looks like a
marketing campaign you know it looks
like it you know it's like you can't
like you gotta if we believe in this and
we don't want another shooting to happen
wow we want to get people you know
moving in the right direction right do
we care more about our profits on black
friday or about saving people's lives
and that was it and then when you had it
that way it was actually an easier
discussion to have because everyone
really at toms is there for the right
reason and even though they want to be
responsible from fiduciary
responsibility they also want to make
sure that if we can actually make a
difference in people's lives we do that
and we've always led that way and i've
been very proud of toms in that regard
but what happened was is we literally
created this simple technology where any
single person in the united states could
go on the website put their name and
address um the address would tell them
you know basically trigger who their
representative is in congress in their
state in their state and then they
percent and then we would print and mail
and pay for the mailing a postcard to
the representative and so the goal was
is to get you know thousands of people
to do this to get all these postcards to
flood the offices of these of these
congress people so that when it comes
back in session they would vote for
universal background checks wow and
universal so it's not like getting rid
of guns all in all no no that's the most
important thing this is for what reason
yeah so so basically we are 100 pro
second amendment 100 pro guns i mean i
grew up in texas hunting i have lots of
friends that are hunters like we have no
problem with guns what we have a problem
with is when guns get in the wrong
people's hands and that's where you see
this huge spike in gun violence so right
now in our country there is no universal
background check at a federal level so
that means you can be a felon you can
get out of jail you can go and buy five
ak-47s no way yes 100
no background no background you can go
get it you can go to the gun show you
can go to you know private dealer you
can do that second thing is you can be a
person that has a mental health track
record uh and go buy guns you can be a
domestic abuser you can have a record of
abusing you know your spouse and go buy
a gun and you can be on the terrorist
watch list and still go by no way i
swear this is why it's so it's like when
i learned this that's why i was like
guys like we're not
this is not a we're not picking a fight
politically this is a human issue 90 of
americans say they're in favor of
universal background checks but there
has not been the political will to get
it done because it's become so
politicized right because people just
hear guns like oh you're taking my guns
away and so that was the biggest thing i
had to
really get across on jimmy fallon and
then the media i did afterwards like
look
we have no problem with guns what we
have a problem with is people going and
buying them in you know so easily where
um where they're not fit to have it wow
and so once we started convincing and
this is what people have been saying in
the media all year and last couple of
years as more shootings happen yeah
they've been bringing up that point
about background checks exactly exactly
they keep talking about it and media
keeps talking about it but no one's been
doing anything when no one created
actually organized way to right how to
harness the voices so what we did is we
did two things we said look we're gonna
make the largest corporate contribution
in the history of the united states we
get five million dollars and that was
five times larger than the second
largest contribution five million
dollars for what for to the
organizations that are working to end
gun violence so that is march for our
lives mothers demand action faith in
action um so these organizations are
doing the hard work because it is a
complex issue of all the different ways
you can you can decrease gun violence
then we created the technology on
toms.com where any american can go and
send a postcard in less than 30 seconds
that was we launched it like i think
like 18 days ago now and this is shown
to be probably you know 24 days or 30
days and we have already had almost 700
000 americans send a postcard crazy i
mean we were hoping to get like 20 000.
really i mean we didn't know i mean like
i mean you know if shooting those stars
would be like it's hard to get people to
act it's hard people to actually take
time out of their day to go to a website
to fill out a form but we realized
there are so many people in our country
that were so fed up of reading about
another shooting and and needed a way to
feel that they could be part of the
solution not just you know saying our
thoughts and prayers are with you like
they actually like there's this pent up
demand we didn't realize at the time for
people to actually have a real
opportunity to act and so by giving them
the ability to go to toms.com to send a
postcard to help get universal
background checks passed it kind of like
unleashed this this pent-up need that so
many people had and it's been amazing
and then the other thing that's been
amazing
and this is something we could never
predicted but some of our biggest
supporters have been gun owners so like
you know the guys who are the um
the uh the lead singer the band florida
georgia line you know country music huge
band you know millions of fans he's a
gun owner and he put a video on
instagram said look i'm a proud gun
owner but i'm also a parent and i've got
a daughter and i don't like the idea
that she's going to go to school and
have to do a lockdown wow you know and
then we had another person that was
cooler and so what we've seen especially
on social media the videos that have
gone the most viral on this have all
been gun owners because they're like
look like i'm a owner like i have no
problem with that but we've got to be
more sensible and i think that's why
we're seeing
this
the tide turning and i you know was
speaking to you know
you know congressman thompson today from
california who's working on the
legislation that's going to be on the
house floor january you know second week
of january and he's like he's like i've
been working on this for six years like
we're this is going to pass in the house
and if we do things properly and keep
showing that the american people want to
be heard like this could be a law and
like that that would be a change in
american history i mean this is
something that over decades has not been
able to happen so it's exciting and so
this is like tom's
like circa 2006 right it feels exactly
like social media taking off and
spreading the story yeah there's a new
uh pain in the world that you're solving
yeah it's like we've in a sense i think
for me personally and i think this is
the lesson for entrepreneurs or anyone
who feels that there's like these peaks
and valleys in their careers like you
need a battle to fight you do otherwise
it's like we're just trying to make more
money yeah and usually we're just trying
to and and even if you're doing
something good even if you're helping
get you know tens of millions of kids
shoes
like over time if you're really an
entrepreneur in your blood you know it's
like you need that battle to fight you
need to do the impossible and so when
when i
you know pitch this to my internal team
and there was resistance i'm actually
glad there was resistance if they would
have said yeah great idea i don't think
we would have executed as well but
because there was some initial
resistance because there was concern
about sales because there's concern
about you know if this was going to be
seen as a political move and and we have
a very equally split politically uh
customer base because of that we
executed so intensely and so carefully
and because of that you know we've seen
um this go viral we've had you know
something like seven billion media
impressions it's three weeks amazing i
mean it's just noisy and so and so to me
what and how have sales been through
black friday yeah so so the great thing
is is we don't have all of our numbers
for our wholesale accounts but all of
our online numbers have been up
and up and up significantly double
digits so not what we were expecting um
because there was no shoes to buy right
was that true or you could go down the
page and find well you can still find
shoes down below but it's like right in
the whole page above the whole above the
fold there was only the postcard wow and
it's been that way for almost two weeks
and we're 700 almost 700 000 as of us
recording this probably when this goes
out close to a million hopefully yeah
yeah and if you're watching and we're
not to a million yet go to the website
and you could be like the final person i
want to go back on jimmy fallon when we
hit a million so what do they do they go
to toms.com yep just right in the whole
page still still it'll still be there
christmas if this is christmas eve we'll
still be on the homepage front and
center through january 1st definitely
through january 1st so it'll be right
there until congress is back in session
test january 4th gotcha it'll take what
do you do 22 seconds 22 seconds you just
type your name your zip code yeah and it
tells you where to send it and you click
send and then we pay for that you pay
for the postage and in the printing of
it yeah deserve thank you at the end
yeah thank you and then thank you has a
button you can click and it will send to
all your twitter facebook everyone smart
yeah and so it becomes a viral loop you
know so that's that's what's been um
so yeah so i mean it's it's it's fired
up about this ah i mean so fired up you
know because i'm excited you get to be
part of a solution like i just hate
hearing about and experiencing things
the pain and suffering in our world
knowing that we have
as humans the tools and the technology
to make it better and i and i and what i
also
am realizing the macro thing that now
has like got me so fired up is
like uh as a brand like we're gonna look
for things going forward that have
become politicized that are not
political or human because there are
more and more things that are dividing
us now that used to be not political and
to me that is the pain point i think
i've identified is there are things and
i don't know what the next thing is
going to be yet but i know there will be
a next thing where it's like look like
this is a human issue that whether
you're on the right or the left or
you're you're from this part of the
world you we all care about the same
thing yeah and tom's can be a business
that brings people together to make
those changes and so that's where i'm
realizing that's really what tom's 2.0
is about and the interesting thing as
you look at like what's what's the
business impact one of the things has
just been fascinating to me is and i saw
the statistics today so it's fresh in my
mind so up until
four weeks ago
85 of our sales were women and 15 male
okay that's been pretty much that way
since i started why is that because the
original shoe we did was this slip-on
called the opera
and it's it's a more feminine looking
shoe there's still a lot of guys
millions of guys have worn it over time
but for the most part it gravitated more
towards women yeah and then because it
was like flat yeah it's like a flat like
you know more thin kind of slip-on
so about two years ago and this is like
kind of you know you know just
look backing now i'm like i'm so
grateful about two years ago we realized
that if we were going to grow our
business and kind of get that next grade
of growth we had to bring on a great
men's designer and we had to create like
boots and and trainers and shoes that
guys could wear you know beyond our
original shoe that we're known for and
so we actually built this amazing
product line for guys in the past two
years the problem is we could never get
any guys attention for them to see it
because
most guys just assume like oh tom's what
my girlfriend wears right that was the
thing or my mom or something like ugh
kind of like yeah exactly uggs is a
great example of this that's why they
hired tom brady exactly
you look cool now yeah but we couldn't
afford to hire tom brady
so we had this issue for two years we
have now we have great men's product but
we never get enough attention because we
don't have a huge marketing budget
because we spend so much money on giving
so
this happens
you know
you know legit you know you know people
who want to end gun violence don't have
a gender connection right so now
about half of our traffic to the website
was guys and half was girls pretty cool
as of now this last week 40 of our sales
are men now no way from 15 to 40. so
think of that because they saw it and
they saw that oh it's cool cool yeah so
they went there for a postcard and then
they saw these boots that are you know
really you know masculine and waterproof
and it's freezing cold and snowing in
wyoming right now and and so one of the
things that's interesting to me is and
this is kind of the entrepreneurial
lesson you can have the right product
but if you don't have the right
mechanism to get the right people in
front of your product your business
isn't going to grow and so what i
realize is while our growth has been
kind of flatlined the last few years
even though our product has been better
than ever the reason it's been flatlined
is we didn't have a fight big enough to
attract
this attention and now that we have
you're not spending advertising no right
yeah yeah and we're spending five
million dollars in giving yeah so it's a
significant investment in resources but
what that's done is it's gotten all
these guys to toms maybe for the first
time and then they see these boots or
they see these sneakers they see these
shoes they're like oh that's that's
actually for me and then and so i think
that what we're going to see if i come
on you know a year from now i think
we're going to have a much bigger
business and i think we're going to have
a business that's much more balanced
from a gender basis which makes it you
know a lot more dependable or
predictable in the future that's pretty
cool so it's been really amazing to me
to see how
many like lessons we've learned in such
a short period of time
just by doing the right thing like it
was just like like at the end of the day
we took a huge leap of you know faith
big risk and it was very risky four
weeks ago it feels less risky today yeah
it seems like you're the smartest guy
yeah yeah yeah well this is my favorite
quotes about entrepreneurs it says when
you're an entrepreneur uh every day you
wake up and you know you're either gonna
be a genius or an idiot but you will
never be a regular guy or girl trying to
get through the day you'll always be
remembered for something right yeah
you'll never be remembered like oh yeah
they were they you know they really got
through the day like it was always
genius or idiot and so i've been an
idiot plenty of times in my career um a
genius maybe a couple times but um and
you know and as this i don't know
ultimately how this is going to affect
the business long term because we're
getting a lot of awareness now but what
i do know is everyone at toms
internally has this kind of renewed
kind of hope and purpose because they
realize that we can
use business use our community use
technology to have an impact in
something that like politicians have had
a hard time doing so that's what's
exciting that's really cool yeah man 700
000 that's cool let's get it to a
million yeah let's get it to a million
go to toms.com right now where you're
listening to this take a screenshot on
your phone yes and tag it on your
instagram story tag you as well i don't
know if you check your instagram yeah
all the time yeah so tag blake and uh
are you at tom
or either at toms you're at blake my
gosh okay yeah blake mykoski make sure
to tag blake and myself uh let's get
this message out there far and wide i
want to ask you uh three final questions
okay great
uh this is called the three truths oh
cool okay three truths so i want you to
imagine that it is you get to choose the
day that it's your last day on earth
okay okay it can be
500 years from now for whatever reason
any day you want okay
okay you've achieved everything you want
you've
grown the businesses helped the
entrepreneurs solve human problems yes
all the things that you want to do in
your lifetime you've done it
and it's a beautiful moment
but it's your time to go you got to go
at some point yeah
and for whatever reason all the things
that you've created in your life your
books your videos your work your
businesses they have to go with you so
no one has access to your information
okay okay but you get to leave behind on
a piece of paper three things you know
to be true about all your experiences in
life wow these would be the three truths
or the three lessons that you would
leave behind to the world
and you'd only get to share three things
what would you say are your three truths
wow that's such a good question
well i think i would start with the
phrase that is is used a lot but it's
been really important to me in my life
um since i was 18. i had one of my best
friends pass away when i when i was 18.
um and i could have been on the plane it
was a plane crash i could have been on
the plane with him and i wasn't
and i i realized that i could never
predict when that day would come
and so that i should make the most of
every day and so when i was 18 i started
signing every letter because we didn't
have email back then
carpe diem seize the day and to this day
every email i ever write i sign at carpe
diem every thank you note i write i sign
it carpe diem every book i sign i carpe
dm because i believe that you know
the greatest honor we can give to the
people who've come and passed before us
um and the greatest kind of honor we can
give to you know whatever your spiritual
belief in terms of how you've been
created is to seize the day is to truly
live every day as if it's your last and
so if this is the last you know uh
conversation i have with someone that
gets recorded you know i want to make it
the best one you know if tonight when i
go home and i read my son his story you
know i want to be present to that
because i want to be the best one so
carpe diem would be that my first truth
um
my my second truth um was also
has been very influential in my life and
it was given to me by a great
entrepreneur named bob deadman bob
deadman started a company called club
corp
and he was one of the largest donors to
smu the college i went to and i got to
meet him
when i started my first business which
was a laundry business and and i asked
him for a piece of advice and at this
stage he was probably in his like late
70s very successful billionaire and i
said you know i said so if you give one
thing write down your piece of advice
kind of like
me and he wrote down on a piece of paper
the more you give the more you live
and and and that i think is absolutely
true like there is nothing that has
given me more joy
more of fulfillment than the moment of
of truly giving and giving like outside
of your comfort zone not just giving
when it feels comfortable or it's an
easy check to write but giving when it
really kind of feels sacrificial giving
when it causes you to get on a plane to
fly halfway around the world to be with
you know kids in the slum like really
the more you give the more you live and
i've never had a day on this planet
where i
involved or incorporated giving into it
that i felt like was not one of the more
meaningful days so i would say carpe
diem the more you give the more you live
and my third one
and this one doesn't come to me like as
immediately as those two because those
have been so ingrained in my life's work
but i do think that um you know
one of the things that i've i've worked
on a lot and my wife has really helped
me a ton is um is is really to be
present you know like like like there's
so many things going on there's so many
digital distractions there's so many you
know people pulling at your time and so
you can come up with all the different
strategies in the world about how to
manage your time or how you're going to
commit to you know certain things and we
talked about that earlier in the show
but but i think the thing is is you can
only truly be in one place at one time
multitasking is kind of i think
like like like i am here right now and i
am fully present with you and i'm
excited about answering these three
truths um but when i get home i only
have the opportunity to be present with
my kids or my wife you know and then
tomorrow if i'm you know with a friend
and having lunch like i have the ability
to be present with them and i think that
i think that that is a practice that
takes a lifetime and you'll never
perfect it um we'll always try to get
better but i think the more moments i
actually have it tattooed right here on
my
on my arm because i want to be reminded
every time i look down like just be
present because that's the only moment
that we actually have is the present and
and the more that you're present
especially with your loved ones and the
people you care about that's what
creates those those memories and those
moments that you will hold on you know
for your entire life wow yeah so seize
the day
uh be president's last one the second
one carpe diem the more you give the
more you the more you give the more you
live and be present i love those man you
talked about your wife a few times
throughout this can you share
the the greatest lesson that she has
taught you
and
uh how important she is in your life
yeah i mean
you know it's it's so interesting
because
when i'm my best self
is when i'm most connected to her you
know like when i'm truly thriving
whether it's in business or with our our
kids or with my friends it's when i'm
i'm really you know really spending time
listening to her and listening to her in
a way that she knows kind of what's best
for me i think that's what her
superpower is she not just me but other
people i think she really can understand
and she has a a gut intuition that
others don't and she can really
understand like when you're in your best
place but but i think the thing that um
that she has taught me the most is is
really goes back to the thing that i
still continue to struggle with though
is is just you know like that that life
is is about these very important moments
with the relationships you have and in
it and you've got to make time on your
calendar to have them you know i mean
she is she is so good at saying no to
things wow and and i'm not we want to
say yes
yeah and she is so good at not answering
emails and so good and not answering
text messages i mean drives you know
people in my life crazy sometimes like
my mom she's like heather is not texting
me back and i'm like
she's present she's present
yeah and so i think the thing that i'm
i'm really grateful to heather is you
know she's really helped me slow down
kind of you know really understand
what's important what relationships what
what do i absolutely have to do versus
just saying yes to everything and
sometimes that's that's the reason i
know that that's so important in my life
is it's also the thing i struggle with
and it's the things that we argue about
and it's like because it is hard to do
but when i do it is when i feel the most
connected and the most present and so
you know it's um it's that and then the
other thing is is she is she is a just a
incredible defender of anything that's
unjust you know she's a huge animal
activist i mean she will do anything for
any animal on the planet um you know she
is the original phone call and saying
someone has to do something about this
after the thousand oaks led to all this
in the ending gun violence i mean when
something is not right you know she is
not afraid to speak out even if it's not
um politically correct even if it's
going to be uncomfortable in a group
setting like she speaks her mind and and
that gives me more confidence to speak
mine and to use my platform to do things
that might be outside of my comfort zone
that's cool sounds like a powerful woman
yeah
very much so well i want to acknowledge
you for a moment for
for doing the challenging things i feel
like you've been leading the way in your
business for a long time doing the thing
that people have said this is crazy you
can't give up you can't give a shoe for
uh selling a shoe that's too much cost
you know how you're gonna build it
for doing the hard thing constantly
because this right now is not like a
popular thing to do with your team with
your business until it is yeah but you
to have the vision and the courage to
constantly
step beyond what's possible is really
inspiring and i would acknowledge you
for constantly
serving other entrepreneurs with your
heart with your leadership with your
words and your actions most importantly
by doing the hard thing
and making a real change in the world so
i acknowledge you for everything like
it's been it's been really cool to
connect with you and and i hope you
achieve everything you want for your
whole life
so make sure you guys go to toms.com
right on the homepage takes 22 seconds
fill out the form uh
send it in they'll pay for everything
and do it all it takes less than 30
seconds check it out right now take a
screenshot of it and you get to
celebrate with us because this is going
to get passed like this is going to
literally change the history of our
country as as it relates to gun
legislation and so one of the reasons
why i'm so passionate about people doing
this is not just because it's going to
be effective but i want to give everyone
a part of the joy to be able to say in
2019 or 2018 christmas eve i sent a
postcard in in 2019 a law was passed
crazy like that's the that's what i want
i want everyone to have that experience
because
it's going to happen wow that's amazing
make sure you guys do that right now
this is a final question we can follow
you on twitter instagram yeah it's at
blakemykosky for twitter instagram
everything and then at toms okay cool
um and for anyone that wants to do that
solar energy give back yeah dmu or yeah
sure maybe we'll invest in the next
freedom the best thing is to dm me on
instagram there you go uh final question
is what's your definition of greatness
[Music]
so
you know my
my definition of greatness
is to l is when is is someone who lives
authentically someone who is present and
someone who really sees the day because
i feel like when you are an authentic
person
and you are present in the moment and
you don't take any moment for granted
that's when you can live your best life
and when you live your best life that's
when you can achieve greatness there you
go yeah thanks so much man thank you
awesome appreciate you
you