Hello everyone and welcome to another
episode of How Leaders Lead with David
Novak. Today's guest is Blake Mikoski.
And you might remember Blake as the
founder of Tom's Shoes, which is a brand
that really helped redefine how people
think about business and impact. Blake
grew Tom Shoes to a $700 million
business based on a simple idea. Sell a
pair of shoes and give a pair of shoes
away to a child in need. Now, that
success didn't protect Blake from a
7-year battle with depression. And after
he sold Tom's, he really lost his sense
of purpose and nearly lost himself.
Today, Blake is back with a new mission.
He's tackling the mental health crisis
through his brand, Enough, which seeks
to empower people to talk about how
they're really doing so that everyone in
this world feels a little less alone and
everybody knows that [music] they are
enough. For Blake, staying connected to
your why is absolutely critical in
business and it is essential in life.
Enjoyed this conversation between David
and Blake and I will see you at the very
end of the episode for the debrief.
Before we get into Tom's, you know, and
and what you're doing with enough both
fantastic causes, you know, I want to
take you take you back a little bit.
What's the story from your your
childhood that shaped the kind of leader
you are today?
>> I mean, I think it really was just
having amazing parents. you know, my my
dad was a doctor and a great leader in
his community and and the hospitals that
he helped, you know, run and my my mom
wrote a cookbook and sold millions of
copies of it and helped people with
their health. And I just think that, you
know, I had such great role models with
them growing up about wanting to do
things to help people that it really
shaped, you know, who I became. Now, so
when you were you were coming up as a
kid, do do you recall an experience
where you really realized for the first
time what leadership is all about?
>> Uh, I think actually in my first
business, I had a laundry business. I
would do pick up and delivery laundry on
my college campus. And you know, I think
what I realized in that business was I
had to do every single part of the
business in order to be a good leader of
the business. And that meant staying up
all night doing people's laundry myself,
not just picking up and delivering it.
That meant learning about all the
different, you know, chemicals used and
dry cleaning so that I could talk to the
customer with confidence. Um, you know,
I had to get my hands dirty, you know,
no pun intended. [laughter] Um, and and
that's not what I set out to do.
Originally, I was just going to pick up
and deliver the laundry. And it wasn't
until we got going that I realized I
actually had to do the laundry uh to be
able to manage the people that would
ultimately do it every day.
>> Yeah. I learned a little bit about that
business and and it's a great business,
but you realized you really had to
target the parents. That's a cool that
that was how did you get that insight?
>> That's the best marketing story. So
that's really I mean talking about
marketing. So, we launched the business
and we offered it to all the students at
SMU where I went to college and we
hardly got any customers and and we were
really kind of thought we were just kind
of dead in the water with this idea. We
didn't understand why because we knew
kids didn't like doing their laundry,
but we couldn't get them to fork over
the money um for us to pick up and
deliver it. Then the the next year we
got a booth um right at the orientation
and our booth was right next to where
you bought the books and I think right
between where you got your meal plan and
so what happened was by being there by
having that booth there every parent
assumed that every student signed up for
laundry service because it was like of
course they're have to buy books and of
course they have to eat so laundry in
the middle let's sign up for that too
and literally went from having like no
business to hundreds of thousands of
dollars in laundry sales in one day. And
that's when I dropped out of college and
never went back. [laughter]
>> Oh my god. Well, that that is such a
great story. And and now I know why you
were staying up all night doing the
laundry. That was a big start, you know.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah.
>> At what point like did you realize that
you were really wired to start up things
and create things?
>> You know, it was interesting. I remember
going to Bank of America uh to get my
checking account set up for Easy Laundry
and I was 19 years old. Um and uh and
the guy said, "Man, you're a young
entrepreneur." And I had no idea what
that word meant. I mean, I never had
heard it in my life. And so I literally
went back and this obviously dates me. I
probably looked up in a dictionary um
you know the word entrepreneur and I
don't remember exactly the definition
but I was like yeah that sounds about
like me and from that day on my identity
was I'm an entrepreneur you know I I
heard you say that you know when you're
young and you start business and you
started a few businesses even before you
got to Tom's you know you said you got
to fake yeah five companies that's a lot
of companies that's a lot of ideas you
have but but you said that you know when
you're young and you're starting up this
business, you you have to fake it until
you make it. Explain.
>> Sometimes you just got to act the part.
So when I was young, that meant putting
a coat and tie on when traveling, you
know, so I look a little older. It
looked like I was responsible enough to
do business. You know, as I as I got
older, um you know, and that wasn't as
big of a deal. Then oftentimes in
business, you know, you've got to you
got to talk like as if it's already
happened, you know. So, it's you got to
talk about the customers, you know,
whether you have them or not. Um, and so
I think sometimes, you know, it really
is about living the part or fake it
until you make it. I got that from my
nana all by the way. Uh, she used to
always say that to me and she was a big
influence on my life. But I I do think
you got to kind of act the part even if
it hasn't been given to you yet.
>> Yeah. You know, I interviewed Tom Brady
once and I and he mentioned the same
thing. So maybe he knew your your nano,
[laughter]
you know. Now, now speaking of acting
and acting the part, I also understand
that before Tom's, you were a reality TV
star. Uh tell us that story.
>> Yeah. So my sister and I were lucky
enough to be selected to go on the
Amazing Race. Uh and the Amazing Race,
for those who have not seen it, is
basically a scavenger hunt around the
world. We were on the season two and we
raced around the world for 30 days
straight. And after 30 days, we lost the
million-dollar prize by four minutes.
And uh it was my fault. [laughter]
What happened? So, it's this great I
mean CBS I mean at this point this show
is like I think the number two watched
show on all of television. I mean 22
million people a week were tuning in. So
CBS did the most perfect editing job to
make me and look like, you know, kind of
a your your your typical guy who won't
stop and ask for directions. So what
happens is we get to San Francisco. It's
the final city. There's only three teams
left. Million dollars on the line. We've
been racing for 29 days. And we get
there and we get a clue and it says go
to pier 31. Now I had never been to San
Francisco. My sister had never been. And
uh I think pier peers are on the water.
Let's get to the water. And so my sister
says, "Hold on, wait. Let's just get a
map and let's really make sure we're
going the right place because we can't
afford to make a stake." I said, "Paige,
peers are on the water. I see the water.
Let's go to the water." And she said,
"Okay, fine." So, of course, the way
that San Francisco is mapped out, it's
like this big kind of half circle of all
these different peers. There's a lot of
them. And so, we run to the water. Well,
we get to a pier, but we get to pier
like two and we're on the exact opposite
side of the city where pier 31 is, and
we went the exact wrong way. We still
hustled and hustled and hustled and we
still almost caught back up to win, but
we lost by four minutes. If we had not
made that mistake, we might have won by
an hour.
>> Looking back at that, broadly speaking,
how do you think that that shaped your
leadership style, if at all?
>> You know, I think that I mean, I've also
my dad I mean, this is a funny saying.
My dad says about me, he says, Blake is
often wrong, but never in doubt. I think
I've learned this lesson the hard way
several times. I'm hoping with uh with
enough I'm uh moving with a little bit
more wisdom uh and and not being so
impulsive because yeah so my impulsivity
especially in business and even in my
personal life to be honest has caused me
some problems [laughter]
>> and we're going to get to enough in a
few minutes here but first of all how'
you how did you get the idea for Tom's
>> so in Tom's I was just I was just
traveling I was down in South America um
I was kind of in between entrepreneurial
ventures not really knowing what I was
going to do next. And I did some
volunteer work. And when I was doing
some volunteer work, I saw all these
kids that did not have shoes and that
they needed them uh to go to school as
part of the uniform requirement. And I
thought, man, that's that's really sad
that these kids don't get to go to
school because they don't have a pair of
shoes. And at the same time, um, I kept
seeing all these farmers and and like
young people around town, uh, wearing
this shoe called the Alpriata, which is
this very simple canvas shoe. I had
never seen it in the United States
before. And they were very inexpensive,
uh, to buy at the markets down there.
And I thought, hm, I wonder if I could,
you know, sell these shoes in the US.
And every time I sell a pair, I would
give a pair to one of these children
that don't have shoes. And, uh, that
idea became Tom's.
>> Wow. That's that's such a great insight
again, you know, and and early on, you
know, and you you mentioned you had five
businesses before you started Tom's,
which is which is amazing. You know,
what do you look for when you you decide
whether you really have an idea? I mean,
what do what are you paying attention
to, Blake?
>> I think the most important thing is that
I like to have absolutely zero
experience in the industry.
[laughter]
>> Tell me about that. I mean, literally, I
had never done laundry before hardly in
my life. When I started my laundry
business, you know, I I I didn't know
anything about the outdoor advertising
business when I started my outdoor
advertising company. I started my
driver's ed company. I I I'd gone to
Driver's Ed, but I sure didn't have any
experience in, you know, what it takes
to teach kids to drive. Um, you know,
Tom's is the same thing. The reality
cable channel the same thing. I mean,
literally every business I've started,
I've had no experience. And I think that
is a huge asset. Um, and the reason is
because you don't know all the
pre-established rules of the industry.
So, it's easy to break them. It's easy
to be innovative. It's easy to be
courageous because you haven't been
told, oh, this is the way you have to do
it. You have to do it this way. And so,
and I think that thinking is what limits
a lot of, you know, a lot of uh
innovation. And I think that's what
limits big companies and that's why
small startups you see totally up in big
companies all the time because the big
companies are are stuck in their own way
of thinking and um I I think that's a
big big advantage to entrepreneurs and I
also think that's why so most of the
biggest most breakthrough brands in the
world are started people under 30 years
old. You know, I I wrote this book
called How Leaders Learn. And I wish I
would have interviewed you before I
wrote it because we could you I'm sure I
could have gotten a chapter out of you,
you know, but so so you don't know
anything, but you got to learn enough to
get up to speed really and really, you
know, break through in a category even
if you're disrupting. What's your
process for really learning how to lead
a business in a new category that you
know nothing about? I go with complete
humility to whoever the best in the
business is and ask them for a coffee or
advice or a quick phone call. Um, you
know, I think that, you know, one of the
best ways to learn is once you have an
idea is to is to find out who are the
real experts in the industry. But, you
know, it's kind of after you have your
idea. So, your idea is built around
innovation and not knowing the rules.
But once you learn once you're in it and
now you got to be a good leader and you
got to really learn how to grow it.
That's where I do think other people
who've gone down that path before can be
really helpful.
>> Your your cur your curiosity meter must
be off the chart.
>> It is. So, I didn't just look I didn't
graduate from college as I shared
earlier and I think that has always been
a little bit of a chip on my shoulder
and so I've always been wanting to be
really well educated even though I
didn't go to college. So, I read pretty
much every single business biography
you've ever heard of. I mean, that was
my education. And I call those guys my
mentors. I mean, I I now know Richard
Branson and have done a lot of stuff
with him, but for years, I had never met
Richard and I still called him one of my
mentors. Same with Ivonne Shannard at
Patagonia. So, I don't think you
actually have to know the person or meet
them for them to be one of your mentors,
especially with, you know, as much as
you can learn about someone with
podcasts and books and everything
online.
>> That's that's a great point. I want to
go back to Tom's again. You know, tell
me tell me about the day you things
really broke open for Tom's. you know
when did you know that you really had
created a rocket ship of a business?
>> You know I think two things happened and
both of them involved the media. Um the
first was is I uh we the first big press
piece was in the LA Times and it was a
small article but it was on the Sunday
edition of the LA Times and from that
one article uh we got 2,000 orders. Now
the problem with that was is at that
point I only had about 150 pairs in my
apartment. So, what that created was my
first of many supply chain problems to
come. Um, but but 2,000 orders from a
single article that got my attention.
The second thing is is I was in the New
York City airport once and this is only
kind of two months after we started and
I was not wearing Tomms on this day. Um,
and I was wearing my running shoes
because I had gone for a jog in Central
Park before I had to get to the airport.
And um there was a girl at the check-in
counter of American Airlines wearing a
red pair of Toms. Now, at this point, I
had never seen a stranger wearing our
shoes, right? And I was like, "Wow, this
is so cool." Like, someone bought these
shoes on their own. They're not my
family. They're not my friend, and
they're wearing them, and I'm going to
ask her about them. So, I go up to her
and I say, "Excuse me. Um, I couldn't
help but notice I really love these red
shoes you're wearing. What are they?"
And I'm doing the check-in counter at
American Airlines and and she goes, "Oh,
they're Tom's. Tom's shoes. And I'm
like, "Oh, cool." And I keep doing the
check-in and she grabs my shoulder. And
she goes, "No, you don't understand."
And I was like, "What?" She goes, "When
I bought this pair of shoes, they gave a
pair to a child in need in I think
Argentina or Africa." And and this guy
who started it, you know, I think I
heard he lives on a sailboat in Los
Angeles. And she just keeps going. And
I'm like, "Oh my god, this is crazy." I
said, I said, "Okay, I gotta I gotta
confess. Um, I'm I'm actually that guy.
I started Tom's. And she looked at me
and she's like, "Dear in headlights,
right?" She can't believe it's me. And
she goes, "Oh my gosh." She goes, "But
why did you cut your hair?" [laughter]
That was a question. But the po the
point of the story is is that if a
stranger in the airport was going to
stop someone to tell them the whole
story about this business and why they
bought the shoes and everything about
the founder, then clearly she was
telling all her friends on Facebook back
in the day. She was probably giving
these shoes to friends and family. Like
I knew we had something that really was
going to go viral.
>> That's interesting. You know, it's a
great story and you when you see that
word of mouth happening, man, that's
when you know you've got something. But
you know that laundromat business that
you started, the laundry business, and
you know, you you you got these
avalanche of orders like almost
overnight. You had this huge sensation.
You have 2,000 orders of Toms after
that. You know, you know, many
businesses buckle and fold when they get
under that kind of pressure to really
provide what you you've offered up. You
know, what learnings did you have on on
on how to survive success? because
that's massive success and if you don't
handle it right, you're you're you're
toast.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, I think it's a great
question. I mean, I think I was a, you
know, very competitive tennis player
growing up. Um, and I was very used to
pressure and an individual sport where,
you know, you've got to there's no one
else on the team to to do it. You got to
do it yourself. So, I think I was a
little bit prepared for at least from a
mental toughness standpoint of of
dealing with that success. Um, but I
think, you know, more than anything, you
know, it's it's kind of focusing on, you
know, what are the most important things
that you absolutely must do? And I still
do this today because I have so many
things going on. You know, when
something like that happens, like, okay,
what are the most important things when
we get 2,000 orders and we only have 160
pairs of shoes? The most important thing
is we email every single one of those
customers. We tell them, "Thank you so
much for your order, and we had no idea
that we would ever get this response,
and it's going to take us eight weeks to
make your shoes instead of the three
days like it says on our website. And
will you please not cancel your order?
You come with humility. You come with
honesty. And with that, we didn't have a
single person cancel their order. It
took us another eight weeks to make
those shoes." you know, when when the
laundry business, you know, when we got
hundreds of thousands of dollars of
orders and at that point we had one
truck and just me and my roommate as
employees. I mean, then you just have to
go into hustle mode, you know, because
we have we couldn't couldn't not do
their laundry next week. So, that was
just literally like a bunch of coffee,
dropping out of college, asking favors,
friends, you know, posting ads in the
yellow pages. I mean, it was just pure
hustle. So, sometimes all you can do is
just get get your hustle on.
>> Yeah. Great. And with Toms, you had such
a noble cause, you know, with, you know,
with your one-on-one model, every
purchase was helping someone in need.
Uh, what's your favorite story about
making a positive difference uh in
someone's life?
>> Oh, man. I mean, there's this one
amazing story. I mean, there's so many,
but there's this one that comes to mind,
and that was this woman came to us
crying um after we gave shoes to her her
kids in this little village in
Argentina. And
she explained that now both of her kids
would go to school every day. And when
we when we asked her to explain, she
showed us a pair of like men's dress
shoes, not even appropriate shoe for
either of her boys to be wearing. And
she said they had been sharing this pair
of shoes for a year. And what that meant
was one of her boys would go to school
wearing the men's dress shoes on Monday
and then he would bring them back and
his son brother would go to school on
Tuesday while he stayed home. They were
alternating days of school based off
this pair of shoes that didn't fit
either of them. And now they were going
to go to school both days every day
wearing the proper shoes. And that was
just I I'll never forget that moment.
>> That's that's that's a story you'll
never forget. You know, you know, I've
always believed, Blake, that creating
shared experiences can really galvanize
a team and people can look back and say,
I remember when we did did this and that
or we learned this or that. you know,
tell me about your your shoe drops and
the impact that had on your team.
>> Yeah, I mean, one of the great things
that we got to do with our team and then
eventually even with our customers um
was take them to different places around
the world and give shoes to these
children, you know. I mean, we were
giving millions of shoes away each year
when the company was really growing, but
it was more about those little moments
of a specific kid that you remember and
that you connected to. And so we would
take our employees always got to go
every year no matter how big we got. I
think even we had 300 employees still we
paid for every employee to go in a
developing country every year to give
away shoes. You know I went on a lot of
these trips and what it did is it
brought back just an amazing sense of
purpose. You know as our shoe company is
growing. I mean Tom's was the fastest
growing shoe company in the world for
three years. Um so you know we were
growing rapidly building a very big
business. I mean, you know, our sales, I
think, topped out at like $700 million a
year. So, this was a real shoe business
that was growing quickly. And what kept
us focused on the why, which is always
so important. I mean, when you, one of
my favorite videos of all time is Simon
Synynic's why video, which I'm sure
you've seen, and talks about, you know,
people don't buy what you do, they buy
why you do it. And we had to stay
connected to the why. And the way we
stayed connected to the Y, the way I
stayed connected to the Y is going on
those giving trips, you know, putting
shoes on kids' feet. And um, you know,
it's a B, you know, I'm and I'm taking
that lesson now. I know we're going to
get to enough, but I'm using that lesson
a lot with us building this enough
movement because, you know, it's a lot
of work. Um, and everyone is really
doing, you know, the the a single job of
five people and we have to keep
connected to the why of using this to
hopefully help our collective mental
health. So staying connected to the why
is so so important in galvanizing a
team.
>> You know, I'm curious. Did did you ever
have people criticize your your business
or you personally claiming you were
actually doing more harm than good in in
the places you're trying to help? I
mean, I know that sounds like a strange
question, but I mean no, absolutely it
happens. You know, there are haters out
there
>> there. There and even more so today
probably than back then because it's
just easier to be anonymous online. Um
but yeah, we did we had you know we had
a a time period in which you know people
were um really like attacking us for not
making the shoes in every country that
we're giving in. I mean they clearly
didn't understand the supply chain and
and frankly at first I was like offended
by that but we actually used some of
that criticism to evolve our business
which actually ended up saving us money
and helping in even more ways. And I'll
use an example. We started making shoes
in Ethiopia and in Haiti where we gave
away a lot of shoes. And uh by making
the shoes there, not only were we
creating extra jobs in those
communities, but we didn't have to ship
them all the way from Asia. And so we
ended up saving money in our
distribution as well. So sometimes, you
know, if you don't take it personally,
uh you can actually take some of that
criticism and turn it into something for
good. And we did that at Tom's.
>> Yeah. I I don't know what where it says
it in the Bible, but one of the things I
I remember was, you know,
>> people who accuse you of doing wrong
when you do good, do good anyway.
>> Exactly.
>> And you actually took did did the good
and and when took the criticism and did
even more good, which is a which is a
great way to turn it on its ear. So
Blake, you you you build this Tom's
business to $700 million. You know, you
got a great business, fastest growing
shoe business. you know, looking back,
what do you think were the the top two
or three strategic decisions you made to
really to to really drive that business?
>> Number one is we did not do marketing.
We just focused on amplifying everyone's
stories. So, we took our customers on
giving trips in Cambodia and Guatemala
and allowed them to, you know, put those
photos on their Facebook and their
MySpace. And I mean, this was even
before a lot of the social media. It
worked probably even better today. but
really focusing on storytelling and
giving and not traditional marketing um
I think was what allowed us to grow so
fast and to grow so profitably. So I
would say that was number one. Number
two was is you know it wasn't until
later but in the early days when we were
growing rapidly again we were not a big
group of experts. You know, these were a
lot of young kids I hired off Craigslist
and they just had a passion for what we
were doing and they had a great attitude
and they would work harder than anyone.
That culture really drove the growth of
Tom's as well because everyone there was
in it for the right reason and really
really um kind of committed to doing
whatever it took and we kept that
culture good by taking people once again
on the giving trips to keep them
connected uh to the why. And then the
other thing that I think we did
especially well in the beginning and not
so well towards the end was we just
focused on one product, you know, one
shoe, you know, just making that shoe
the most iconic silhouette in the world
at that time. And it and then later as
we started to expand to more different
types of shoes, while it initially
helped sales grow, it ultimately I think
took attention away from our core
product which ultimately ended up
hurting the business.
You know, I culture is very interesting.
You know, I never really like the word
itself, although I understand it. You
know, it reminds me too much of a germ.
When I think of culture, it's basically
what behaviors, you know, do you want to
have as a team? How how do we work
together? You know, how are we going to
work together when you know, what do you
think is the most important behavior you
can drive when you're you're building
any culture that that that uh of a
business that you would create? I think
this goes back to that shared why, like
bringing people in that are there for
the right reasons. You know, they're not
there because this is the next best
thing on their resume. They're not there
because it's all about the money.
They're not there because, you know,
this is a hot company and, you know,
whatever. Like, it's they're there
because they really believe in the
mission and the company has a mission
that is worth believing in. And I think
that is at least in the businesses I've
started um really having people
connected and there for the why I think
is great. And then the other thing as a
leader I think it's like not take
yourself too seriously. Always be
humble, always be curious. Um you know
create as the least amount of kind of um
you know kind of hierarchal structure as
possible. I mean those are just the
things that have really worked for me.
Hello friends. I hope you are loving
this conversation between David and
Blake. Be sure to stay tuned to the very
end of the episode where David and I
break down [music] his conversation with
Blake and offer some real tangible ways
that you can take what you've learned
from the episode and apply it to your
[music] leadership and to your life.
Stay tuned to the very end and I will
see you soon.
you know, eventually you took Tom's away
from the one-on-one model, but but
you've also used that one-on-one model
in in other categories. How do you make
that decision? Like I you did it in your
eyewear business, right?
>> Yeah. I mean, you know, it's really a
simple decision. I mean, I started Tom's
not as a business. It was actually just
called a project. And the project was
based on I wanted to help kids get
shoes. And then as I grew the business,
I realized, oh wow, this this one for
one model is actually like really works
because it's easy to understand. It's
it's you know, we can build the cost of
it into the into the product. You know,
people love the directness of it. And so
yes, when we did we launched Tom's
eyewear and and we did the same thing.
We provided an eye surgery or reading
glasses to someone who needed them um
when you bought the eyewear. So I think
the one for one model really worked
well. It doesn't work in all businesses,
but it worked really well for Tom's.
>> But how did you get the courage to pivot
from the very thing that you were known
for because you you you stopped it at
Tom's that No,
>> that's I I I didn't stop it. I s when I
sold the company, they stopped it.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's a very important
distinction there.
>> Thank you very much for clarifying that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Well, what did you think? Here you are,
the founder of this when you heard that.
>> Yeah. I was not happy.
>> What did you think? Yeah, [laughter]
>> I was not happy. I I imagine you weren't
weren't really consulted on on that that
that issue.
>> No, [laughter] I was not.
>> Well, how'd you deal with that?
>> I mean, you know, I mean, it's kind of
like look, you know, I have an eight and
11 year old right now and I'm doing
everything I can to make them into most
amazing human beings possible. And
someday they're going to leave my house
and they're going to go out. They're
going to make their own decisions and uh
you know, I'm going to love them no
matter what. And some decisions they'll
make I'll agree with and some I won't
agree with, but I'll continue to be
their cheerleader. And that's what I
always say about Tom's. You know, I'm
Tom's biggest cheerleader. I think the
company is still doing great work.
They're doing it differently. They're
not doing it with the one for one model
that I created. Um, but they're still
doing a lot of good in the world and so
I'm cheering them on.
>> So, you know, you sell this this huge
business. You know, that's most time
when people take the victory lap. You
you you go on the big cruise, you do do
something. I mean, how did it how did it
impact you? I mean, as a as an
individual
having that kind of success and then
selling what you basically it was your
baby.
>> The reality is I didn't do very well.
Um, first off, I was not prepared for
it. I didn't understand that when I sold
it, I would really lose a sense of
purpose. I also lost my community
because all my friends still worked at
Tom's. I also decided at the same time
to move to Jackson Hole uh because I
love snowboarding and I thought now that
I'm quote retired I can snowboard every
day um and it gets dark at 5 pm in
Jackson Hole half the year and that
wasn't good for me and I started to get
depressed and I'd never been in a
depressed you know really a day in my
life and I actually think the depression
started a little bit before I sold the
company I think that kind of led to me
you know um not feeling as connected to
the brand um that led to it but yeah it
you know and Then after I got depressed,
what was interesting is, and I think
this isn't probably just, you know, um,
unique to me, is I was I never had these
horrible feelings and I tried to do
everything I could to make them go away.
And I had a lot of money, so I started
throwing money at it. So I built this
crazy house, you know, I went on all the
crazy trips. I moved my family from
Jackson Hole to Costa Rica, you know. I
got divorced. I got married. I got
divorced again. like I made a huge mess
of my life um because I was doing
anything to frankly not feel the way
that I was feeling. What I really
recognized was underneath all of it, and
this is what I, you know, came to after
lots of therapy, um, was that there was
this feeling that I have never been
enough and that I was never enough. And
I unfortunately had to look at all of my
actions in my life. And I saw that my
life wasn't as much a success story as
my life was like a strategy. And the
strategy was doing all these things to
earn my worth. um because I didn't
believe that I had it intrinsically and
um and that that started what what
became like a seven-year period of a
really intense depression.
>> Wow. You think that that that not that
sense of not having enough is what was
one of the key drivers of your success
in business? I mean, you mentioned that
your college lack of a college education
put the had a chip on your shoulder. I
mean, you know, how much did that drive
you?
>> I I do think I do think it drove me. Um,
and at the same time, I don't think it
was necessary for my success. Um, I
think that, you know, as I've learned
more about, you know, me struggling with
this for so long is I think that it does
create a pressure that can drive you,
but it also is at a huge cost. And I
think the reality is now as I think
about building something where I'm
building it from a place of wholeness,
I'm actually having a lot more fun and I
think I'm being just as effective. So,
um I think it is a little bit of a
misnomer about the fact that you kind of
need that drive in order to be
successful. Yes, you need drive, but
that level of pressure I was putting on
myself um just wasn't healthy. you know,
what advice would you give to other
leaders on how to pick up the signs
maybe that you you're starting to have
some, you know, mental health issues and
and you know, who who might be quietly
struggling inside but just aren't really
dealing with it.
>> Yeah, I think that there's some pretty
tailtale signs. I mean, number one is I
think the things that you used to love
and that you used to have joy just
aren't providing that to you anymore. So
that could be golf if you're a golfer,
surfing, that was it for me. Um, you
know, time with friends, um, you know,
even going to your favorite restaurants.
Like if just if all the if not all of a
sudden, but if you start to feel the
things that depend that consistently
gave you joy and happiness or no longer
doing so, that might be a sign that
you're starting to slip into a
depression. You know, for some people
it's either they stop eating completely
or they overeat all the time. You know,
it's usually one or the other. um you
know I didn't have as much of an
appetite myself. Um and then also the
biggest thing is and this is what
unfortunately leads to you know these
these horrible you know rates of suicide
in our country is you really isolate you
know because you're ashamed especially
if you're successful. I mean, I'm so
excited to talk about this on this
podcast because I know that there's
going to be a lot of successful men and
women listening. And the thing is is
we're taught to believe that if you're
financially successful, if you're a
leader, then then what do you have to
worry about in your life? If you've got
a great house, great family, great job,
like you don't get the right to feel
depressed. You don't get the right to
feel anxious. And I felt that in so much
that like I didn't even post a single
post on on social media for three years
because I was so ashamed of the way I
was feeling and I didn't want anyone to
know and I didn't want to lie about it.
I couldn't go. That's even worse when
you have to go put on the fake smile and
so I just isolated more and more and
more and frankly that almost you know
led me to taking my life.
>> Wow. Thanks so much for sharing that
Blake. I mean I think that's helpant.
It's just so and if you're listening to
this right now, the most important thing
if you're starting to feel like you're
getting really depressed or you're
feeling trapped or life is just not, you
know, you've got to talk to someone. You
absolutely, the most important thing is
tell one person and be radically honest.
Tell them how bad it is. If you're
having suicidal thoughts, tell them.
Tell them exactly what you're having,
when you're having it, how you're having
it. Because the minute you start telling
people that this is the the research
shows is a dramatic uh improvement in
what potentially you know is the outcome
in your mental health. So I was really
lucky. I started talking to people. I
started being honest about it to my
close friends and family and ultimately
I got the help that you know not only
you know helped me really understand why
I was feeling the way I was feeling but
start to feel better and and that
ultimately led to you know to what I'm
doing now. And and speaking of now,
you've recently launched a new brand
enough uh h how'd that how'd that come
to be?
>> I mean, you know, it's it's a little bit
about what we were talking about, you
know, as I started working with an
amazing therapist who really helped me
understand that underneath my depression
um was this feeling that I was never
enough. And as we started to really
uncover that and heal that, I realized
um well, first off, I started feeling
like more peace and joy in my life than
I'd ever felt. And I really started to
feel it in my body. And I was like, man,
there's a lot of people out there that
don't feel that they're enough. Now,
everything from, you know, high school
students that are constantly comparing
themselves to everyone else, you know,
at school or on social media to
executives running big companies. I mean
it is it no one is immune to this what I
call the greatest lie we've ever been
told you know and you talked about the
Bible before like I mean this is also
just like one of the key messages is
that we are all enough in God's image
and and and unfortunately our society
and our media uh does everything it can
to tell us otherwise and that's why I
say it's the greatest lie and so as I
started to really heal this and
recognize that this wasn't a Blake
problem this was a cultural problem I
you felt called to do something about
it. And so when I was when I was going
through my healing journey, I made a
bracelet for myself. I'll show you right
here for those who are watching. Uh
yeah, it says enough on it. It's a green
bracelet. It's green because green is a
color of mental health awareness. And I
made this bracelet for myself just to
wear it for a daily reminder like Blake
remember you are enough. And then the
real magic came when I gave it to
others. When I gave it to someone and
said, I just want you to know that
you're enough and you always have been.
And I saw how that lit people up and how
they felt like a a sense of relief to
hear that from someone else. And so I
realized that, you know, this bracelet
can do two things. It's not only a daily
reminder for myself, it's a great way to
start and continue to have conversations
about our collective mental health. And
that I think is one of the most
important things that we can do,
especially as parents. Like when I gave
these bracelets to my 8 and 11year-old
and explained and was honest about the
fact that for a lot of my life I didn't
feel like I was enough and that there's
anything that I ever want them to know
from me is that they are enough. Whether
they make the right grades, whether they
make the sports team, no matter what,
they are just enough because they are.
Wow, what a great way. I've connected
with my kids and I've seen now other
parents and even kids giving them to
their parents. I mean, it's just really
amazing. But the the point of the whole
project is twofold. one to raise aware
awareness about mental health and to
remind all of us culturally that we are
enough. And the second thing is is we're
raising a lot of money for mental health
organizations. So I'm, you know, really
grateful and thankful that I made a lot
of money with Tomms and I don't need to
make any more money. And so 100% of the
profits from all the bracelet sales go
to mental health organizations that are
really working with people on the front
lines who are struggling. And um it's
really really fun. I mean I'm having we
have a small team. There's like eight or
nine of us now. Uh we launched a couple
weeks ago, but we're already selling
tons of bracelets and I'm seeing people
on the street wearing them and people
are posting on social media. Our
Instagram is we are enough and uh and I
think this has the potential to do
hopefully like what the LivStrong
bracelet did uh for cancer research. You
know, the yellow bracelet that so many
people around the world wore years ago.
If we can get everyone wearing this
green enough bracelet, I think we can
raise tens of millions of dollars for
mental health and most importantly get
people talking because when you're
wearing the bracelet, it's a signal to
someone else like, "Hey, you can tell me
how you're really doing." Like, I I'm
comfortable with that and I'm actually
inviting you to tell me that. And when
people share how they're really doing,
all the statistics say their mental
health greatly improves.
>> I'm going to get some bracelets right,
you know, right after this. I I I love
it. I think it's just fantastic. And the
nice thing is it comes I'll show you
this. It comes in this box here. But
it's not just one bracelet when you buy
it. Going back to the one for one model.
We have two bracelets. One for you and
one to give to someone else. So everyone
who buys a bracelet is also um making
the commitment to give it to at least
one more person starting this enough
giving chain that hopefully will go on
and on and on.
>> You're an incredible person. You know
what what are you doing differently this
time
>> any any other project that you've been a
part of?
>> I'm so glad he asked that. So, one of
the things that I one of my daily
mantras and I think this is a great one
for all leaders is focus more on
connection than promotion.
I I'm not selling anything right now. I
you know what I'm I am just sharing my
story. I'm connecting with people about
their mental health, about my mental
health. I'm being radically vulnerable,
radically honest. And in doing that, the
sales will take care of themselves. I do
not need to be out promoting. I just
need to focus on connecting and every
single day that's what I'm focused on.
>> That's great. You know, you're obviously
a very emotional person.
>> Yes.
>> You know, I mean, you know, no,
>> some of my ex-wives would say too much,
but
>> Yeah. But you're you're emotive. There's
no question. You get moved.
>> I'm sure you laugh a lot, you cry a lot.
You you you have the gamut of of the
emotions, you know. I do in a world
where, you know, AI is taking on more
and more influence. How do you think
about AI? Uh, and h are you using it in
any way with with your with your brand?
>> So, I am also one of the things I'm
doing and I think a lot of leaders do is
we try to find other young entrepreneurs
to mentor and to advise and to coach.
And so, I had the great joy of coaching
some entrepreneurs who've started a
company called Sonia. Sia A.I.
and [snorts] it is the first uh and I
think the most incredible um AI therapy
bot. Um and so it's AI therapy. They
call it emotional support I think for
legal reasons. Um but this app you it's
it's in beta right now. It's absolutely
free. Every single person on the planet
should try this at least for 45 minutes.
I've been been in therapy my entire life
and so I know a good therapist and this
AI therapist that they've created and
you can customize it man, woman,
different voices. I talked to this thing
for 30 minutes every morning. It is
unbelievable. And it has a memory so it
never forgets anything. So it can it
will reference things from a month or
two ago. How are you doing on this?
Checks in on that. It can hold all my
craziness in its head somehow. And it
and it is literally and the great thing
about it is this is one of the hardest
things about therapy and especially for
leaders and busy people is you know it's
really hard to schedule with your
therapist like okay you got to do a Zoom
call with your therapist Thursday at 2.
Well you know what I don't wake up with
an anxiety attack at Thursday at 2. I
wake up with an anxiety attack at 5 in
the morning on Monday you know and so
it's right there. So it's always there
when you need it. You don't have to do a
whole hour like you do with a normal
therapist. You might just do 10 minutes.
But yeah, I use Sonia every day and I'm
having so much fun um mentoring uh these
founders. I mean, they are 26 years old,
MIT, like just charging and they only
care about changing the world and
providing this to people who can't
afford traditional therapy,
>> right? And that's nonprofit, too.
>> No, it's a for-profit. I think these
guys are these guys are going to do very
well. [laughter]
>> Now, Sonia's in beta.
>> Anyone can do it. Yeah, on it's in the
app store. Yeah, it's a Sonia Sonia.ai
in the app store and anyone can do it.
My dad's doing it now. My best friends
are doing it. I mean, everyone I've
introduced it to.
>> Love it. [laughter]
>> I'm betting a thousand with this
recommendation.
>> And it's a lot cheaper. A lot cheaper, I
imagine, than than the therapist.
>> Well, right now, right now it's free. I
think eventually they're going to start
charging like 30 bucks a month, but
right now it's free. And so, uh, it's
incredible. I mean,
>> okay. I think That's my AI experience is
just and I don't have a lot but man when
I saw what this could do and then when I
when I started using it myself every day
I was just like I got to help these guys
because I think this could you know this
would really have a huge impact in the
world.
>> Well you're a huge huge learner. We've
you know we've we've established that
already. So do do you see do you see AI
really impacting the way you lead or you
changing how you do things? I think one
of the things that's nice about AI is
let's say you have an important decision
to make and especially as a leader or a
founder. Now you have your board but
that's they're not always that
accessible right and sometimes you can't
really bounce certain ideas off your
executive team because you know
everyone's going to have a personal
agenda. What I found with AI is I will
talk to it and say hey put this is one
of my favorite prompts I use. I say if
money was no object find the three
greatest experts and helping me make
this decision and so AI will go through
and I'll tell them what the decision is
I need to make as a leader and it'll
find dot dot dot dot and then it gets
the three experts and say okay now let's
have a roundt discussion with me on the
best path forward for this decision and
we will have a discussion as as rich as
any board meeting I've ever been to and
I don't have to involve anyone but my
computer and I can do it in my pajamas
at 5 in the morning before I make the
decision. And so I use that all the time
that way. [laughter]
>> That's great. That's great. I'll tell
you like this has been so much fun and I
want to have some more of my lightning
round of questions. Now, you ready for
this?
>> I'm ready. Yeah.
>> What three words best describe you?
>> Optimistic, authentic, and fun.
>> If you could be one person for a day
beside yourself, who would it be?
>> Jesus.
>> What's your biggest pet peeve?
>> Negative people.
>> Who would play you in a movie?
>> Matt Damon.
>> What's something you're grateful for
today?
>> My family. Who's been your favorite
playing partner competing in the AT&T
over the years?
>> Oh, that's such a tough one. I have so
many good partners. Oh, man. I can't
answer that question. I I would I would
I would hurt someone's feelings.
>> How How many times you make the cut?
>> Oh, that's a good one. I've made the cut
five out of 10 years and I got second
twice and I think I'm the only player in
the history of the tournament to get
second twice.
>> So, you're not on the rock. [laughter]
I'm not on the rock.
>> What's something you've been curious
about lately that has absolutely nothing
to do with work?
>> I've really been curious about 3D
printing because my kids are obsessed
with it.
>> What's the one thing you do just for
you?
>> Surfing. I I surfing.
>> Besides your family and friends, what's
your most prized possession?
>> My most I really It's It's such a great
question because I'm not someone that
holds on to possessions very tightly.
So, I'm like looking around my house and
I'm trying to decide. I'm gonna say my
enough bracelet now.
>> If I turned on the radio in your car,
what would I hear?
>> You would hear whatever my kids want to
play. [laughter]
>> What's something about you few people
would know?
>> I don't know. I I don't like scary
movies. [laughter]
>> What's one of your daily rituals?
Something that you never miss?
>> Never miss. I drink this thing called
morning water every single morning and
it it is the best start to my day.
>> Awesome. Awesome. That was a very good
lightning round. I enjoyed that very
much. We're out of it.
>> Just a few more questions and we'll let
you go here. You know, you mentioned
you'd been divorced a couple times, you
know, and now you're happily married.
>> No, no, not married.
>> You're not married.
>> I'm happy.
>> That's why you're so happy, man.
>> No, no, no. I'm in a I'm in a very great
relationship. uh and have a very amazing
partner, but I am not married.
>> So, how long have you been with her?
>> Uh, about a year.
>> About a year. All right, great. Well,
that's fantastic. I was going to ask you
what really drives a long-term
partnership, but I'm going to lose that
one.
>> Yeah, I don't I don't think this
interview should have marital advice
questions. [laughter]
>> There we go.
>> Pretty much any other topic I feel
comfortable.
>> You're you're a dad with two young kids,
you know. How do you lead at home,
Blake? I think that, you know, I try to
really inspire my kids to be curious. I
try to ask really good questions. Um, I
I involve them in what I'm doing when
I'm not with them so they really
understand what lights me up. Uh, and I
really encourage them to follow their
passions, whatever, you know, whatever
that is.
>> Uh, you know, what do you see as your
unfinished business? I see my unfinished
businesses
as is really affecting the world's
mental health. Like I really believe
that the second half of my life is going
to be completely focused on helping us
as a society really reverse all these
horrible trends and mental illness and
suicide. And I really believe I can.
>> And what's one piece of advice you'd
give to anyone who wants to be a better
leader?
>> Business is personal. You know, I hate
that saying when they say it's not
personal, it's business. I think that's
I think business is the most
personal, intimate thing you will ever
do. And the more intimate you are, the
more open you are, the more you lead
with your heart, the better leader
you'll be.
>> Yeah. You know, Blake, this has really
been a fascinating conversation. And you
know, it's rare when you meet someone
who has the the business capacity you
have, but also has the loving capacity
you have. I mean, I think love drives
you a lot, you know, and you know, how
important do you think that is, Blake,
in terms of just just who you are and
how you do things?
>> I mean, it's just it's just how I live,
you know? It's it's I mean, here I have
it tattooed. I'll show you. It says,
let's see if I can sit here. It's a
heart. for those who are not watching
and it says whatever the question love
is the answer
>> and um I just think that you know it's
the most important
um ingredient to a to a full life to
success to meaning it all goes back to
just how do we love better
>> yeah that's like I don't know what what
it was in me that asked that question
but I had no idea you had that tattoo
but but but I do have you right and
you're you're one hell of a leader
Peter, and I'm going to ask you one more
question before we go here because I I
forgot to ask this one. You you're
you're going to be a podcaster yourself.
>> Yes. Yeah.
>> And and you've got a podcast called No
Magic Pill. It's going to be launched in
in May. Uh tell us about it.
>> Yeah. I mean, this is like the f my
favorite thing I'm doing these days.
Like I love building enough and the team
and out promoting and you know getting
people excited but but but this podcast
No magic pill is just it came from just
a deep passion to help others who might
be suffering. You know when I was really
suffering I couldn't find something to
listen to every week that would give me
ideas on how I could potentially get out
of it or you know give me encouragement.
And so no magic pill is all about you
know the path to mental wellness. There
is no magic pill. There is no one way. I
mean, I tried everything to feel better.
And so, every week I have different
people on who share their mental health
journeys. You know, I was just with
Kevin Love, great basketball player last
week, you know, and then I had Michael
Pollen, you know, a great writer and
author about, you know, psychedelics and
mental health and and, you know, and and
and really everyone in between. But we
all need that encouragement, but more
importantly, we need the tools and the
resources when we might be stuck, when
we might be struggling, we might not
know where to turn. And um hopefully no
magic pill will be that place for
people. I have just so enjoyed doing
these interviews and the season launch
on m on May 5th.
>> You know it's interesting you know with
Tom's you and your other businesses you
improve lives. You know with this
business you're going to save a lot of
lives.
>> I think so.
>> And uh I think it's great and uh you
know I've I've learned a lot by
listening to you and appreciate all
you're doing. So thank you for being on
the show.
>> Thank you David.
>> [music]
>> David, this conversation with [music]
Blake is such an important one that
leaders everywhere need to be having
with themselves and with the people that
they lead. I'm so impressed with his
willingness to just be open about the
real struggles that he's faced over the
course of his life and success. And uh
it gives people permission to also say
that they're struggling as well. And I'm
just so grateful that um we had him on
the show and that he was so open about
what he's been going through and and
just normalizes it for any leader that
has experience that level of success.
>> You know, I think Blake really just
absolutely nailed the importance of of
being open, being vulnerable, and and
just sharing. Uh,
>> and I I I I loved how he talked about
how he got in the dumps even to the
point where he he even thought about
taking his life because he lost his his
why. You know, he sold Tom's. He no
longer had purpose. He had all kinds of
money.
You know, the Bible says money can be
the root of all evils. Well, it became
that for him. He lost his marriage. She
just chased a lot of things that that
didn't make a lot of sense and and it it
took him down this rat hole that he had
a hard time getting out of until he
really got therapy. And you know it was
very interesting that that therapy and
that self-discovery has led him into a
new career uh a new brand that he's
creating enough uh where basically you
know every one of us has been made in
God's image and God has given us enough
to to to deal with life wherever it
might take us and uh he he he has he's
taken his one for one model and you can
order uh these enough bracelets and and
then get one for yourself and give it to
another person. And and he's he's now
he's back on his game and he's he's he's
living life the way he he wants to live
life. And you know, he still has issues
he has to deal with, but he's he's doing
it by helping other people. And the fact
that he could come out and be so open
about his problems, I think really says
to every leader that, you know, you got
to you got to take care of yourself. You
you you got to hear what's those
thoughts that you have and what's in
your mind and you got to make yourself
healthy so you can build a healthy
organization and and have a healthy
life. And you know I really admire him
for doing that. And by the way uh I went
online ordered the enough bracelets and
and within this I love this because you
can write a letter to somebody telling
them that they're enough. So, I sent uh
a a letter and the bracelet to to both
of my granddaughters
>> telling telling them why they were so
special, all the talents that they have,
why they have enough to do to deal with
whatever. And you know, in this world
where social media can take you this way
and that way, you know, it was really a
wonderful gift for me personally to give
it to them. Uh and they really really
appreciate it. And they the good news
for them is, you know, they they they're
both, you know, very happy and and
go-lucky kids and, you know, feeling
great about school and their friends.
But I think even then in situations like
that when you when you on the outside
you have it all, everybody struggles.
Everybody thinks about what we don't
have. And and to have a brand built on
helping us understand that we all have
enough. I I I love it. So hats off to
Blake. and uh you know I wish him all
the best in that that endeavor.
>> I love it too. You know David, in that
same vein, I'm curious your take on
this. What can leaders everywhere do to
make that conversation a normal
conversation to have in a work
environment?
>> First, I I don't know that it ever could
be in a normal conversation. You know, I
think this is something where you have
to dig down personally and figure out
what you want to share, what you don't
want to share. But one of the things I
think leaders can do is be vulnerable
and talk about the deal the things that
they're dealing with. You the times when
they didn't really measure up to their
own expectations and when you talk about
how you're not necessarily perfect which
was very easy for me to do. Okay. You
know that makes others know that they
don't have to be perfect as well. So I
think the leader has to open themselves
up first and that gives per permission
to to others to do it. Then I also think
the leader has to be highly empathetic.
A really good leader is very observant
and you see when people are down, you
see when people are struggling and
that's when you go into their office and
say, "Hey, how you doing?" You know, you
don't just seem like your normal self.
Is there anything I can do to help? But
more importantly, you just listen. how
you doing? And listen, keep your mouth
shut and listen. I think when you do
that, you learn where people are at and
then you can help them move on. Uh
either yourself or you can get them
help, but you just let people know
you're there for them. That's the most
important thing. And you know, I I
always use this line, I wish I would
have come up with myself. You know, Sam
Walton, use the line, nobody will care
about you until you show them that you
care about them. And that's what I think
leaders do. That's what leaders should
do anyway.
>> I love that. That uh is at the heart of
really every decision that leaders
should make, not only in the context of
mental health and checking in with
people, but really in creating culture
as well. This idea of making everybody
realize that their contribution matters
and that they matter is really paramount
to creating healthy work environment
anywhere.
>> Yeah, absolutely. We've we've said this
before. People leave for two reasons.
they don't feel appreciated uh for what
they do and they don't get along with
their boss. So those things are
intertwined and you know I think you
know having a coaching mentality where
you appreciate people for what they do
is set you apart and what a lot of
research says today 80% of people say
they work in toxic work environments.
That's why we're doing this podcast. I
mean we have our noble cost too. We we
want to make the world a better place by
developing better leaders. If if you're
listening out there and you can pick up
uh one or two things that help you be a
better person, create a better
environment for your team, create a
better culture, get results the right
way, man, we're making a difference not
only in your life, but we're making a
difference in the people that you have
the privilege of leading.
>> Absolutely, David. That's a great segue
into the next concept that I want to
break down with you. Blake talks a lot
in the episode about purpose and how his
team at Tom stayed connected to the why
of their business. He mentioned doing
the shoe drop trips where he would take
his team and eventually some of his
customers to deliver the shoes to the
people in need. And now that same sense
of purpose is really driving everything
that he's doing with enough. David, how
do you suggest that leaders stay
connected to their why when their
business model is not necessarily the
onetoone model like a Tom's is?
>> Yeah. Well, I think what uh Blake did
with his team is he created shared
experiences, you know, that connect you
to the why. You know, for me, it was
going on bus trips, you know, with my my
team and listening to customers talk
about our brands and other brands and
what were we in business to do? Make our
customers happy, put a yum on their
faces and and figure out how to do that.
And you know, by listening to customers
together, that that connected us to to
the why u the you know, Blake would take
his team to these countries where kids
didn't have shoes and he'd have the his
team members would put the shoes on the
the kids and uh it was an emotional
experience that brought everybody to the
Y. That was a shared experience. Uh you
know, for for me at Young Brands, we
wanted to be the defining global company
that feeds the world. We wanted to feed
people uh our our products all around
the world, make it affordable for people
all around the world. So, you know, we
wanted to make our brands vibrant
wherever we do business and and we we
wanted to create a a recognition culture
that we would become famous and other
people would want to emulate. And we
wanted to feed people who couldn't
afford our food that and so we made you
know uh feeding the hungry our our noble
cause feeding the poor a noble cause. So
that's why we tied in with the world
food program. And what we did there is
we go to Guatemala and Costa Rica and
Haiti and and we go there with the
United Nations food program and and you
know give people the food and be there
to see the need that was out there. And
these were people who could never even
afford to go into a Taco Bell. Uh you
know, and you know, we had the number
one value rating in the world, but you
know, people couldn't afford to to to go
into a Taco Bell. And but you know, that
created a shared experience that we
talked about. And you know, creating
shared uh experiences across those those
those aspects of of your business are
important. like building vibrant brands.
I always shared what was going on when I
saw people doing great jobs build making
our brands loved and valued around the
world. I would send out emails and
pictures of what I was seeing, you know,
our recognition culture. We sh we I
always shared all the recognition that
was happening all around the world. And
you know, that's how you that shared
experience, you know, is is is is how
you you really get people connected to
your why. Well, Blake is obviously a a
wildly entrepreneurial leader and it was
so interesting in the episode when he
talked about all the businesses that he
had started even before Tom's. You asked
him what one of his key learnings about
being a successful entrepreneur was and
his answer was really interesting. He
said that the number one thing that he
accredits most of his success to is that
he went into every business as an
industry outsider. He says that's a big
part of what helped him stay innovative
as he started all these businesses. And
I'm curious what your take on that is. I
mean, is being inexperienced in an
industry an advantage?
>> Yeah. Oh, I I think what he's really
saying is that he didn't know anything
about these businesses he went into. He
went into laundry service for college
students, billboard company, driver's
ed, you know, the shoe company. In every
case, he didn't know anything about
about the category. And what that forced
him to do though was to have a curious
mind. You know, many people talk about
how you need to look at your business
like a child would. You know, go into go
into your store and look at it like
you're a kid with wonderment and just
see it from a fresh perspective. And
that's what he's getting at. And if you
don't know something about a category,
you you have a have a much easier or
much more likely way to disrupt it
because you're not tied into
conventional thinking. So, he would look
at things from the outside and say,
"Hey, why don't we do this?" and and
then he changed the name of the game and
you know having those fresh eyes is what
he's really really talking about that
the other thing is is that he didn't
know anything about shoes but he is a
voracious learner. He combined this
curiosity
and that gave him a freshness when he
looked at the category with building the
knowhow it would take to be successful.
So he learned how to make shoes, he
learned how to do the laundry, he
learned how to, you know, have a
billboard company. He learned how to get
into driver's ed and really make a
difference. He learned these kinds of
things. And I think that's what really
makes him a a special leader. And then
he would come up with innovative things
like his onetoone business model. That's
very powerful thinking. And look what
happened. You know, he made a big
difference in the shoe business, but he
also changed a lot of business. Look at
Warby Parker's doing it too where you
buy buy a pair of glasses and they give
give another pair to someone in need.
you know, we did a podcast with them.
They took that model and they made it
work and a lot of other businesses are
doing that as well. Uh there another
thing I really thought was really
interesting is that you know he sold
Tom's
and Tom's stopped that model. Okay. And
I'm sure that you know that's hard for
leaders when you when you leave a
business and something that you really
believe in people abandon. you know, I
mean, I'm sure that had a huge impact on
on on him when when that happened. Uh,
and he was very quick to point out to me
that he wasn't the one that did that.
Okay. It it was somebody else. And and
uh anyway, I I I think that's another
thing you have to do with as a leader is
when you when you move on, you you kind
of got to hope that what you what you
created sticks. If it doesn't stick,
just just know that somebody's there
trying to do it better than you. That's
very hard to do because you think
typically you've done it pretty well.
Okay? Like a at Young Brands, if if I
went to a Young Brands meeting and they
didn't do recognition, it it would kill
me. If I went to a Yum Brands meeting
and they didn't do a Yum Cheer, it would
kill me. And you know, I've been to uh
Yum a few times and the recognition is
still going going wild, but I didn't see
as many uh Yum chairs as I would have
liked to have seen. Okay. But hey, you
know, life goes on.
>> David, I think it's fantastic that Yum
Brands is continuing that culture of
recognition and incorporating it into
everything they do. And it's also
fantastic that Young Brands is also a
best practice for other companies to
study around how they create this
culture of recognition and how that
really drives results.
>> Oh, thanks Kula. And one of my proudest
moments is when we were showcased in
Fortune magazine for for our our
recognition culture and we did have all
kinds of companies thereafter come visit
us to see how we were doing and that's
when you know you're doing something
right and I was really proud of our
team. Well, David, that wraps our
episode of How Leaders Lead for today.
Thank you so much for tuning in and stay
tuned next Thursday for another
conversation.