Okay, why don't you all take your seats?
Come and take your seats. Good
afternoon, everybody. My name is Anne
Harrison. I'm the dean of the High
School of Business. Welcome to today's
dean speaker series. It is co-sponsored
with the Center for Social Sector
Leadership, otherwise known as Sizzle.
Um Nora here who runs it is is uh
sitting right here. I am absolutely
thrilled to introduce our guest today,
Blake Mikoski.
Um Blake's story is a really powerful
one. He was on a trip in Argentina in
2006 and while he was there he saw many
children who had no shoes and he was
deeply affected by how difficult their
lives was were and so he decided to
create Tom's shoes. Um, and in doing so,
he created the one for one business
model. And that's a model where a
customer by buying a product helps
someone else in need every time they
buy. And that was a complete revolution
in the way to do forprofit
business.
Amazingly, over its lifetime, Tom's has
provided over 96 million pairs of shoes
for children around the world.
[applause]
Um, since then, Tom's expanded into
other areas of vital needs, for example,
eyewear and safe water. Um, now Blake
didn't stop there. he published a book
starts something that matters and every
time that book sells one copy he donates
a child's book to a child. Um so that's
really amazing. His current ventures
include co-founding a wellness program
made for and his philanthropic endeavors
include working in the area of
legalizing psychedelics. Hopefully we'll
hear a little bit about that today too.
Um, we're incredibly
fortunate today to have such a
trailblazer here working in the area of
socially responsible business, an area
that Hos excels in and that we're
passionate about. Um, Blake, our
students have so much to learn from you.
I just want to thank you once again for
coming to speak today uh to give your
insights to our community. Um, so I just
some quick housekeeping. When you sat
down, you might have noticed a note card
on your seat. Um, if you a question
occurs to you, write down the question
while you're listening to the Q&A and
then you can hand it um to our um our
assistants here, my colleagues. They'll
be collecting them and then there'll be
time starting about 110 for some Q&A.
Um, so now I'm going to turn over the
session today to two students who will
be doing the Q&A, Eli Eli Breler and
Ivonne Mandreon, and they will moderate
today's discussion. Take it away.
[applause]
Thank you. Hello. Can you hear me? Okay.
So Blake, thank you for being here. Um,
as we've mentioned before, here at HOS,
we care a lot about social impact and
entrepreneurship. So, everybody here is
very excited to hear from you. Um, to
start us off, why don't you tell us a
little bit about your journey starting
Tom's? Kind of from your perspective,
how what influenced the one for one
model and how that helped drive the
success of Tom's.
Okay, great. Well, Tom started in
Argentina and there's kind of a funny
backstory of how I got there. Um, how
many people have seen the reality TV
show The Amazing Race? Oh, a lot of
people. Okay. Did anyone see it 20 years
ago when I was on it? [laughter] Two
people. Yes. Um, so my sister and I were
on this TV show, Amazing Race. And for
those who haven't seen it, you're racing
around the world for 30 days and there's
a million-doll prize at the end. And
interestingly enough, the last leg of
the race was here in San Francisco. And
uh unfortunately
um at a very critical moment, my sister
said, "You know, we're almost there to
win the million dollars. Let's stop and
ask for directions to make sure we know
where we're going." And as such a cliche
as a man, I said, "No, I know exactly
where I'm going. We don't need to stop
and ask." And next thing I know, we were
lost. And we lost the million dollars by
four minutes. And uh after we lost a
million dollars by four minutes, about a
month later, I got a text message from
my sister and it was this like random
string of numbers and I thought that's
weird. And I thought, well, maybe she,
you know, kind of butt dialed me or
something and and that's what came
through on the text. So, I didn't
respond or anything. And then the next
month, I got another text message and
it's a different random string of
numbers. And so, I called her and I
said, "Paige, what's with these text
messages?" And she goes, "That's the
interest you owe me on my half million
dollars."
[laughter]
And so that was a great experience. But
what the Amazing Race did was it really
took me to all these countries I had
never been to. Uh and Argentina was one
of them. And so I decided that I want to
go back to a lot of the countries. And
so in January of 2006, I took a trip to
Argentina. I was there for about a
month. And um I experienced a bunch of
different things. And one of the things
that I experienced was and it was the
first time that I'd really seen this was
just, you know, really intense poverty.
Uh just outside of Buenos Cyrus, I saw,
you know, many kids in the street and
not wearing shoes and sniffing glue and
and and just some really horrible things
with these children. Uh and at the same
time, um I noticed that a lot of the
young people were wearing these slip-on
shoes, uh called alpraatas. And you
know, I grew up wearing Converse and
Vans and kind of these thick bulkier,
you know, slip-ons, but these were like,
you know, really um different. And so I
asked my friend at the time about these
shoes and he said, "Yeah, you know, the
farmers wear them, the polo players wear
them, you know, and I thought they were
really interesting." U in a very
serendipitous way, I met a woman that
was running a nonprofit and they were
specifically helping kids get shoes for
school. Um the shoes was part of the
uniform. And so many of these kids that
I saw in the streets, the reason they're
in the streets and not in school is cuz
their families couldn't afford the
uniform which included a pair of shoes.
And so I had this kind of morning ritual
where I drink my coffee and write in my
journal about the day and you know have
some of the things I'm thinking about
goals for the day. And when I was
sitting on this farm that I was staying
at in Argentina, I was writing in my
journal and this idea came to me and the
idea was really simple. It was just, you
know, what if I took these shoes that I
see all these people wearing that I've
never seen before and sell them back in
Venice, California, where I live, and
every time I sell a pair, uh, we give a
pair to these kids that desperately need
them for, you know, for their school
uniform. And um, we'll call it shoes for
tomorrow. Um, the idea was that if you
buy a pair today, we give a pair
tomorrow. And most people think my name
is Tom. It's not. Um, but um, that's
where the name Tom's came from was
tomorrow shoes. and we wanted to put the
whole word tomorrow's on the tag, but it
wouldn't fit. Um, so we shortened it to
Tom's and that's how we got the name.
Yeah,
that's really incredible. And uh, as
someone with two sisters in the crowd
right now, I can only imagine that
costing us all a million dollars for
four minutes. You're probably catching
grief about that today. So, I I
empathize with that. um you know we are
on an NBA campus and so I think one of
the things that we're really curious
about is the business of Tom's and the
one for one model signals a lot how you
can have a profitable successful
enterprise and also have it do good do
well for the world right so I think one
of the things we're curious about is how
you layer in social responsibility and
what complexity that adds you know what
challenges have you faced in maintaining
Tom's commitment to social impact while
ensuring the company's financial uh
responsibility what sacrifices do you
have to make on both sides of that coin
to make sure that both can succeed
financially and your social goals.
Okay. Um well, I think it maybe start
answering the question just thinking
about the financial aspects of the Tom's
business model. There's really kind of a
magic formula uh that Tom's, you know,
kind of created and that other
businesses have followed. And it's not
necessarily just the one for one model.
It's this idea that our giving and our
commitment to our impact um had a
greater influence on the customer than
any type of marketing we could ever do.
And so while you know many companies
might spend 10 15 20% of their margin on
marketing, we spent basically zero. Um
and instead we took that money and we
used it to pay for another pair of shoes
which was oftentimes less expensive than
the marketing. And so that's why like
when we we became extremely profitable
and which was a kind of a surprise to me
because when I started the we didn't
even call it a business, we call it a
project. We started the Tom's project,
we priced the shoes based on how much it
cost for us to make them in a guy's
garage in Argentina. So you can imagine
when the business took off and all of a
sudden we were working at big factories,
the cost went down so much that our
profit went, you know, went up a lot.
And so we really had to focus on to be
successful as a business, we actually
need to focus on our giving as much as
anything else and telling that story of
the giving. And I really I learned that
lesson in a in a really kind of funny
way. I was uh in the JFK airport. We had
just started Tom's um and I was probably
2 3 months in and the only people we
really sold Toms to was like my parents,
their friends, um you know, um my
neighbors. Uh, and I was living in
Venice, California. And so I was in New
York trying to get new stores. And um, I
decided to go for a run right before I
had to get to my flight. And so I went
to the JFK airport not wearing Tomms,
which was unique for me at that point. I
always wore Tomms. And so I had my
running shoes on and I go to the
American Airlines check-in counter. I
never forget this. It was kind of one of
the most meaningful things the early
days of Toms for me. And I went to do
the kind of electronic check-in. And
next to me there was this woman uh
wearing a red pair of Toms. And I had
never seen a stranger wearing our shoes.
I mean, it was so cool. Um it was it was
such a cool moment. And so I'm kind of
looking at her and I'm thinking, gosh,
should I say something? And so I decide
to to say, you know, hey, I really love
these these shoes you're wearing. You
know, what are they? And she says,
Tomms. Tom shoes. And so I'm doing the
check-in. And I'm like, "Oh, that's
cool." And she literally physically put
her hand on me and said, "No, you don't
understand. This is the most amazing
company in the world."
She goes, "When I bought this pair of
shoes, they gave a pair to a child in
Argentina, and there's this guy who
started I heard he lives on a boat." And
and and she just went on and on. And so
I I was feeling bad. And so I was like I
had to stop her. And I'm like I'm like,
"Excuse me, actually um I'm I'm that
guy. I'm Blake. I live on a boat." And I
started Tom's and and she goes to me,
she looks at me like like deers and deer
in headlights. Like just like she's so
like what? And she goes, "Why did you
cut your hair?" [laughter]
And I was like, "How did she know I cut
my" And I realized that she wasn't just
a customer, she was a she was just
totally invested in this. And she had
watched all these videos on YouTube of
us giving the shoes away. And so that's
how she knew I had cut my hair. But then
as I, you know, said thanks to her and
went to my flight and started thinking
about that conversation, I realized
that, you know, this woman took the time
out of her day at an airport to tell a
stranger about Tom's. So how many people
has she already told about Tom's? I mean
definitely all her friends and family
and people on Facebook and you know and
so I realized that the effect of just
one customer connecting to our giving
was going to have a such a magnitude
effect on how many shoes we would sell
and ultimately give away. And so that's
when we really decided that as a
business model we were not necessarily
going to be focused on the things that a
traditional business was but really
focused on giving and telling our story.
And that's why our model works so well.
Yeah, that's awesome to hear. Um to see
that something you believe in others
also believe in and you know it grew
into you know what Tom's is today. Going
off of that a lot you know large scale
innovation something that is very hard
to do. There's some products out there
that we see that we think this large
scale is inevitable right? um what are
some of the challenges that you
experienced uh with scaling up Tom's and
how did you face those challenges?
Um the well the biggest challenge was
making the den shoes. Um I mean I had
never made shoes before. Um my Argentine
polo playing partner Allejo had never
made shoes before and we met this guy
who said he could make them in his
garage um which he could do somewhat
sufficiently. Um, so really scaling the
production once the business took off
was really, really hard. Um, you know,
what I found was the key to that was
finding people who did know how to make
shoes, uh, and had done it for companies
that really scaled. And so we very early
on we were able to attract um, a really
senior executive from one of the big
shoe companies uh, to come and start
working in my apartment with us. I think
he was employee number two or three. And
the first two were interns off
Craigslist. But um but but you know Sean
came to us and I remember it was really
cool. I went on a a factory tour with
him in Asia and we were drinking beers
one night and I said to him, I said,
"Sean, you know, why did you come to
Tomomps?" You know, because I mean,
we're paying you probably half as much
as um as you uh as you made at this, you
know, I think it was Nike or Converse, I
forget where he was at before. And he,
you know, very senior in his in his
role. He'd worked in the industry for I
think 30 years. And I said, you know,
cuz we're paying you probably half or
twothirds what you're paying and you
know, you're having to do the job of
basically five people. Um, and it was so
cool. he's told me he said and this goes
back to giving being our key
differentiator is he said you know
because now
um you know my kids think I'm so cool
you know and my daughter thinks it's so
amazing that I'm helping kids get shoes
and so I get to you know that that's a
big part of why I'm here and that's also
I realized that you know just focusing
on our giving and staying authentic to
that was was so important because
without Shawn we never would have been
able uh to scale the business.
That's really interesting. It feels like
people are attracted to it because it's
solving two problems. It's putting
stylish shoes on people's feet. That's
actually a fun problem to solve. It's
also putting shoes on the feet of people
in need, and that's an even more fun
problem to solve. I think when we think
about the most successful businesses,
the most successful products, like
that's what they fundamentally do. They
solve problems that people can't solve
themselves. Like Velcro allows me to
fasten my fasten my shoes. Advil allows
me to reduce pain, inflammation, all
that kind of stuff. How do you go about
figuring out what problems people need
to solve and how you can solve that
problem? And even one step further, if
you know how to solve the problem, how
do you turn that into a business that
can solve it for a lot of people? What
does problem solving and filling need
look like for you?
Okay, so I'm going to tell a story from
a different company. Um, so I've started
I think five or six companies and most
of them were before Tom's. Uh, and one
of them was an online driver's education
company. Now, how I got into that
business is is is uh, you know, really
by listening to someone's problem. Um, I
was at a barbecue for a television
network that I'd also helped start and
um and and my head of programming son
was there and he was 15 years old and I
asked him, you know, what are you doing
this summer? And he kind of said, uh,
I'm learning to drive. And I was like,
huh, that's not the I mean, I would
think that if you're learning to drive,
that'd be exciting for a 15-year-old.
And I said, well, what why is learning
to drive not that exciting? And he said,
"Ah, you know, it's a I'm in this
classroom and it's stinky and it's dark
and it's in this like mall and I got
this old lady teacher and I can barely
understand what she's saying and the
cars are just crap." And I mean, he was
just super negative. And I was thinking,
well, this is not good for our safety on
our California highways. You know, if
this is how this engaged or disengaged
this kid is, like we are in a lot of
trouble. And so I went home that night
and this is right when um you know
MySpace was out and there was no
Facebook yet. Um and um some of you
probably don't even know what MySpace
is, I'm realizing. Um so but um and it
was also when they were just starting to
do things online that traditionally had
been done, you know, in brick and
mortar. And so I thought, well, you
know, one way to, you know, solve this
problem of these classrooms that are
really not that inspiring. they're
usually in like Sears malls or
something. Uh is to see if we could take
this class online and so that you know
it could be more engaging, more
entertaining. They could do it at their
own pace, you know, and so that was, you
know, one idea and and I worked really
hard with some legislature to get that
changed in um California so that we
could do that. And so that was step one.
Uh and step two was we got to get better
cars. Like these cars have got to be
more interesting. Now, this was right
when Toyota came out with the Prius. And
so, they had this huge desire to get
people to know what an electric car even
was. And, you know, starting with young
people who might be more environmentally
inclined was one big part of their
thing. And so, I cold called Toyota down
in Torrance and got a meeting and they
decided to like give us four cars at
like, you know, basically the cost. But
the third thing was the teacher and I
and that was something that was going to
be a little bit harder to do because you
know people who were kind of driver's ed
teachers were pretty uh a very specific
type. They're usually retired. Um you
know they were usually you know um you
know I mean it just they were it was I
think everyone can remember their
driver's ed teacher unless you went to
our school cuz I'll tell you why ours
was special. Um and you'd really
remember because what we decided was
these teenagers were not paying
attention to their teachers at all. And
so we thought about, okay, how can we
get them to pay attention? Now, we were
lucky because we lived in Los Angeles,
so we had a lot of actors and models.
And so we went and basically hired a
bunch of Abbercrombie Fish models and
actors that had all this free time and
we knew that teenagers pay attention to
them and it worked. And so we had them
as our driver teachers and uh they would
post pictures on MySpace of them and
their teacher and uh and so we solved
all three problems at once.
[laughter]
That's beautiful. I uh I distinctly
remember my driver's ed teacher self-
brand himself as Tupac Dave and he was
far too old to be trying to educate
15-year-olds about Tupac and not
teaching them about driving. So I I
understand not learning anything and
also trying to make sure kids actually
learn how to drive so it's safe. Um piv
pivoting a little bit. You're mentioning
a lot of partnerships like you're
talking about Toyota, you're talking
about these Abocrombian Fitch models.
you've been talking about this person
that you met um who was working at Nike
came to work for you and I think
partnerships are key and I know you
often talk about collaboration as being
key to success. I'm curious, what are
the green flags that you look for in
individuals, entities, partners, um, of
what you think would make them a
trustworthy part partner, a good faith
partner, someone who you want to do
business with, whether it's an
individual or an entity, kind of what's
your criteria? What are the green flags?
I mean, I think the most important thing
in a partnership is, is the partnership
going to be seen as something that's
authentic, that makes sense? You know,
um, the best partnership we ever had was
with AT&T. Uh it was truly one of the
the the biggest turning points in our
business and I would even say in my
life. Um because what happened was is I
was on uh CNN doing an interview. And um
I did an interview and I was they were
asking about how many people worked at
our company at this point. There were
like 40 of us. Uh, and we were selling
all over the world. And they were like,
"How in the world do you run your
business when you're in places like
Ethiopia giving shoes or Cambodia or
Guatemala and there's only 40 of you and
you're competing against these big shoe
companies?" And I pulled out my, it was
funny, I had a Blackberry back then. Do
you guys remember Blackberry? Okay,
good. Um, I'm not as old as I think. Um,
and so I pulled out my my Blackberry on
the CNN interview and I said, "This is
how I do it." And I basically I can run
the business and do everything from my
phone while I'm in Ethiopia. And um and
and and so this ad exec was in the back
of a taxi in New York and they saw this
interview on CNN and they thought, "Oh
my gosh, if he uses AT&T, this is
perfect." And so they called me and
luckily they asked me if I used AT&T.
And I said yes. And that was one of the
great, you know, lucky moments of my
life because they said, "We want to do a
commercial about you and Tom's and your
story and we don't want to like create
something slick and we want to actually
go with you on a giving trip to
Argentina and just film you and make a
commercial." And so they made this
commercial and it was like lightning in
a bottle. They loved it. They tested it.
It tested well. They premiered it on the
Masters Golf Tournament, which if you
know of that tournament, they only allow
three different commercials for the
entire term. And then they played it at
the NBA, you know, you know, final final
um playoff games, everything. They ended
up spending $30 million on a commercial
to basically tell the Tom story [snorts]
and but it was completely authentic
because I use AT&T and so it worked
really well for them. Our business grew
500% that year because of that
commercial. Um, and so literally I think
u, you know, I mean we went from, you
know, I mean it was just it was crazy
how much it grew and that was really the
beginning of our our our mass growth.
But that partnership was so important
and the reason it worked to your
question is because it was completely
authentic.
Thank you.
Yeah, that's a great partnership story.
Um, moving a little bit away from the
business side and trans transitioning
into leadership. I strongly believe
every great venture has a strong leader
behind it. You often talk about being a
servant leader, one that aims to serve
others. You talk openly about your
failures and vulnerabilities. Um, how do
you think sharing some of those
experiences have shaped you into the
leader you are today?
Thank you. Um, well, I think when you
hear the term servant leader, I think
it's a really important term. Um, and it
goes back to the fact of, you know, in
most businesses, the your employees that
are on the front line are serving
customers. You know, you heard that
phrase and in order for them to really
serve your customers, they need to be
served from their managers. And I think
that's really the job of a manager or an
executive is not just to lead the vision
of the business, but to really serve
those that are working for them so that
they feel empowered to, you know, really
serve the customer. Um, I think also,
you know, leaders really set the culture
and I think, you know, talking about
failures and vulnerabilities, um, you
know, you really, I believe, need to set
a culture where it's okay to fail. You
know, I always say if I'm going to fail,
I want to fail fast. Um, so I don't
waste a lot of time and money failing,
but I I I learn from it and I move on.
And so I think it's really important
that as a leader that you show that
failures are not going to be
reprimanded. You know, if anything,
they're going to be celebrated because
what did we learn from that failure? And
I think that's a really important part
of leadership.
I love hearing that. And I think one
other thing we hear a lot of successful
entrepreneurs talk about is luck. So
learn quick from your failures, but also
you have to have some luck sometimes.
You know, some say they create their own
luck and that they earned it and they
built that luck and if they didn't work
as hard and put themselves in those
situations, that luck would have
happened. Others say a beautiful
opportunity fell in my lap and I got
lucky that my idea worked. So I'm
curious what you think about luck and
how much luck has played into your
success.
I mean, I'm a lucky guy for sure. Um,
[laughter]
so I um I I think I think there is some
truth to this idea that you know the
harder you work the luckier you get. Um,
but I also think that, you know, um,
sometimes just an idea, you know, I
mean, how do we have an idea? You know,
start there. Like I'm sitting on a farm
in Argentina and this idea is somewhat
downloaded or transmitted to my brain
that then goes to my journal that then
goes to starting a business that then
goes to kind of changing the face of
business across the world. Like I I
can't take responsibility for that. like
I have no I mean from a spiritual
perspective I don't really understand
how that came about but I feel really
lucky that I was the one that got to do
it. Um and so so I do think that you
know you can make your own luck and you
have to work hard but I also think that
in certain businesses or certain ideas
that come and really you know have a
huge effect on culture um that idea was
just it time was to come and the person
that got to bring it to the world is
pretty lucky. So, I feel lucky.
Yeah, that's great. I think we're all
hoping for some a little bit of luck out
here to [laughter] go on to our next uh
endeavor. Um, so your ventures have
given us shoes uh provided safe drinking
water and restored vision of countless
individuals at a global scale. going
forward, where do you think uh the
greatest need will be and uh what new
business models outside of the one for
one model? Um have you been excited
about or um you've seen actually work?
Well, I think if I was an entrepreneur
starting out today, I would be spending
a lot of time looking at green energy. I
think that, you know, um one of the
biggest, you know, problems facing our
species right now is the climate. And I
think there's going to be so many
opportunities. There already have been
so many opportunities, so many, you
know, fortunes built focusing on, you
know, you know, how we can live in a
more sustainable way. But, you know,
it's something that I don't have a lot
of experience or expertise in. But I
think that's where I would really be
focused because I think that there's
just going to be, you know, we we have I
mean, technology and innovation is our
only way out. And so when there's a
necessity, there's usually great
opportunities for entrepreneurship.
I think half of my classmates here who
are going into green energy and climate
tech just got really excited. So, thank
you for that. The future is bright, my
friends. Um, I I do also want to ask
about another interest that you have in
something that you've pledged time and
resources towards, which is the
legalization of psychedelics. And I just
want to know like what inspired you to
get involved with that and where do you
think the opportunity is for that to
succeed or just any general thoughts
about that space which is kind of new
and upcoming?
Sure. So, I I think um I mean I'm I'm
really excited about this. I feel like
this is really at the beginning of a new
frontier and how we help address so many
mental health challenges. Um you know,
I've struggled myself with depression.
Um I know many people that have and I
know many people that have taken the
traditional route of of pharmaceuticals
and talk therapy and and have not had
success. Um, I had the opportunity,
gosh, it was six, seven years ago, uh, a
friend of mine, famous podcaster Tim
Ferrris, many of you probably know, um,
called me and and had known that I had
worked with psychedelics myself and had
found them, you know, very beneficial.
Um and and we had shared that with each
other and in private and um and he said
you know the the John Hopkins is
thinking about creating the first ever
center for psychedelic research in the
country and they're looking for a few
philanthropist um to kind of step up and
help you know endow this. And at that
point, you know, most of my uh giving
had been through Tom's and then also um
a supporter of of some of these
nonprofits like Charity Water that I'm a
big fan of. And so this was kind of a
you know, giving to a university and and
helping endow a department for
psychedelic research. This was really
kind of outside of my scope. But, you
know, I realized and Tim really helped
me understand and see that there was
going to be very few opportunities as a
philanthropist to have their dollars be
so leveraged because if if this worked
and and John Hopkins could show, you
know, the effects of psilocybin or MDMA
or, you know, LSD on different mental
health challenges that this could be the
beginning of legalization and and really
our society accepting that these are not
necessarily drugs, but they're actually
medicines.
And um and so I made that donation and
it was the largest donation that I had
made to date at that time. And then
about 2 years later u there's an
organization called MAPS uh that has
been working really hard to um put MDMA
through the FDA um for mainly
[clears throat] for helping with PTSD.
And they were at a critical place in
their FDA um kind of path and they
needed to raise I think 10 million
bucks. And so, interesting enough, Tim
Ferrris called me again and uh and and
and Tim and a guy named Joe Green were
putting together this this round and
trying to raise this for the nonprofit
and they explained the benefit
especially to many of our veterans. Um,
you know, the statistic that haunts me
every day when we think about our
veteran community is that 17 veterans a
day commit suicide. I mean, that's more
people are dying of suicide than die in
combat now. And that to me is just
inexcusable. And so seeing how MDMA can
have an effect on that um and helping
with the PTSD and depression that many
of them experience was, you know, really
an amazing opportunity for me. And so I
made that investment. Um and then I just
kind of sat back and watched these two
for about four or five years. And then a
couple years ago, I decided to get more
engaged and more involved. Um, I made a
a investment here in the in the Berkeley
Center for Psychedelic Science. Uh, I
continued to help John Hopkins. I've
worked with the VA now on um some
projects there. Um, and and what I'm
finding is is, you know, I like things
to happen fast. I think as an
entrepreneur, that's kind of one of our
characteristics. This is going to be a
long process. I mean, this is something
that I probably commit the rest of my
life to because that's how long it's
going to take for things to really
become legal to have, you know,
regulated access. We're working on a
bill through the legislature in
California right now um to create um
regulated access for P tsd for MDMA and
psilocybin. Um you know, that'll go to
the governor's desk, you know, next year
around September. So, there's a chance
that it it gets passed. um which will
then really you know change the
landscape across the country. But this
this to me is the most exciting you know
kind of science advancement that we
could have that could have the biggest
impact on what really is a health
epidemic in our country um with mental
health issues. So I feel really really
lucky. It's kind of like when Tom's idea
came to me and I got to be part of a
change in the way that business is done.
You know, I feel really lucky that now I
get to be a part of a way that hopefully
we help, you know, millions, if not
billions of people around the world uh
with mental health issues.
Thank you so much. I I do want to thank
you for all that. I'm very passionate
about the space personally. Do I wish I
had my own Tim Ferrris? Absolutely. But
otherwise, uh just interfacing with
Well, be careful. Tim Ferris has been
very expensive for me.
Okay, [laughter]
that's true. That's true. That's true.
Um but no, it's a it's a huge need. Um,
and I think I could ask about 200 follow
questions about that, but I want to be
conscious of time. We have a lot of
questions here from the audience. So,
the last question we want to ask you is,
you know, you're sitting in front of a
room of aspiring leaders, entrepreneurs,
people who are going through their MBA
or teaching at this program so that they
can make a real difference. And so, just
for the aspiring leaders in the room,
whatever capacity that is, do you have
any last words of advice, parting pieces
of wisdom just for us aspiring leaders?
Oh man, that's always the hardest
question because like do I really want
to sit here and give you advice? I mean
I'm not that much older than most of you
guys in the room. Um
I mean I think we were talking about
this back there and so I would say if if
you have entrepreneurial desires um then
this is advice that I think is
particularly for you. uh and that is
that I really had this kind of belief
that you know to to found a successful
company it it really has to come from a
passion from a from a need from
something that you've seen in the world
that you're frustrated with or you don't
agree with or there's a product you wish
you had but you can't buy um I I really
believe that that's where the great
businesses come from. I think it's very
dangerous to, you know, come get your
MBA, learn about entrepreneurship, and
be like, "Okay, I want to be an
entrepreneur. I'm just going to go start
a business without the passion behind
it, you know, just because you think
you're going to make money." I've seen
most of those businesses fail, to be
honest. And so, if you make making money
the reason you're getting into
entrepreneurship, I think it's
dangerous. I think if you make the
change you want to make or the product
you want to create or the service you
want to provide because you deeply care
about it the reason you're becoming
entrepreneurship then the money will
follow and and so that's um that is what
I would say is you know kind of one of
the main pieces of advice I have for
entrepreneurs. The second piece of
advice, I'm gonna give two now. I just
realized there's another one. Um,
is
you, this is, and this is going to be
super contrarian to this group. I can
tell already. Um, because you're
spending so much money to get your MBA
here. Um, and so as soon as you
graduate, um, as soon as you graduate,
you're going to have a ton of pressure
yourself, your student loans, your
parents perhaps, uh, to go out and get a
job that will pay the most amount of
money for a job that you can get. And
that makes sense, you know, initially.
Um, and but but but the truth is is no
matter how much money you make working
at a bank or a consulting firm or
whatever. [snorts] Um, it's not going to
actually have that big of impact on how
much money you make in your life. And
I'm not saying making money is the only
reason that we work, but it is one of
the reasons. And and so what I tell
people is like instead of going out and
just chasing the biggest paycheck right
away, think about what you're most
passionate about and invest your time at
least for a few years in that without
the pressure to pay those loans back
right away or to make as much money as
possible. Because what usually happens
is if you follow your passion and you do
something that you're really deeply
interested in versus just trying to make
money, you become really good at it. And
when you become really good at anything,
usually you make money at it. And so
that I know is probably not gonna it's
falling on some deaf ears, but that's
fine. Um, and you may think I'm naive
and idealistic and it's easy for me to
say because I already made money. Um,
but but but I really have seen I've
given that advice u to undergrads and
and MBAs over, you know, probably, you
know, 15 years of speaking now. And I
and I've had people come up to me, you
know, or write me emails or letters
years later and say that really made an
impact because they end up getting into
something that they deeply cared about.
They got really great at it and then
they made the money. So there you go.
That's brilliant. Thank you so much,
Blake.
Turn it over to Nor.
[applause]
So, first I want to thank Blake for
starting off with the loss. We don't do
that very much in business [laughter]
school. And I want to really acknowledge
um Eli and Ivonne who came up with the
questions and posed them so well. Don't
you think? Yes, absolutely. [applause]
So, my name is Nora Silver. I'm a
faculty director for the Center for
Social Sector Leadership, we call SISLE,
and I'm an adjunct professor here. And
Ann was kind enough to share this dean
speaker series with us. Before we open
it up for your questions, which I do
have here. Thank you very much. Um, I
have a few for you. How many of you are
Berkeley or Hos students?
Okay. How many of you came here in order
to make a difference or create social
impact at Berkeley or HOS? How many of
you came here for that? Okay. About
half. Do we have any alumni here?
Welcome back.
Do we have any friends and family of
Blake or of Sisle? Yay, Emma. Ella. So,
okay. So I want to take a minute with
the students in particular. Whatever you
came here for, if you are curious about
the kind of innovation that Blake made
or the kind of career path that he took,
I want you to know, do you know that you
can explore it through Sisle and I want
to point out a couple things. Gloria,
would you stand up? Gloria is right now
teaching a course called reinventing
capitalism for a sustainable, humane,
and equitable world. It's offered this
spring. It will be offered next spring
as well. Stay there. In the fall, Gloria
taught and will teach again business
models for social impact. She teaches
that with Kristen Gruce Richmond. Both
of them are serial social entrepreneurs
who can introduce you to different
models such as that Blake described and
describes in his book. Thank you,
Gloria.
[applause]
For those of you who want to found
something with social impact, we do have
an impact startup disco. It's an
intensive week-long with Jorge Calderon
that will walk you through those initial
kind of scary steps. And lastly, I'm
going to be teaching in the fall a
course on social movements. I'm
exploring teaching that if that's what
you're interested in. We have a lot of
experiential programs and one I want to
point out to you because it's coming up.
If any of you are interested in trying
exploring a social impact summer
internship, we have a program that will
supplement your salaries if that's what
you're worried about. So come look for
the HIA with net impact and we'll let
you know about that. And we have career
advising. So I and Sisil's executive
director are serial social
entrepreneurs. We have faculty 20 plus.
Would you raise your hands here? I see
you. Come on.
that teach on things and know about
things in the world because they're
they're professional faculty, right? So,
they're out there working on these
issues at the same time that they're
teaching you things like climate tech
and global health and food and education
and economic development. So, whatever
is stirred up in you from hearing about
Blake doesn't need to stop here. There
are many more resources at Berkeley and
at HOS available to you depending on
your interests. And I just want to make
sure you know where you've come to start
the journey. So there are people here to
help you with your curiosity, with your
thinking, with your next adventure, no
matter what that will be. But now we
still have some more questions for
Blake. So Blake, back to you.
Ready?
Sure.
All right. I You may not be ready for
this one, but we'll try.
Have you paid your sister 500,000 plus
interest? [laughter]
So, how many people know this clothing
brand called Aviator Nation? and raise
your hand. Enough. Okay. So, my sister
started this company and I think Forbes
last said that she's a billionaire now.
So, I think she's doing fine.
Maybe she should pay you. No, I'm
kidding. All right. All right. So,
here's the next question. Tom's was a
pioneering business model and I think
received disproportionate scrutiny and
criticism. How did you navigate it and
what would you have done differently in
hindsight? H yeah, I mean that was a
really hard thing for me because you
hear this you hear this uh adage that
you know the media loves to build you up
so then they can kind of tear you down
and you know we got a lot of flak for
you know how we were what impact were we
having on communities by just going out
and offering a handout and that was
really hard because all we were trying
to do is do good I mean I was in
Argentina saw kids that didn't have
shoes want to give them shoes like I
didn't come with like a public health
background or you know or you know and
so we really at first were like you know
angry and frustrated and scared by this
uh and then we decided we had to lean
into it and so ultimately what we did
was we hired some people who did have
that background who really understood
the impact of you know giving free goods
in these communities how it impact the
local community um and that really led
us to doing um some local manufacturing
so we did a manufacturing
[clears throat] plant in Haiti after you
know the earthquake
um which was really successful. We moved
manufacturing also to Ethiopia um which
you know created a lot of jobs in
Ethiopia. And then the other thing we
did is we realized that just giving
shoes was not enough that we had to be
part of uh health programs as well. And
so there's a lot of health programs for
um worms that kids get in Central and
South America. And so they want them to
come in and take the medicine that would
keep them from getting worms. But the
incentive a lot of kids wouldn't come do
it. they started saying if you come you
get a free pair of shoes and so that was
a big incentive. We worked with the
Gates Foundation on that. Um and so yeah
so we just had to get smarter and better
and more sophisticated in how we did our
giving.
Great. Thanks.
So how have your previous ventures you
mentioned four or five before Tom's
right um allowed you to be successful as
an entrepreneur? What did you bring
forward from those? I mean just lots of
learning. You know a couple of them were
moderately successful and a couple of
them were huge disasters. Um uh you know
one disaster was after I was on it was
not a disaster but it was a failed
business I guess. Um is after I was on
the Amazing Race um I recognized that
there was this tremendous amount of
interest in reality stars and their 15
minutes of fame. Um but there wasn't
really a market for um really kind of
capitalizing on that. And so um I
decided to start at I think at the age
of 25 I was very naive. I decided to
start a television network and it was an
all reality cable channel in which I
went around and bought the rerun rights
of reality shows because once you kind
of knew who won they really had no
interest at the networks. But what I
realized is people cared so much about
the reality stars that you could pair
the stars with the shows and they could
kind of almost do like these shows where
they gave commentary about what they
were thinking when they did that move on
Survivor or how they got that person
outed on Big Brother or something like
that. And so we were able to get the
content for basically next to nothing.
We knew that advertisers really wanted
to reach this audience. It was mainly an
18 to 34 audience which was the key
audience that advertisers wanted to
reach. All these components showed that
we were going to have incredible success
in this business. Um the one thing we
did not think about um which was the
most important and the reason it failed
was there were only about 10 cable
operators in our country at that time um
and including DirecTV satellite
provider. And so the cable operators in
DirecTV basically had a monopoly as to
what content we see. It's not like today
where you can see it on Hulu or you can
see it on, you know, a number of
different streaming networks. Um,
obviously YouTube being one of the
dominant players. Um, so we basically
had an amazing product. Um, people
wanted it and we had advertisers willing
to pay for it. But our only way we're
going to get anyone to ever see it was
through these cable operators and they
had no need for another network. I mean,
they had 400 channels already. what was
getting one more was not going to have
anyone all of a sudden decide to pay for
cable television. They were paying for
cable television for many other reasons
already. And so they basically said no,
you know, we're not interested. And so
we ended up going out of business. It
was incredibly painful. I I had to lay
off like 40 people. Um you know, it was
it was a really challenging challenging
situation. Um, and what I learned from
that was is I never wanted to be in a
business again where so few people had
the power to make it work or not work.
And so when I started Tom's, the great
thing was is there's thousands of, you
know, stores in America that sell shoes.
And and so that was, you know, I didn't
have to go out and, you know, get this
one big fish customer. I could go and
focus on one after another after another
after another. And so that was one of
the real lessons that I learned from a
per an earlier business that you know
failed that really helped me as I
thought about Tom's.
Great. Thank you. So the buy one give
one model used by Toms has longstanding
been a point of celebration. However,
there have been shortcomings and
challenges and all of that. Here's the
big question. Is it truly possible to be
a business for good? And how should
incoming business leaders incorporate
I'll read it as it says corporate
philanthropy into their company brands?
Absolutely.
I can just talk loud too.
Hello.
We're trying to broadcast sole.
Hello. Great. Um I don't know how to
juggle. I would love to learn though. Um
so I yeah I mean I think that there's a
lot of examples of businesses for good
out there now. Um Tom's being one of
them. Um I think the key is to really
focus on you know kind of three things
and you hear this a lot of time in
conscious capitalism the three Ps you
know people planet and the profit. Um
you know by doing that you can really
build a business where all those
stakeholders are equally um benefiting.
Um, I think the the I will say the bad
news in all this is is that and because
of the success of Tom's and other
companies like Tom's, it's not as novel
to be a business for good as it was when
we started. When we started, there was
nothing like this. I mean, there was Ben
and Jerry's that had been giving, you
know, there was the body shop that had
been giving Anita erotic, but neither of
them built their whole business on it
like we did with Tom's. So, we really
kind of pioneered this and several other
businesses as well. But now today, if
you were starting a business, I was
talking to an entrepreneur the other day
and they were saying, "Okay, well, we're
going to incorporate this giving model,
helping people get clean water, etc."
And and they're going to invest a lot of
money in that. And I said to them, and
they thought it was weird coming from
me. I said, "I don't think you should do
that." I was like, "I don't think
there's going to be enough return on
your social investment to make it work."
like I talked about from a marketing
perspective because so many other
companies are already doing it. So I
think now what I would say for
entrepreneurs that really want to do
good in business is it's really
important to incorporate it into the
business model itself. So it can't it to
do it as a add-on or to a if you do this
we give this I think can be can be more
difficult but if the but if the actual
business itself and that's why I use the
example of green energy if the business
itself is making the planet a more
sustainable place then it is a business
that's doing good but it's also not
necessarily having to carve out a
percentage of its margin to do so.
Okay. And the um the final question from
the group is um you talk a lot about
conscious capitalism and for-profit
business and in your book you also
herald or celebrate nonprofits and
philanthropists and many people draw
divisions between those but you don't.
Can you talk a little bit about why you
don't or how you see that? Well, what I
tried to do when I wrote this book,
which is a long time ago now, um, as I'm
thinking about it and I'm trying to
remember some of the things that I said,
[laughter] um, but, um,
you know, I tried to to really, uh,
highlight, you know, two different
organizations. businesses that were
innovative and they're giving and doing
good like Tom's. But then also some of
these new nonprofits that were being
created that were operating more like
businesses. And so I'll use Charity
Water as a great example. How many
people know Charity Water? Raise your
hand. Oh wow. Okay. You should
definitely check out Charity Water. Not
a lot of people here know, but they've
been incredibly innovative. My friend
Scott Harrison started it the same year
I started Tom's and his idea was to
bring water to as many people in the
world that need it as possible. And if
you look at the marketing of Charity
Water, it's as it's as innovative and as
slick as any new, you know, Silicon
Valley backed tech startup. I mean, the
branding is unbelievable. The
storytelling is unbelievable. Um, it
competes with any business in terms of
marketing. Um, but it's a nonprofit. Uh
they also do really really innovative
marketing campaigns like asking people
especially young you know young people
people who are 15 16 17 years old to
give up their birthday in order to raise
money for um for wells and they found
this to be incredibly successful um
especially with social media because
they can message out to all their
friends like this year instead of having
a party or bringing a present I'm asking
you to donate $10 you know for every
year I've been born or whatever. Uh, and
they've raised, you know, I mean,
literally they've raised, I think, $300
million in the last couple years through
these campaigns. Um, so I also try to
talk about like something like that in
the book as well because I think at the
end of the day there's a lot of big
problems in the world that we want to
solve and sometimes the right vehicle is
a nonprofit and some like in the
psychedelic space for instance um and
then sometimes it is a for-profit like
Tom's. And so I don't really see a
distinction between either um as long as
the organization is being used to
address a major problem in the world.
Great. Thank you, Blake. We're hitting
our time and I'm going to take a little
editorial freedom and go off script
here. Um Alan Ross, would you come up
here?
[applause]
Allan does not know I was calling him up
here, so bear with us.
Allan is doing something I think is very
innovative as a philanthropist and he
sent out an email just yesterday asking
us to vote. So Alan, I want to
relinquish the final two minutes to you
to make a pitch to the group.
Well, thank you so much. It's very
sweet. It's very surprising. Um,
[laughter]
um, I started something a couple years
ago called the Chris Kindness Award. And
everyone calls me Chris. I'm Allan. Um,
I named it after my kid's preschool
teacher who died. Uh, just the sweetest
guy I ever met. And I give a thousand
dollars every month to someone in
Berkeley who does a kind act, random
acts of kindness. We've had a gas
station attendant, someone who
volunteers, children's hospital, a
teacher. uh this month was a 16-year-old
at Berkeley High who's from Afghanistan,
just arrived in America a year ago, who
helps new coming uh kids from all over
the world acclimate to Berkeley High.
Sweet, sweet stories. And we just
announced our three finalists for this
month um on Monday. One of whom is a HOS
person, former student of mine of 20
years ago, Olive Davis. Anyone know
Olive?
wonderful woman who uh was with Yay for
a while, young entrepreneurs at HOS, and
now she started BBE several years ago,
giving back to the community, bringing
in youngsters from middle school to HOS
to educate them about business to get
them interested so they'll go on to
college and all. Wonderful person.
Anyone can vote.
Chriskindnessawward.org.
Um voting goes through Friday. If you
want to vote for all of that would be
wonderful. And we need nominations.
We're seeking nominations all the time.
Go on our website, nominate anyone who
lives, works, or goes to school in
Berkeley. And we've we're raising money
now. We now give second and third prize
cash prizes also. And we're trying to
grow throughout the community and beyond
Berkeley as well. So
chriskindnessawward.org.
Thank you so much, Nora. Thank you,
Dean. Appreciate it. [applause]
Thank you. So, we know that many of you
are doing meaningful and interesting
things for your local communities, for
your friends, for your family. We want
to thank you for all of that. For Blake,
Ivonne, um, Eli, an thank you for
coming. Thank you for listening. We hope
you were inspired to go out and try
something really meaningful to you that
you're passionate about in the world.
And H is here to help you. Thank you
very much. [applause]
[applause]