hey everybody Welcome to the podcast my
guest today is Blake MOSI Blake is a
Serial entrepreneur perhaps best known
as the founder of Tom shoes he's got a
new company called made for and he's
just a super cool guy he's a deep
spiritual cat we had an amazing
conversation tons of incredible
takeaways I think you're going to really
enjoy it so hit that subscribe button
and without further Ado please enjoy my
conversation with Blake MOSI
[Music]
right on man you're here in the flesh
we've been trying to make this happen I
can't remember when we first started
going back and forth on email but it was
probably like two years ago or something
like that really long time coming I'm
glad we could do it uh face to face I
appreciate you coming out here um to
make this happen so many cool things to
to talk about with you I'm actually like
what what's the way in with this guy
because there's so many but maybe one
one way we can kick it off is to talk
about this Mutual acquaintance that we
have Shaman yeah explain to people who
April is man that is a hard um hard bill
um April's a shaman uh and she um has an
amazing gift of taking people on Vision
Quest I went uh to the medicine wheel um
which is kind of kind of equivalent of
America's
stonehinge uh with her on top of a
mountain in Wyoming for 4 days about a
year and a half ago and it radically
altered many aspects of my life yeah and
uh since then I check in with her about
every six months and for guidance on
different things and her ability to
connect and communicate with
Supernatural aspects of this Human
Experience is is is something that seems
impossible but um but she's always so
accurate yeah I consider myself a pretty
rational individual who also has a
spiritual bent like I'm open you know
and I've gone and done sessions with her
and have never left one of those
sessions without feeling completely
rocked by her Insight all of which
ultimately are proven true in the short
term or in the long term like all our
kids have done sessions with her my wife
goes to see her like all the time and
it's amazing yeah you know and I don't
know what it is I've stopped you know
trying to answer that question but um
for me this is the way I've tried to
explain to people who think that
anything in this realm is is is very
hard to believe and that is like I have
uh you
know not legally adopted but basically
adopted Ethiopian son he's 24 years old
and I met him when he was 14 living in
rural Ethiopia and I agreed to take him
on and have supported him ever since and
he spends holidays with us and so for
all practical purposes I'm his second
father and you know he and I always talk
about how it's just incredible like we
don't pause and think about the fact
that I can take a picture of myself or
what I'm doing that day and push a
button and almost instantaneously he's
in rural Ethiopia on his iPhone he gets
that picture so that data travels
through air across continents across
oceans and then you know lands on his
phone and so when I think of April's
gifts and people who have these gifts
it's you know they have the a receptor
that we don't have that is you know
catching information uh that is
traveling you know through and so that's
the way I look at it like a transistor
radio she has a dial that I don't have
she can tap into a certain frequency
that you know
not that crazy to think about when you
think about how the picture gets to
Ethiopia what is what is an Insight that
she provided you with that that you know
rocked you um you know there was a a
really amazing experience that happened
where I had a vision when in the wheel
with her of a person um from my past and
a um and a uh a message to um help this
person out and helped them out in a
pretty significant financial way uh and
doing it
anonymously and I called my business
manager who thought I was completely
crazy and said this is what I want to do
I don't want it ever be back to me and
just want to happen I had this Vision it
was it's something that really important
to me based on some things in the past
and I had not seen this person in 10
years um and uh I um did it and no link
back to me nothing um but this person
um uh I could have run into in the 10
years because we have similar circles
that we're in but literally for 10 years
had not run into this person and then on
a very very important day spiritually in
my life um months later um I when when
when seeing this person would have meant
something to me and I don't want to give
away this person's identity um I went to
a yoga class at a studio in a city that
I've never been at because I was there
um randomly um and every single mat in
the whole place uh was full except one
mat when I got there late and I went and
I sat down on the mat and this person
was sitting next to me uhuh and I just
looked at him and it was just I I
literally I don't seen The Truman Show I
looked up in and I was ready for the I
was ready for the world to part or the
sky to part and someone say cut he did
it like passed the test and I mean to
this day I get goosebumps telling the
story well that's a very specific
example of of what I think is a
recurring theme of your life like this
kind of has happening to you all
the time like you there is something
about who you are your presence your
disposition your worldview your energy
that does work like this Beacon of
Attraction not to get too secrety about
the whole thing but I think there is you
know am a believer in that and I think
that you're somebody who navigates the
world from that kind of perspective of
Attraction like this knowingness like
this is going to work out like oh I'm
I'm supposed to you know I really want
to connect with that person I don't need
to make it happen like it will just it's
going to transpire because this is the
energy that I'm emitting from you know
my dome right yeah I know and that's
played out in your life like a lot of
times especially with my journaling
practice that's something that over the
years has really um kind of really
confirmed this belief of that we can
manifest manifest the life and the
opportunities um because I've been
journaling since I was 15 I do it every
single day it's like the one thing I I
actually more consistent journaling than
brushing my teeth or taking a shower
like you know like I um I just it's
something I've always done and a couple
years back uh as part of a film project
I had to go back and read a bunch of my
my journals and and have and I have like
a big fire safe full of hundreds and
hundreds of journals and it was amazing
to read what I was writing about at age
15 16 it all came true by age 20 what I
was writing about in age 20 all happened
in my 30s like and it wasn't like a in
some of it was almost in the form of
prayer um some people would characterize
but really it was just this is what I
want in my life this is what I want to
bring into my life this is what I think
I can do if given these um opportunities
um to be responsible and and to use my
life for the highest service and every
single thing uh continues to happen and
so when you when you reflect upon that
you know what do you make of that like
what what was the the I think it's kind
of what you're saying I think there's
something um that we can't
scientifically prove uh that um that we
have the capacity as humans to really um
if we put enough vision and interest uh
in an outcome happening uh if our
intentions are good I think um and if
it's going to work for the greater good
of humanity I think a lot of it can
happen and so um it's not like it's a w
wish list you write it down it happens
tomorrow but the the the themes of all
of it have happened and a lot of it in
Great specificity of what was written
and so I've I've really committed even
more so to journaling and the power of
prayer and the power of you know really
medit meditating on um um in asking for
clarity and messages from whatever you
believe in yeah um and it and it has
continued to play a huge role in my life
well there is something powerful about
taking a thought that's occurring to you
and when you write it down it becomes
just a little bit more real yeah and
when you revisit that or you repeat it
it becomes a little bit more entrenched
and then it finds its way into your kind
of daily awareness and then it gets
spoken about and before you know it
there's a you know a material
representation of that idea even if just
a kernel to build upon and that's how
all dreams are created constructed right
absolutely so when you when you Journal
is it take a certain is there a form to
that like is it it doesn't sound like
it's the artist way kind of morning
Pages it's more intentional no it's
definitely not morning pages and I I
like that practice and I have done that
at times when I've wanted to kind of
create some more creativity flow in my
life but but really for me it's um a
little bit of reflecting on you know
what's happened in the last day week or
you know this experience today and what
I learned from it and and kind of um you
know as if I was writing to a future
self that want to learn from the
experience and then a lot of it is is
and what am I um you know what am I
wanting to bring into my life so it is a
little bit in the vision manifesting you
know and and this is what I want like
you know to bring into my life with my
son this week you know I have my son
this week and you know he's going to be
I really want to bring into giving him
an experience to you know go Boogie
boarding and help him with his fear of
the ocean and this is what I'm planning
on it's almost like a game plan for my
life and um and so for me I think that
also helps me um I think it's like have
less um stress or anxiety with how I'm
going to spend my time cuz I kind of map
it out in the journal and or what
experiences I want to have um and then
you know it also gives me a thing to go
back and look at later if I need to if I
was going through a hard time or having
a challenging experience and really kind
of see how that was affecting me uh and
oftentimes I find that what felt like
was really challenging then turned out
not to be so much and then that helps me
kind of deal with Ching situations in
real time with more confidence cuz it's
kind of like that saying this shall to
pass you know it's you kind of realize
like um you know one of my favorite
quotes of all time is uh from this poem
If by rard Kipling and it says if you
can meet Triumph and disaster and treat
those two imposters just the same and I
feel like my journal has taught me that
over and over again it's like nothing's
as good as I as it was when I was
writing it down and nothing is as
challenging as it was when I was WR
writing it down right and academically
or intellectually we know that to be
true but when it gets tested in the real
world right when you're flying high and
like selling your company or you're at
your low point you know it's pretty hard
put those into motion yeah totally
there's a lot
of um Talk these days about practices
like journaling and mindfulness and
meditation all these self-care practices
that have really become you know
mainstream in a way that they never have
been before so what was it about you at
at 15 you know in
1989 or 90 or whenever it was when you
began this process I mean there wasn't a
lot of talk about it then like what what
was going on with the 15-year-old Blake
that thought like I'm going to start
journaling yeah I I think um I I don't
really know because my par neither of my
parents were journalers so I don't
really got I think most of the things
that I did in my life at an early age
resulted I read a lot and I'm sure I
read a book of someone you could have
been through school or whatever that
talked that was successful that talked
about journaling being an important part
of their process for me also I was a
really competitive tennis player and
part of my early journaling was really
um from kind of a mental um you know
mental practice of like really
journaling about my practices or matches
that I won or lost or why I think I lost
them and so it was a little bit more of
an athletic bent originally um when I
read those journals a lot of it is
around my tennis and my desire to win
and my frustration and matches that I
lost and you know and these types of
things but um I really don't know um
where uh what was the Catalyst I just
know that it's something that kind of
I've always done yeah one of the things
that that I related to a lot about you
growing up was your passion for tennis I
was a swimmer I mean I'm older than you
but the the story is somewhat similar in
that we both had this passion for this
sport we weren't the most talented but
we both figured out that we could bridge
that Talent deficit Gap by working
harder than the other guy yeah to get to
that place that we wanted to get to and
how that you know informed you as an
entrepreneur and perhaps continues to
inform you today yeah I know I mean I
think there's a real blessing even
though it didn't feel like it when I was
the last man on the team every year um I
think there was a blessing in um having
to the only way to have any level of
success uh was just to outwork everyone
you know I think it's why my favorite
movie of all time is Rudy you know like
I'm so connected with that character of
wanting to be on the nerded Dame
football team so bad that he would do
anything uh because that was really the
mentality that I had uh being a tennis
player which has been probably the
greatest gift as an entrepreneur because
being an entrepreneur is off also and
often an individual sport um and uh and
you have to you know work extremely hard
it can be extremely lonely and you know
the there's no certainty of the results
same with tennis you know or swimming
for you so I think I a lot of what I
learned and I think was my destiny was
uh to learn that through tennis so that
it could be applied to my
entrepreneurial career um and and I
think that was incredible preparation
for it well you strike me as somebody
who who you know has always followed his
curiosity who's unafraid to fail who you
know kind of looks at the world with
wide eyes in a very optimistic way and
says oh there's a thing like I could do
that right most kids you know are not
like that or they don't they don't
filter the world that way so I'm curious
about how that was instilled in you do
you think that was hardwired into you
just from birth did that come from your
parents I mean you you know your dad was
a doctor yeah your mom cookbook author
like Big Time cookbook sold like
millions of copies of this no butter
cookbook or whatever um you know who was
the who was the mentor in the house that
was you know instilling that in you well
I think you know I have you uh spent any
time with the inag are you fam with that
so I went pretty deep in the inag about
two years ago and I'm a seven the
Enthusiast and I feel like shocker yeah
I know it's so I mean that's what's so
amazing about Ingram it's like so dead
on uh and so convicting when you think
of the the areas in my life that
challenge me the most and how it's so
just like prescriptive and reading some
of the great work about the ining gram
but I bring it up because it really has
convinced me that um there's nine types
that we really do arrive here with an
operating system and you know if we want
to get really spiritual about it like
maybe we even choose that operating
system and maybe we come multiple times
and you get to come nine times and try
all the operating systems I don't know
but I feel like I was hardwired as a
seven since the beginning and then I
think then it's up to our parents to
provide the software so if the hardware
was you know my personality type that I
do believe is hardwired in I don't think
that came from my parents because my
brother and sister have totally
different Hardware yeah you know um but
the software is what our parents teach
us our friends our you know places where
we grow up and that is what kind of
creates the unique Ness of each human so
that's the way that I um kind of look at
nature verse nurture um is you know
Hardware we come in with and software we
get and hopefully we get to continue to
update our software as we go right well
your your hustle game was right out of
the gate right like there was no you
know putting a a clamp down on that
right like from teaching tennis lessons
in the neighborhood to the um laundry
delivery service company that you
created in college like it's just been
one successive business adventure after
the other I mean I think a lot of people
look at you and they think of Tom's
obviously your biggest success but that
was the product of you know four or five
businesses that preceded it sure and you
know and what I'm working on now made
for like it's totally a accumulation of
everything I learned from Toms plus the
other businesses so one thing that I
think is interesting about my
entrepreneurial life and I say this
because I've read so books of
entrepreneurs so I didn't graduate from
college but I literally uh don't know
another human that's read more
biographies of entrepreneurs than I have
like I just devoured them in my 20s
because that was my that was the way I
learned and so most entrepreneurs um
especially if they've started multiple
businesses um there's usually a pretty
clear link between the businesses um now
you look at my career I was in the
laundry business The Outdoor Advertising
business the online drivers education
business the television network business
you know the shoe philanthropy business
and now in the you know space with made
for to help people you know live their
best lives and reach the highest state
of wellbe and so there's really no
direct links between them but what there
is if if you and I've really spent time
thinking about this is there is a
cumulative of like I learned this so
This allowed me to apply it to this and
I learned this and it made me apply to
this and so you know now um definitely
you know with having this mission of
trying trying to help people with their
mental health and their personal
well-being is a derivative of what I saw
with Toms and what I experienced um in
that you know a lot of people in
developing countries while they have
very little material wealth um they have
a lot better mental health than we have
here in the United States and so what
are we missing that people in Uganda or
Ethiopia or Venezuela you know in very
rural areas are getting so right um and
that's what was kind of the question
that led to um to really going down this
path and working with scientists and
really trying to understand that which
led to the made for company so all my
businesses I think even though they're
not related per se they all have like
this kind of Arc of of curiosity and and
and personal experience right I don't
want to go through Siri Adam like all
your businesses I think everybody should
listen to uh how I your episode of How I
built this with guy RZ it takes you know
he does a great job of taking you
through like all these iterations of
things that you've done um I'm more
interested and not that that's not it's
super fascinating and perhaps we can
recount some aspects of the Tom story
but I'm interested in that inflection
point when you're at the peak of your
powers with Toms and you have this kind
of emotional realization that all these
things that you've done in some part
um to be you know a happy person right
like you're doing it of service you're
running a business you're employing all
these people um but it's also very much
an aspect of you know these cultural
drivers these messages that we've been
told our whole life like if you want to
be happy well you be financially
successful and you serve others and all
these things and you kind of met your
maker with that a little bit in terms of
you know really taking stock and
inventory in an honest way with how you
were feeling about yourself so let's
talk about that a little bit yeah I mean
it's looking back on it now it's it's
such a blessing even though it felt so
challenging at the time um because I'm
an achiever and I set my goals and write
in my journal and say this is what I
want to accomplish and when you
accomplish it you expect to get a
certain feeling and I think um most
people in their life um spend most of
their life having these external goals
and external accomplishments or um
Family situations or whatnot that we
have been told by Society is the um will
result in happiness and um maybe because
I started early um in my entrepreneurial
life and I grew up fast I achieved you
know pretty much everything that I set
out to achieve you know um before I was
40 and that to everyone and myself at
the time thought like a huge blessing um
but what it what I found was is that
I woke up one day or a series of days
and didn't really think that my future
was going to be better than my past and
that's a really scary place to be in um
I think that leads to a lot of mental
health issues and devastating um
situations for people and it wasn't that
I didn't like my w my life or my
situation or my business or I didn't
wasn't proud of what we accomplished
with Tom's but I realize that if we
anyone in me specific in this situation
if we are looking to external
accomplishments external praise anything
anything even your kids love for your
sense of peace and joy ultimately you
will realize that it doesn't work MH and
that is a really scary place to land and
that's that's where I landed I had to
lished everything I'd been on the covers
of every magazine I'd helped you know at
that point 80 million children get shoes
I'd made hundreds of millions of dollars
I mean I literally you had kids I had
everything that I possibly could have
been told was the key to a not just a
happy life but actually a meaningful
life like I you know it wasn't like I
you know just chased after like the you
know the these hedonistic right and it
wasn't just a company that was profit
above everything else like there's such
a built-in massive surf aspect what you
were doing you think buffer you against
you think but actually I think it in
some way made it worse the
shame feeling that way that but also
there was nowhere to go so if you think
about if you had a traditional
businessman or woman and they built a
huge company made a bunch of money had
all this and they realized ah it's
really not what it's cracked up to be
now I can be a philanthropist for the
next 20 years doing that but I already
done that and I realized it wasn't any
better than you know and so so I reached
a point where um and there's this this
this amazing teacher who I I love named
sad Guru I don't know if you know but we
got to spend some time together we have
a very shared passion for golf and we've
golfed together and he's stayed at my
house in Wyoming and and and he said
that in the uh in the yoga sutras
there's um this one book and I forget
which one it is but the very first line
is uh and now yoga and what that meant
to him as he explained because he knows
quite a bit about my life story is that
moment was when my yoga really started
was I had to accomplish all those things
I had to do all of that in my life to
realize that the joy and the peace and
the sense of connection to the great
mystery that I've been searching for
would never be found in those external
things and that's when I could start my
yoga practice yeah and that's to refrain
as an opportunity but ultimately to have
to basically experience all of that on
the grandest level in order to
understand fully that it isn't the
solution right because anybody who's
listening or
watching myself included yeah there's a
little bit of that but there's also like
yeah maybe he says that but you know
that's not going to be the way it is for
me right and it's like it doesn't matter
how many successful people you know sit
across from me and tell me you know
their version of exact same story it
always holds true right and yet it's so
difficult to wrap the human mind around
that like how could that possibly be
true because it's so contrary to
everything that we've been hardwired to
believe since as long as we can remember
totally I mean I actually had a very um
prophetic conversation where I was told
this was going to happen and it was by
Ted Turner so I looked up to Ted Turner
a lot as an entrepreneurs I said I read
all every biography and there's a few
great ones on Ted Turner and Ted Turner
had some similarities with me you know
he started an outdoor advertising
company before starting CNN started
network uh I I lived on a sailboat for
six years Ted Turner was a huge sailor
won America's Cup started a started a
cable TV Chanel started CNN um so I um
was asked to interview Ted Turner um
maybe seven or eight years ago at the UN
um and I got to spend the morning with
Ted Turner he was real hero to me so
like this was a really special
experience and so I spent you know just
months preparing for this interview and
read every book again and you know was
really excited to do this interview with
Ted and
uh and so right before we went on stage
we're having this conversation and Ted
said to me he said you know we're
talking about life and he said you know
in life and in business especially in
business you know it's like this ladder
and it's not like the corporate ladder
like you're hear about but it's like
this lad L of like believing that if you
climb up this ladder that at the top
there's something magical and something
that's going to give you everything that
you've ever wanted and and as you start
to climb the ladder you see this
beautiful bag on the top of the ladder
and you can only think what's in the bag
when you get to the top and he said I
spent so much of my life climbing that
ladder to get a peak into that bag and
he says and I've seen inside the back
and of course at this age I was like
maybe I don't know was 38 40 years I
said what's in the bag he goes I'll tell
you what's in the bag the bag is empty
and even though I've told you you still
need to climb the ladder and look for
yourself he knows well enough to know
that just him telling you that ain't
going to do it and I never forget that
conversation with Ted I mean it was one
of the most beautiful life like when we
watch the the the movie of Our Lives it
will definitely be in the Highlight Reel
of my life because he told me he said
you're I he saw me he saw himself
probably in me and saw exactly the path
I was on and uh wanted to tell me but
also wanted to tell me that I still had
to go down the path so so was there a
specific moment where it dawned upon you
or was it a kind of a slow realization
slow realization and did you pick up the
phone and call Ted and tell him I've
arrived ared the bag is indeed not not
full it's not full um no it was really
more of a
slow um process and I think that in in a
lot of Life Transformations I think
happens um you know kind of over time
you know I think things just start
losing their luster you start losing a
little bit excitement or energy around
things you start realizing that
something's a little bit more shallow
than you than you realized before um and
in over the cumulative effect you
start just to energetically wake up and
not have that same passion and
enthusiasm and optimism that you built
your life around and that that can be a
pretty scary place um so yeah it was it
was over time over about twoe period of
time for me well the thing that you have
though that I think separates you from
from other people whove who've been in
that place is this Seeker disposition
like you're you know from Reading you
know business entrepreneurial and self-
health books as a young person like you
strike me as somebody who's always
looking to grow all the time right
spiritually emotionally mentally like
there's a firm commitment there right no
matter what like you're always exploring
these different and new
modalities um and I and I have to
suspect that that's been a Saving Grace
like to keep you on this you know
journey of selfimprovement no matter
what because it's rare it would the
typical Arc for somebody like yourself
like setting aside the one forone model
of TOMS would be you know make all your
bank yeah you have this existential
crisis but you ultimately never really
reckon with it or grapple with it and
you just end up playing a bunch of golf
and giving a bunch of money away yeah I
mean that's really and there's there's
there's no judgment in that and
oftentimes people might have their
external goals whether they're Financial
or otherwise met you know later in life
in their 60s or their 70s and then they
can kind of Coast on the golf course or
wherever their hobby of choice is uh
into old age and enjoy being
grandparents and all these other things
that are out there that satisfy
um but when it happens to you at age 40
uh you're in a different position and so
I think I am very grateful that I have
this Seeker disposition uh that I'm
insanely curious uh and I really believe
that you can um kind of work through any
uh situation that you're that you're in
and so it really led me to go down the
path of um okay there are a lot of
people in the world that are thriving
and what are they doing that I'm not
doing because I did everything that
Society told me to do I did everything
that my parents told me to do like I
think I've really got an A+ on on all
these things and I feel like this but
not everyone feels like this and there's
some people that have gone through what
I've gone through and are thriving and
there's some people that haven't had to
reach any of those external
accomplishments and they're thriving so
who what who are these people and what
are they doing that I'm not doing and
that led me down you know working with
you know many different scientists that
study human behavior top universities in
the country it led me to seeking out
people like sad Guru and other you know
spiritual teachers like Rob Bell like I
mean it really led me down a path of
really talking to the widest net of
people from scientists to Shaman to you
know um going down to South America and
having plant medicine Journeys I mean I
was willing to try anything um but what
I found and it's no it's it I I don't I
think it's um it's no surprise that It
ultimately led to something that then
led to another entrepreneurial venture
and you know so it's like it's like
obvious I mean that's what's going to
happen I feel like I'm so predictable at
this point um but but it did because
what happened I realized was the this
the things that were holding me back was
not paying attention to the little
things in my life life the internal
things I was so externally focused that
I wasn't really taking care of myself um
not just in some of the traditional
self-care ways that you know we we we
kind of spoke about the beginning but
some very specific practices that there
have been you know you know kind of
double Placebo studies at University
show have a benefit on how you know
people's energy levels are how their
sleep is or their you know kind of
Outlook of the future being better than
the past and so um what I found was even
though I tried so many different things
and met with so many different people
the the what made the biggest difference
was actually working on the simplest
things and just like really dialing in
some simple things like the power of my
breath or spending time in nature and
why that's important for my brain or you
know how your mindset can change through
neuroplasticity and that's those little
simple things that I worked on is what
had the biggest effect and over time is
that really started to kind of give me
and ground me and feeling like I was
more in control with how I woke up and
felt every day that's what led to and I
think that's where my the disposition of
of of that I had that caused me to start
time like okay how can I help as many
people learn this too because there are
a lot of people I mean out there
suffering I mean you can read any
headline in the news now and you see
that we have more people on
anti-depressants than ever in the
history of America you know more people
taking sleep aids just to get a night's
sleep I mean we are as a society
suffering and having experienced some of
that suffering really motivated me to
you know want to do something to help
people not have that you know suffering
if it's not necessary yeah 100% I mean
we're not in a great place with mental
health physical health across the board
here we are the day after the election
anxiety rates are like you know off the
charts at you know historic levels of
course um and I want to get into all
these modalities but I think a thought
that I had
was beneath the success and the admitted
um you know kind of uh drive for
external validation that's that's been a
Hallmark of you in the past there has to
still be this undercurrent of humility
in order to be that Seeker because
because you're not going to seek out Rob
Bell or S Guru you're not going to be on
the on the on the path to you know
sitting at the feet of wise people to
hear what they have to say unless you
enter that equation from a place of
humility this place of like I have more
to learn like these people seem to know
something that I don't like let me allow
myself to be open to what they have to
say yeah I think maybe that's you know
maybe comes back from being an athlete
and always like having so much respect
for your coaches mhm you know and like
really really at an early age seeing
that you know no matter what if you're
the best player in the world and when I
was growing up it was Andre Agassi you
know he still had coach yeah you know
like does coaches I've had a life coach
for 14 years and it's weird that most
people don't like we understand that
like how are you going to be a great
athlete if you don't have a coach but we
don't think of that in any other context
of Life yeah I mean it's I think you
know I don't think therapists and life
coaches get near the respect or the are
held up with enough importance in our
society because I think being a human uh
we need coaches and and they they take
many different forms and everyone can
choose their own based on their
spiritual beliefs or their you know um
their life situations but for me I've
always been oriented and part of the
secret mentality of like who who knows
who's experienced this who knows this
who could coach me on this who could
give me a perspective I don't have and
um and I'm really grateful that I've had
that mentality and I think it you know
um it does you know the word humility is
one that I think is always uh an
interesting one because people who say
they're humble that's like an oxymoron
right if you're saying it you're you're
performing on some level and that's
coming from a place of ego yeah so I
think I always but I do think it's fair
in this situation to say that at least
from a disposition is I approach my
challenges with humility based on the
fact that I know there is someone who
has studied this situation or been in
the situation and can provide some real
uh value right and and I'm really
grateful for all the people that have
been you know mentors and coaches and
and and therapists and people who have
helped me on this journey because being
a human is not easy certainly is not one
of the modalities that I know you're
passionate about and I know you talked
with Tim Ferris about this recently is
the Hoffman process yes I I do want to
get into this a little bit F I know
about it I've never done it myself do
you know Neil Strauss yes so Neil's
constantly telling me I have to do the
the Hoffman process and I know that I
would glean so much but he's like when
are you GNA go when you going to goil
after our medicine wheel I was like look
you gave a gift to me I was like I'm
going to give the gift to Hoffman to you
and she went so if the Shaman's going uh
you know um clearly um everyone there's
some gold there right um no it's it's
it's I say to people it's like I I think
it's like the the if if if we got a hard
going back to the the analogy of if we
come in with an operating system we get
software like I think Hoffman is like
getting all the bugs out of your
software like every software program is
going to have glitches and bugs and and
and and we all have parents and we all
have life experiences and we all have
our own versions of traumas and things
that you know really um create patterns
in our lives and Hoffman is an
unbelievable experience I use the word
experience they say process but it
really is an
experiential um you know seven days
where you really start to understand why
the heck you are the way you are and no
judgment good or bad but knowing why and
and which of your patterns and which of
your um you know ways of being or
responses that are so automatic at this
stage and hardwired into your brain
which of them are serving you and which
of them aren't
and then they have incredible ways to
rewire yourself to let go of the things
that aren't serving you um my favorite
Hoffman story is and I I don't think
I've shared this with um is um is that I
lost 20 pounds after Hoffman uhhuh now I
wasn't like heavily overweight I was
like I'm like 165 now I was probably
like 185 and that was kind of a normal
weight um and uh and I literally was
carrying 20 PBS of stress MH 20 pounds
of un you know things that I had never
worked through from my childhood um you
know and and so hoffen would never say
that they it's not a weight loss aight
thing but by by having your hormones
disregulated it's it's you know keeping
you heavier than you normally would be
yeah I mean I don't know the science
behind that but it's like it's just
there's the correlation is exactly to
that timetable um and I bring that up
just because it's like Hoffman has kind
of a magical effect on pretty much
everyone I know that's ever gone and
people do become almost Evangelical
about it that have gone like you've seen
with Neil um because it's just so
liberating I mean it's just like you
want every human to be able to live with
this awareness and this Freedom that you
get through understanding how you got to
where you are but a lot of it is correct
me if I'm wrong about like early
imprinting like in your youth right and
and the kind of messages that you're
receiving as a young person from your
parents and how those you know really
become part of that um it you know it's
somewhere in between software and
Hardware really right because it becomes
so entrenched in you that it really is
your Hardware at some point at some
point yeah I mean because I I would say
the thing is is they talk about this
thing called the negative love syndrome
and so basically they say his children
from like age you know basically up
until age 12 um is you know you all you
need to survive and all you want is love
or attention from your parents and so
everything that you do or learn to do is
either doing something that's mirroring
your parents behaviors and patterns to
get their love or is the exact opposite
of your parents to get their attention
and so you can literally Trace back all
of in they help you understand these
patterns that are basically becoming
your software and you can trace back
back to which parent or caretaker if you
had a grandmother or someone that was
really involved and you can actually
Trace back to them either doing the same
thing or the exact opposite thing right
and it's fascinating because then once
you start to see your personality and
your life experiences a collection of
these patterns then you realize how
unconscious you are and how you're
living your life and and that is can be
frightening but also incredibly
enlightening to people because then you
have the choice to choose do you want to
continue to live in this unconscious way
and just responding to Things based on
what you patterned you as a kid or do
you want to um use these practices to
disrupt those patterns and then choose a
different path and um yeah it's so in
your case so what was what would be an
example of an epiphany that you've had
as a result of undergoing this I mean
one of the ones that's the most silly
and and kind of embarrassing um which I
think is why I like to share it is my
mom I was the first child and I was also
the first grandchild and my mom was a
housewife before she wrote her cookbooks
and you know um when I came around I was
her pride and joy I mean I was like
literally the center of attention like
no one's been the center of attention
cuz my grand I was the first grandkid I
was the first child I was I mean I was
and so my mom's whole sense of self for
a number of years really revolved around
this baby and then this young kid and I
felt that in a big way and it continued
on even once I had brothers and sisters
and so my earliest experiences with
women uh specifically um and my mom was
um I am feel really good when I'm the
center of attention uhhuh and so um it's
it's you start looking at some of my
life choices and they've all been to get
more attention you know and I mean even
even some of the really pure
philanthropic stuff it's like well that
gets more positive attention right and
and so it's amazing you didn't become an
actor but you did do the reality TV
thing so I guess in certain respects you
did in some ways right but but what but
was this is the fascinating thing is
okay it's one thing to say okay like I
understand where my deep need and
comfort for attention is but where is
that holding me back where is that
causing me to not feel authentic in my
life and then creating some um some
negative emotions in my life and so it
wasn't like looking back at like oh some
of the career choices those are so
obvious now if I'm someone who is
starving for attention all the time but
then it was something like really simple
and this is my I just in a meditation
Hof and I realized I love to go
snowboarding and I realized that on ski
lifts you know you have three or four
people on the lift you have 15 minutes
on the lift that my need for attention
was so great this is embarrassing but
it's funny is that I would always
manipulate the conversation on a ski
lift to ultimately so someone had to ask
me what I did for a living so I could
say I started Tom so they could tell me
how great I
was like every ski lift is the same damn
conversation and it was so embarrassing
to realize that my little boy and me
still needed the attention so much no
matter how much success I've had doesn't
matter how many magazine covers you
still need that
nebras to say so what do you do to be
Inon hle oh you know and so once I
realized that it was so liberating
because I stopped doing it I was like I
don't need it it's not it's not serving
me anymore this is like limiting me from
really learning about this person that
could be like the most fascinating
person in the world or have a great
message for me because I'm so focused on
needing my own attention and it's
created so much more real um intimacy
and meeting with strangers is create
more Comfort at at parties like I don't
like I actually play a game with myself
now where I tried like in a new
environment see if I can get through the
entire night with no one knowing
anything about my professional life you
know they they they learn things about
me about my kids they learn things about
about my hobbies but it but it really
was I mean that's a long drawn out way
to say one thing I learned but that's
the level of kind of the root of things
you get to and then when you realize
them and you kind of can laugh at them
and look at them without any judge
judgement which is what Hoff really
Alles you do then you can be free from
them yeah I mean I think that's the most
powerful aspect of the story you just
told like as as funny as it is the way
in which you can kind of own it
completely without that Pang of shame or
embarrassment there is a freedom in that
like you can you and that's I think that
that's totally related to like the
weight loss thing you're shedding that
burden on yourself so you're able to
carry yourself in a lighter way a more
cleare eyed way where you can be present
with people and not be in that like need
neediness you know kind of dynamic that
basically is completely uh you know
perverse and not authentic to who you
truly are like that inner child within I
right when you walked up today your
t-shirt for those who can't see you says
truth on it and it was so like Divine
that you were in that t-shirt because it
is so much I think part of this journey
for me has been being to look at myself
and look at everything with no judgment
so that I can live not just the most
truthful life but like truth to myself
and that's when I feel like we really
get this sense of just lightness when
there's there is no Jud everything
happens for a reason and you make
decisions good or bad judged by Society
but it's it's I don't believe that
there's that any of it has come from a
bad place but I think when you do this
inner work and things like Hoffman you
start to put the pieces together and
then you like oh like I could beat
myself up for being like always having
to be the center of attention and what a
horrible characteristic that is and no
one wants to be around someone like that
or I can be like no I'm just a little
boy who that's all they knew growing up
and so when they got out to be a big boy
they just had to keep playing the same
role but I don't have to do that anymore
yeah it's also not about vilifying your
parents like totally you know what I
mean like they do right so but that's
been like a thing with me like I'm I
have fear of of engaging with that
process because I don't want to cast
dispersions on my parents but ultimately
that blinds me from the relief that I
could receive by working through these
things right I mean I'm a I'm a product
of of of 12ep like you know I've been
sober a long time so my entry point to
any kind of tools whatsoever is the
process of like you know performing the
inventory yeah which reveals you know
it's similar in that it reveals these
character traits that you have that that
you know tend to recur in your life and
and Lead You Down dark Pathways and
there's a self-awareness that comes with
that and then you get into the immense
process but there's so much work that
Still Remains to be done you know I'll
never forget sitting across from I had
gab mate on the podcast and he starts
you know I knew he would do this and I
allowed him to do it but for him to like
kind of flip it and just start he's
starting asking me questions about my
parents and it's like you know to him
it's Crystal Clear like why I'm behaving
the way I'm behaving you know and it's
like there's so much to learn and to be
gained by um by not being afraid of of
you know availing yourself of all these
interesting modalities so I think you
know at some point I will do the Hoffman
process and it's not like you're not
going to reveal what actually happens
it's like you go to this place and you
undergo this experience that is very you
know t
tactile right it's not about reading a
book or or like experi that's the thing
it's a fun exper I mean like there are
challenging times but there are some
really fun times too that you know us as
adults don't get the opportunity to
engage in and and modalities and ways
that you do that and so it's very I
always say it's very
experiential um and and I do think there
are many of my friends who have
hesitated most of them have all gone now
um because I'm quite persuasive in that
regard
but some of them were the ones that had
great relationships with their parents
like oh I don't want to go and vilify my
parents I'm like look I had amazing
childhood I'm still incredibly close to
my parents and like everything that I
learned that I learned from them of
patterns that I don't want to keep
anymore many of them came from just you
know the way that they loved me there
was nothing wrong with it it just has
there's a cause and effect for every way
right and and I think what I've also um
found it to be incredibly helpful uh and
and I go back to probably more than ever
is how I parent my kids because I'm
realizing you no matter how good or how
involved or how I'm trying to do there
are um responses that I'm creating even
if they're unintended and I am never
going to do it perfect and I already
have a spot for all my kids at age 21 to
go to hoffen already
prepaid so uh you know but um and I
probably be the day the week after their
hoffin I'll learn more about myself than
I've ever learned um but but yeah like
it's a really great tool to have that
awareness of how there are unintended
consequences even for the best
motivations right um well let's talk
about made for sure so you have
this occurrence in your life where
you're feeling depressed and not sure
what the next thing is you're grappling
with you know meaning in your life how
does that ultimately translate into this
new Venture well it's it's fun because
you know I as I've said in we started
our conversation talking about a shaman
so I think this is like the perfect
segue into how this happened you know I
um my first response to dealing with my
depression and and kind of you know lack
of positive outlook for the first time
in my life which was you know really
intense for me because I'm such a
positive person was to go the super
spiritual super Supernatural way so it
was Shaman it was plant medicine
Journeys it was you know theas
meditation Retreats I mean it was that
and uh there was a lot of insights and
stuff that I gained from all of that
experiences um but I met uh a guy who's
now my business partner uh at made for
his name is Pat dosset and we met
through mutual friends and he was a Navy
SEAL for nine years and he uh thinks
probably like you would stereotypically
think Navy SEAL think he's very
methodical science only no Fufu no fads
no I mean this guy is like it's
a shaman free zone with this guy this
guy you don't use the word Shaman in the
room with that and I met him and we were
on a surf trip together and uh we're
talking about kind of what he's going
through what I was doing and and what
his personal interests are and um and
he's sure that you know if I asked this
question to him and several others
because I was also thinking in this way
I was like if you guys didn't have to
work for money and you could do anything
you want to do with your life what would
you do like anything and Pat gave an
answer that was very much in line with
kind of what I was seeking and that is
you know I would help um everyday people
live their best lives by getting access
to the information and the science that
very few people get except Navy Seals
and top performers and I thought wow
that's that's amazing like I that's kind
of you know one of the that's kind of
something I would love to understand as
well and so over a series of surf
sessions and and lunches on the boat we
talked about that there is is um an
incredible growing body of knowledge in
the scientific community of you know um
practices and habits that everyday
people could could partake in and would
make a real you know uh difference in
their lives and Pat um you know was very
interested in taking an approach that
was very different than mine was was
really interviewing scientists and
getting them um to share what they've
learned and what they've been able to
prove in terms of human behavior and so
I said I think this sounds great so I
was like Pat Like Pat was working for
Google at the time I was like if you you
know would be open to leaving Google and
pursuing this full-time I would fund it
almost like a research project um and
some of it for my own benefit because of
the place that I was in and we agreed to
start working on it as a project um
that's another thing a lot of businesses
I mean Tom's wasn't a business it was a
project for a while um and so the made
for was a project and um and you know
shortly into hat starting to kind of
Kick the tires about okay what are some
of the practices that are most uh
prevalent in high performers and people
who are living in a high state of
well-being he met um Andrew huberman who
I you just had on the show and so and he
met Andrew at Hoffman oh he did Back to
Hoffman that's unbelievable I didn't
know that part that's crazy yes so Pat
went to Hoffman after I talked so great
about it and then um if you've been to
Hoffman you can go back on the
graduation night for any class and we
had a friend graduating and so Pat went
to support him and Andrew was graduating
and they sat next chair at dinner wow so
that's how that amazing uh and so um
Andrew has a a lab at Stanford that is a
and he's a neuroscientist for people who
didn't hear that podcast uh that you had
him on and uh Pat started telling Andrew
about what we're doing and Andrew just
lit up Andrew is like this is exactly
what we need like we us scientists get
so frustrated that we spend all of our
Lives you know proving things that could
really benefit Humanity but we don't
have a delivery mechanism that gets out
there unless we write a book or write a
paper or this or that and Pat and I were
much more interested in um teaching
people in a experiential way versus
writing a book or yeah hosting a podcast
or whatever we could do at that point
and so Andrew uh signed on to join us um
and he said okay let's
identify um originally we were going for
12 going back to 12 steps or 12 habits
or 12 months of the year we're looking
for 12 things that could transform
someone's life 12 either habits or daily
practices um that have been proven by
the scientific Community to make a
demonstrative difference and working
with Andrew and him introducing us to
other scientists and Specialties
everything from you know sleeping to
nutrition to um you know breath
techniques we found that we could only
find 10 things so um we ultimately
create a program it's called made for uh
that is a 10-month program where each
month uh we send you a kit and in that
kit comes in your in the mail you can
have everything you need to learn the
new habit or practice for 30 days and
and the the the kind of um thinking
behind teaching people this way verse
you know using a digital app or a
website or any other modality was what
we recognized was in this time period in
our life we are so digitally distracted
uh we have so much information it's not
that don't have the information but we
very we find it very hard to carve out
the space to really um experience deep
learning and in order for deep learning
to happen you need to have something you
do consistently without distraction and
so the made for program is completely
analog there's no digital app or
application and it requires you know a
little bit of effort you know 10 15
minutes a day for 30 days to learn or to
experience this this habit or practice
that can make a difference in your life
and so um we have have a a different
scientist and different kind of
University or lab partnered with each of
the months um and uh and and it was you
know basically a derivative of the 10
things that I found made the biggest
difference for me yeah I love that it's
analog um not that there aren't powerful
digital tools that are available to
people but when you kind of canvas that
space I mean we're in the age of like
people trying to connect with their
Wellness in a meaningful way and there
are a lot of very you know well
developed helpful apps out there but
they tend to pick a lane like this is
mindfulness this is meditation this is
you know sleep this is a fitness tracker
but there isn't anything that looks at
this holistically and even more
specifically from the perspective of how
you actually change a habit right like
if you can be on all these apps but if
you're lacking tools for how to actually
make a habit stick you're not going to
reap the benefits of of any of it right
and so I think it's really smart and
interesting that you would go the
neuroplasticity route and really analyze
like how do you actually get somebody to
adopt a new habit with staying power and
that comes through tiny actions taken
consistently you know that have staying
power only through repetition right and
breaking things down into their smallest
little pieces seems to be the consensus
about how we do this you're either an
all-in person you know I'm kind of that
way but most not that way you know um so
if you read you know Charles DG's work
or or James C's book Atomic habits like
they all kind of say the same thing
which is like you got to start with
these tiny little things and the problem
is it's not sexy it's not like I'm going
to run an ultramarathon in a week you
know it's it's really like these tiny
little things that no one gives a
about and don't look good on Instagram
totally and that's why as a business it
can be quite challenging because we and
especially with having a business
partner Like Pat who's like no bu
like all of our marketing and
all of our explanations of what we're
going to help you with sounds really
boring cuz it's like we're B you're
going to drink water every two hours or
something like that yeah like I mean
we're going to talk about hydration but
the interesting thing about the water is
is the first step in getting people to
really make a sustained change is
convincing them that that they're the
type of person that can make a sustain
changed even if they have the desire
they all the the mindset that most of us
have especially if we're adults you know
age over 25 years old uh is I am the way
that I am and and I've tried everything
or you know this doesn't stick and so we
actually start with hydration because a
it's one of the most important uh you
know aspects of how our bodies operate
and there's incredible amount of science
behind you know the negative effects of
even a small amount of dehydration which
a huge amount of Americans are
experiencing every day so we start with
something that we know is going to have
a physiological impact almost
immediately unless you already have a
incredible hydration practice which most
people don't even if they think they do
um and the second thing is it's so
simple like you we have a very special
water bottle that you get in your kit it
keeps track of how much water you drink
throughout the day it has a tactile kind
of reward system with these like prayer
beads that you move every time you
finish a bottle so you get that dopamine
hit every time you do gamifying a little
gamifying a little bit yeah and so so
but what the beautiful thing about that
is is it's something so simple but
almost everyone immediately experiences
two things one they experien the
physiological benefit of being more more
hydrated but the more important thing
they experien is I actually stuck to
something for 30 days I accomplished
something it was simple it was water but
I can't wait to see what month two is
because I have positive momentum and I
my mindset is now not one of a fixed
mindset but of a growth mindset and
Carol DW wrote a great book right yeah
so the story changes from you don't
understand like I don't do that kind of
stuff I'm not the kind of person that
does these things I don't like that to a
value shift where by undergoing you know
the first of 10 of these you start to
tweak the brain into believing like I'm
the kind of person who makes positive
changes in my life and the cascading
like Downstream impact of that is the
most powerful thing of all it's less
about the water
more about like that shift in
selfawareness and that change in the
story you tell yourself about who you
are and what you're capable of for for
people who' have seen the movie Karate
Kid this is my favorite analogy is you
know when Mr Miyagi uh is teaching uh
you know Ralph uh the karate chop he has
him washing his cars wax on wax on waxs
off and Ralph is so frustrated like this
is boring I don't understand why I'm
doing this there and then there's that
great moment in the movie when he
immediately sees that the wax on is the
the great blocking of the karate chop
and that is a lot of what we have found
with these practices of made Force these
are basic simple things that we're going
to have someone do and the reason
they're basic and simple is because
they're easy to stick to so we set you
up for success by not asking you to do
herculin things each month they're
things that you know anyone can do
regardless of the time that they have
available we are very busy and so the
nice thing about these RS you understand
because in the kit also comes a you know
15 20 minute read on the science behind
why you're doing what you're doing so
you understand where you're going and
what what the benefits will be by
accomplishing the challenge that month
but some of them are a little bit like
the the waxing on wax off you're kind
like oh I'm drinking water I'm drinking
water and then at the end by some
prompts that we give you we realize oh
no what I really was doing was changing
the neuroplasticity in my mind to tell
myself that I can stick to something for
you know every day and so when the next
challenge comes I'm going to be more
likely to accomplish it even if it seems
a little harder in the beginning because
I've built this this change in my growth
mindset and so ultimately the the the
biggest reward of starting made for for
me and I think Pat would probably say
the same and Andrew would be is we get
the most amazing testimonials from
people that have had Transformations
that have nothing to do with our program
like we don't have I mean like you know
like that is the thing that's so cool is
that people say I've always wanted to do
this in my life and now I just did it or
I had this really challenging um
relationship with my mother-in-law that
I've been avoiding for 20 years and I
fixed it or and people have lost weight
and weight loss isn't part of our
program it's you know it's amazing the
what I see is what has happened is when
people do these other things and you
know they optimize their sleep through
the program or you know they heal
relationships or have a gratitude
practice the all these things that we've
all kind of heard of
but when they do them in the systematic
way what they ultimately do is change
their mindset and whatever they do with
changing their mindset just always
astonishes me because I'm like we never
thought about that when we were
designing this program and and that's
what's been the most rewarding is we had
these great Zoom calls with members and
we just chat and hear what they're going
through and it reminds me of the early
days of Tom's being on the ground giving
shoes and seeing the joy in these kids
faces because you know someone who's
gone through a hard time and has faced
something challenging whether it was
depression for me or the loss of a loved
one or loss of a job and then being able
to grab onto something like the made 4
program and make a change like there's
just nothing better like it's the
coolest thing to hear these uh
experiences that our members have had
and it's pretty new right like you you
launched it pretty recently so you're in
kind of like a beta test mode with like
a smaller group of people or what do you
have like a couple thousand people doing
this yeah so we started actually um so
almost almost I guess it was two years
ago or a year and a half ago we finished
the program and we did a formal beta
people beta test of a thousand people
and they were friends family we did some
you know kind of random advertising on
Facebook to get some diversity in the in
the beta group and we had a thousand
people do the beta group and we refined
the program a lot during that time we
officially launched to the public on
March 4th like a few days before Co hit
and uh it was it was a fascinating time
to launch I mean it was
it was really hard from a business
perspective because we had all this
media and stuff planned to share what we
were doing um which all of that got
squashed for several months because the
news cycle so focused on covid but what
was great about it was I think the you
know thousand people that signed up
those two months that did get the
information through Instagram or
whatever we had means of reaching people
they have been become our greatest
Advocates because during a time of covid
when there's so much uncertainty so much
you know feeling of loss so much change
so much fear they were able to ground
themselves each month in whatever they
were learning with made for and so we've
actually seen kind of opposite of our
projections where it started off slow
and then it's just had this hockey stick
growth and I think we have 5,000 people
going through the program right now and
um and it's all been through this kind
of people sharing their experiences it's
almost all referral in that regard and
uh and it's been really cool that to see
that it has been uh something that
people have really um benefited during
this challenging time of Co so what is
the process of of bringing someone like
Andrew huberman in and like what imp
what kind of impact does he have like
it's one thing to say okay we want to
take these people through a 30-day
challenge there's nothing there's
nothing unique or new about that so
where does the Neuroscience come into
play in terms of you know you I I would
suspect like when you're gamifying the
drinking like those are all little
little tweet
Hues it and it compelling to the to The
Reptilian Brain yes so I think a big
part of what Pat and Andrew specifically
really connected on was really Andrew's
understanding of how the brain works and
how habits are formed from a
neuroscience perspective and so things
like moving the bead every time you
drink the water not only is your body
feeling better cuz it's hydrated but but
Andrew was you know was able to show us
how like gamifying it in that way
creates this dopamine it's so amazing
because it seems so silly it seems so
dumb right yeah but like our brains you
know just love it we're simple simple
folks um you know other things are you
know like you know in the month about
sleep um you know one of the absolute
worst things for Sleep has nothing to do
with how you go to sleep really but how
you wake up and that is is people using
their phone for their alarm clock
because what happens is even if you say
I only use my phone for my alarm clock
what really happens and they have lots
of studies to show this is that when
someone wakes up and they push the
button turn their alarm they see a
notification they see a text they see an
email pop up from their boss immediately
their cortisol level just spikes and so
any opportunity for them to enter the
day with calmness and and and and and
and encourage and engaging mindfulness
practice whatever that is um is gone if
and so really understanding things like
why that cortisol spikes happens when
you see something that is trusting and
then how to intervene and so one of the
things that you get you know in the
Sleep month is we give you a
oldfashioned alarm clock and we say for
30 days try not putting your phone in
your bed and see a do you fall asleep
better because you're not looking at
stressful things or goinging the
internet or last night looking at the
election polls all night long um and
then B when you wake up you don't have
that initial strike of cortisol because
you're not seeing something that can be
stressful right and so it's things like
that that you start hacking when you
have someone like Andrew who looks at
what is actually happening with all
these little mundane behaviors that we
humans do and there's a lot more going
on than we realize right well hydration
and sleep you know it's easy to kind of
grock what the tasks are going to be but
among these 10 habits you also have
vision Clarity nature breath movement
like what do those look like like what
does what does clarity look like or
Vision yeah so so that's really about
and that you know in some ways um goes
back to the over decade that I've worked
with this life coach out of Vancouver
Dave Phillips um you know Dave really
helps mainly works with CEOs and and and
entrepreneurs but he helps all people uh
that he works with really understand how
your um your vision for your life um and
the level of specificity you have with
it has such an effect on how you spend
your life and how you spin your life
affects your levels of stress and and
feelings of happiness or whatnot and so
I spoke at the earlier part about how
like I really feel that I manifest a lot
of my life through my journals um but if
you take that to a step further is when
you look at what your um goals of your
life is and have Clarity around that
then you also recognize okay if these
are my goals this is what I want to
accomplish this is what I want to
experience well then I got to serve
these roles so maybe my goals are you
know this but my roles are I'm a dad I'm
an entrepreneur I'm an athlete and then
if I want to achieve these goals through
these roles I have to there's tasks that
I have to do I have to spend time with
my kids have to pick them up from school
I have to be there for family dinner so
then those start to inform your calendar
and our Calendars our most sacred thing
uh in terms of really being the
predictor of a lot of our well-being and
so in this month we really work with
Dave and in a process that he's
developed to help you really understand
you know how are you really spending
your time and is that really benefiting
you in the way that you think it is and
it really is by looking at different
aspects of you know having these um
having these uh you know clear goals
having these clear um kind of uh you
know kind of vision and mission
statements in your life that really can
be your Northstar and guide you so that
you can make better decisions that that
that are not just reactive decisions on
what the Day brings you but that are
ultimately connected to a vision and
having this Clarity around what that
vision is yeah it's interesting the
clarity piece is tough though like to
bring it back to the Hoffman example if
your behavior is being motivated or
triggered by subconscious impulses that
you're not consciously aware of then
your instincts and your intuition about
what you should and should not be doing
are tainted right like it becomes a
bigger puzzle to you know or thing to
unpack to really get to the bottom of
that and to get to a place where you
have enough Clarity where you can trust
those instincts or that you can say with
assurance that these are truly my values
and this is what's driving me and this
is where I want to head otherwise
maybe you know that thing that you think
you want to do isn't really the thing
that you want to do yeah it's
interesting this is not part of hofman
or made for but it's something that I
would say is one of the um realizations
biggest realizations I've had about
myself and and I think just humans in
general and that is um even without the
hoffen process even without great
coaches just the act of slowing down has
a incredible effect of cutting through
through what is subconscious vers what
is really um in your in your kind of
your best interest or your highest truth
and so part of a program like made for
is really getting people to slow down
enough to really think about things that
they don't typically think about in some
ways and so yes in a perfect situation
you can go deep into your inner child
and your and your and your subconscious
um and unconscious behaviors through a
process like Hoff or something else um
but even without that just the act of
doing a exercise that causes you to slow
down and really think about what's
important to you just the slowing down
aspect can have great great benefits and
and I found that my Mantra right now is
just to slow down in everything I do
because when I slow down when I'm with
my kids I really see the incredible
beauty and mystery of of a five
5-year-old and a three-year-old um and
when I slow down you know um when I'm at
a dinner party with friends I really get
to feel and experience what someone's
going through positive or negatively and
it's just so easy to our brains are so
good at at thinking they know what the
next thing is that we can move so
quickly through life and through
decisions and and whatnot and so I think
having Clarity um is one of the real
Keys is just to do whatever practice it
is but to slow down long enough to
really think about it one of the things
that I
think um seems to be a huge priority for
you or or a strong value is surrounding
yourself with high vibration people
right like if you if you canvas your
life and I did a deep dive like you
always make a point to make sure that
you're you know um dropping in on
interesting communities you know I know
you're part of the Summit Community
right like just you know where can I
find really interesting people who will
push me and broaden my worldview and
expand my aperture so I can remove those
blind spots or solicit the support or be
a support system to other people so I
think it would be interesting to talk a
little bit about the importance of of
community and finding the right
community that supports you and that you
can support well and and I think it's
also so one of the things that seeking
out different communities that are
different than you you know and really
trying to I mean that's you brought up
Summit I think one of the things that I
like about Summit or a Ted conference or
Ted videos or what not is like there's
people that have total different
backgrounds total different educational
experiences total different motivations
in life uh that I can that I can be
inspired by and learned from um and so
you know I think that's one of the
hardest things about this this time in
our history of Co is it's been really
hard to Foster that and most of it has
been through you know zoom and and and
being very intentional about trying to
connect with people um and and keep
Community um but but for
me going back to realizing that life's
joy and satisfaction does not come from
external accomplishments
where I landed is I need to develop the
tools and habits to regulate what's
going in internally and so that led to
made for but also what I learned is and
I already had experiences but I think I
even it ratcheted even higher on the
level of importance is it's all about
the relationships that you have and you
know I think people who are most
fulfilled on their deathbed or those who
really invested time in really not lot
you don't have to have lots of friends
um but really deep relationships and so
you know one of the connections that you
know LED Pat and I together um and
continues to benefit both of us deeply
is we have a group of guys that have
been getting together now for 14 years
uh once a year sometimes twice a year um
from from our different parts of our
lives but we all feel kind of share in
the same values and we also love to do
some of the same activ ities mainly
surfing and and this group of guys are
all doing different things all live in
different parts of the country all you
know some varying of Ages you know um
some kids have already gone to college
and are long gone and some are having
babies next month you know in four
months because Pat's having another baby
um and uh and so for me that has been
one of the most beneficial things in my
life to have a group of of and
especially as a as a man uh cuz I think
it's even less regular for men vers
women in this case to have a community
or group of people that you can kind of
bring anything to and that will always
kind of speak their truth to you with
anything that's going on in your life
and and so while I have been very
fortunate to be part of amazing
communities like Summit Series or Ted
Community or these kind of more public
facing communities I think the thing
that I benefited the most from in my
life has been intimate friendships and
this one group of guys that I'm so close
with that's interesting yeah it has been
it has been hard in this time right now
to stay connected to those relationships
and you know I miss it you know I'm I'm
a you know I'm a much more introverted
person than you but I've noticed like
how much I'm thirsting and hungry for
being just with other people yeah like
this is like my this is like my social
outlet you know what I mean no when I
heard that we're GNA do in person I was
so excited because I've done so many
Zoom calls with friends with made for
members I mean like and it's great I
mean I'm that's if there's anything I
have really taken away from this in
terms of is that if you if you bring the
highest level of intention to a video
call you can really connect yeah like I
mean it's you can it's not all the um
physiological things you get from being
in person aren't happening but it's a
lot I think it's a lot more effective
than we thought before Co like I kind of
dismissed video calls like I'll just
call you on the phone but now like if I
have a friend and haven't seen him in a
while I'm like we're FaceTiming because
looking in your eyes and and and seeing
you in real time it does make a
difference yeah when you look
out uh at the landscape right now you
know I think this relates to what you're
doing with mid4 there's a lot of
acrimony there's a lot of division
there's a lot of you know heated debate
to say the least at the moment people
are suffering there are lots of people
who are um feeling overlooked
disenfranchised and this gets translated
into a level of vitriol that I don't
remember in in my lifetime so how do you
think about you know our current
cultural moment and how that relates to
your relationship with self-improvement
and you know mental emotional and
spiritual well-being you know one of the
things that I really hoped was going to
come out of the co experience and I'm
not not uh as satisfied with what I've
seen as what I hoped but I I think
there's still um directionally where we
have to go as a human society is is um
is that there's so much more that is in
common with us that's really than what
divides us like if you really just if
you just did a piece of paper and you
said I mean in any of these issues uh or
any of these situations like we
are all as vulnerable as much more
vulnerable than we realize when we see
something like covid and it affects the
person in the high-rise in Manhattan as
much as someone in the Township in South
Africa
and I think there's been a lot of great
rhetoric over the years and musicians
and and great writing about really are
all one but I really think the
um the movement that really has to
happen is for us to really spend more
time looking at the similarities and the
beauty of those similarities and I
definitely feel like that is been cor
been connected to my mental health
journey and realizing I'm not so special
after all like this is not this is not
um I'm not the only person that's
experienced this there are actually
millions of per people that are feeling
this way or having trouble in this
regard and
my desire now is to is to help them and
and because that's just kind of what I
like to do but I think where we are
right now the the anything that can help
people see the similarities and the
connections over the differences and the
divisions is something that we have to
move towards and I don't have the answer
prescription but that's just like in my
gut it just like when I look around and
I slow down really when I slow down I
really look at the the specifics of what
is happening I'm like we're just we're
losing the narrative because we're so
focused on the negative or the division
or the differences when there's so many
positives and similarities there and and
I I wish I had a better answer to how we
get there but I feel like that's where
we have to go it's certainly the only
way forward but how to get there is is
really a tricky problem to solve I mean
you would think that when Co was visited
upon us as a collective that that would
be a unifying event that's what I
thought and what we saw was exactly the
opposite and that's dispiriting you know
it's it's a bummer that something that
we could have rallied behind and and and
come together around has really created
an even deeper divide and it's easy to
um lose hope about the future as we see
that um that Gap continue to expand uh
and I think it's being exacerbated by
these digital tools that have been
weaponized to P pit each other against
each other it's like I don't have in my
daily life I'm not having strife and
conflict like I see on social media so I
know in my heart that we do have you
know this great
shared um you know unifying you know
threads and themes and things that we
care about with our fellow human beings
but that's not what we see when we look
at our screens every day
the impact of that I think is not to be
um overstated at this point and figuring
out how to you know Rectify that is well
small problem you use the word
weaponized and I think that is a very
fair um description of how these um how
how this how these apps and and sites
and targeting and all the stuff that I
don't understand exactly how they do it
but I know the effects of what's
Happening happening and it has pitted
people against each other in ways that I
don't think they ever would have been in
without these these tools and so I think
one of the things that's important is
for people to try to develop some real
um uh you know just awareness around
how these things that seemingly seem
innocent are affecting us in such a
powerful way yeah and to be more aware
and mindful of just powerful they are
and to the to the neuroplasticity point
the extent to which they really are
manipulating our emotional state and and
I think that requires appreciating just
how easily manipulated we are like we we
don't like to believe that we are but we
clearly are and we're seeing that
getting played out right now yeah um I
want to talk a little bit about uh this
I don't know what you would call it it's
not really a blog like this next steps
thing that post you published recently
because I think there's you know a lot
of people watching and listening who who
um you know aspire to make their imprint
in the world and want to do something
interesting that has that has meaning
but they're you know much further uh
earlier along the path than you and you
kind of created this multiple I don't
know what it would what you would call
it a series like a written series funny
we trying
to yeah it's like it's not um enough
content to be called a Digital Book and
we realized that you know um we wanted I
wanted to share just basically the
lessons that I learned over the last you
know 10 years of TOMS and in the last
two years of building made for with
entrepreneurs and people who want to
make a difference in the world and I was
trying to think of a a a medium that I
really enjoy and I love I do love to
write and I wrote a book in 2010 and
that was a great experience but I didn't
want to go through the whole process of
writing a book again CU it took two
years of my life and I just didn't have
that energy right then and I also feel
that you know everyone is consuming
everything digitally so so yeah so it's
kind of like a it's like a it's like a
mini book or digital series of lessons
that has you know pictures and videos
and anecdotes from U my life experiences
through Toms and and then most recently
made for and uh it was really fun like I
think that like in one of the things
that I try to characterize most of my
work projects around now is is it fun
and it was fun to kind of go back over
memory lane and to really kind of sit
with okay how did I actually start like
doing that in you know why was that so
effective with Toms and how could
someone who's starting a business out of
their garage today or wants to create a
new new nonprofit like how can they
benefit from the lessons that I learned
and so I wrote this you know series of
uh lessons I call next steps and it was
really about looking over the past 15
years to kind of
in some ways for myself to think about
like okay what do I want to bring into
the future and uh it's been really fun
because it's been I I I published it
about a week or two ago and and I've
gotten so many great interactions and
conversations with people online because
of it yeah so it's sort of you know
basically guideposts right like go with
your go with your gut like this is how
you trust your intuition why giving is
good like they're basically principle
based yeah totally based on principles
through a lot of funny stories that
happened through the early days of TOMS
and and most recently being an
entrepreneur again with with made four
what's your relationship with Tom's now
so it's it's such a I I describe it this
way is I feel like toms is
um my child that's in college and I say
that because um you know whenever I uh
you know call and have a great
conversation with the CEO at Tom's or
someone at Tom's like they're always
seem to be really happy to hear from me
and we have a great conversation but I
don't show up in the dorm
room you know I'm not just showing up as
a proud dad and you know is your laundry
clean do you need your laundry picked up
and done exactly so I'm there I always
am happy when they give me a call uh and
I'm more than happy to give you know um
my perspective on something that they're
making decision on but I'm definitely
not showing up in the dorm room and then
also it's kind of like in college they
have parents weekend right and so you
once on once time a year parents come
out and they get to experience
everything that's kind of the same thing
like they put a dog and pony show on
Blake's coming yeah and so let's see
what's what's happening but you know
it's Tom's like many businesses and in
you know in retail and the consumer
space have been hit hard by covid um you
know there's some things that have been
real blessings I mean the online
businesses continue to grow dramatically
um but um but I think there's a you know
it's a long road ahead as we see all
retail try figure out what the future
looks like how many retail outlets are
there now I mean you know in terms of
the I mean I think at one point you know
in terms of number of outlets that we
sold it was like 8,000 or 10,000 um you
know we never really got deep into our
own retail I think we had 15 stores when
I stopped being involved um but mainly
it's through you know your wholesale
Partners who have their own challenges
you know you know like a Nordstroms or
whatnot um and uh and and you know we
always had a strong online business
because the business was really started
you know in my garage and selling online
but that has even become more important
because so many people are shopping at
home now so to date how many shoes have
been donated so we almost at I mean
we're so close I mean it's like 98 or 99
million right um so we're really close
to that 100 million Mark and I think
that's when they'll probably bring you
back for the celebration right that's
crazy wow and also then you got into uh
prescription eyewear there's all these
other kind of giving arms to Toms these
days that have broadened that which
which has been really I mean I think as
an entrepreneur those are my greatest
memories of my you know Tom's you know
Journey it was not just in the shoes
that we gave but then being like Oh we
can you know help people get cataract
surgeries you know and in 15 minutes
take someone who's blind and within 48
hours given their sight back through a
surgery that we can pay for by selling a
pair of sunglasses on Abby Kenny you
know so um I think the thing I'm most
proud of within the walls of Tom's but
then even with Tom's influence on other
businesses has been just that how so
many entrepreneurs and businesses see
that you can be a profitable business
but also have a really meaningful impact
on the world yeah I mean that's the real
Legacy of this whole thing like not only
did you Pioneer this like one for one
model it really reconfigured the
capitalistic landscape totally to
establish and demonstrate that you can
create a very um profitable company at
scale and still make the giving
component of it very very real and
meaningful not just meaning not that you
know it's it's so heavily integrated
that they're not separate at all and
that really that the Ripple effect of
that I mean you just see it everywhere
you look now well I think what's
happened is is the society is and
consumers have changed their
expectations of businesses so before and
it's you know it's not just Toms there's
been a lot of amazing companies that
have you know kind of been birthed
around the same time or shortly
thereafter that have really helped
change what the customer expects from a
company and so ultimately a company's
going to behave in the way that gets
more customers yeah so it's just the
economic law there and so what used to
be okay and that was companies you know
having a CSR department and writing a
check to a nonprofit that was really
meaning you know in terms of the scale
of their business was you know
inconsequential but looked good in a
photograph in their annual report to now
customers want to really know you know
how is this being sourced you know you
know what are your labor practices what
are you doing with your profits what
percentage of my purchase is actually
going to do something besides just go to
the bottom line like the the the
customers become um much more demanding
yeah and and I think that's good for
society the expectation of
transparency and and and the expectation
that there is something more meaningful
than just the balance sheet the p&l
statement of this company but you know
does is there a warie Parker without a
Toms like you did set in MO I mean you
weren't the first to do this but you
were the first to do it at such a
massive scale right and that's made a
huge impact and I look at um I look at
that impact in the same way that I look
at what Scott Harrison did in the
inverse situation of creating a giving
model that be that was like an
aspirational brand like bringing the
best of what you know a capitalist
culture could could offer the nonprofit
sector and merging those worlds and and
what he's been able to create and the
the legacy of that on just the giving
ecosystem at large oh yeah I mean it's
changed the way that that Charities
operate the way they communic unicate
the way they Market um in such a
profound way and it's been such a joy
I've been part of Charity water since
day one Scott's one of my great it's the
greatest it's it's super cool but when
you look now there's also like the kind
of dark underbelly of all of this is the
is the green washing that you see also
where there's a lot of lip service to
this that isn't meaningful or
substantial in any way and it's very
easy for a company to say we give away
1% or we do this and they're really
doing it from uh you know a marketing a
positioning and marketing yeah decision
and not really you know part of the
ethos of of or the mission of the
company yeah that's the thing when I
speak at universities or lecture at
different things I always say is like
you know I think the customer um demands
transparency and authenticity and you're
better off to have no giving program and
just be we sell this we make money we
have a great product if you like our
product buy it verse trying to Spring
wrinkle on some type of Feelgood message
on because I think people just see
through that and I think it backfires um
and I think that's been one of the
harder Parts about having this Legacy is
I have seen so many things that I've
just cringed at especially more with
bigger businesses that have tried to you
know add this on because someone in
marketing read a case study about Toms
in a business school um and so you know
but what I always say is as long as the
collect
direction is to a higher Consciousness
in how we operate our businesses then I
feel that um what we started in motion
you know 14 years ago now is going to
continue to have positive effects like
it it has to be directionally going that
way and um and I think that really goes
back to like you know how conscious are
we being as consumers and as
entrepreneurs or people who work at
companies well there's a strain of
economic economics oriented people who
who cast dispers on the conscious
capitalism model like it's it's
lip service but I don't believe that to
be true like I think you know what
you've created and there's other
examples out there establish not only
its viability but it's almost D rur if
you want to be competitive in today's
world I I I think so I mean John Mackey
the founder of Whole Foods you know
friend he's been on the show yeah I've
did his conference so I've met all the
I've met a lot of these people that are
that are doing this I think he through
his books and he just came out with a
new one um you know proved that this is
good business and I think that's what's
so important is and I think that's why
we've seen a shift and why more and more
companies have have adopted this way of
thinking is you know there are a lot of
stakeholders that you need to pay
attention to um in order to you know
maximize your profits and it's not just
the investor or the financier it's the
employees it's you know who helps make
these products like everyone has to be
healthy for the business to be healthy
right knowing everything that you know
now and all these experiences that
you've had what is the advice that you
would give to the young upstart Blake
who's you know hustling Billboards in
Nashville or starting his laundry
business wow I uh I mean you've done
pretty good was there anything you
changed or where where did you see
yourself going astray maybe on the
external validation piece well yeah this
is where it's interesting it's going to
all come back to
uh the inner Journey that I've been on
uh that we've spoken about throughout
the show here and that
is
um through a plant medicine journey I
had through some um work at Hoffman I
have a consistent theme that has that
has um been revealed to me and if I
could have re and if I could have
understood this at the earlier age I
think um I just would I would have I
would have struggled less internally and
that is
um I'm good enough you know I'm fine I
don't I don't need to be any more
perfect I I uh everything that I have
done and that I do um is my best effort
and if my best effort is is enough and I
think a lot of people um have this inner
critic and it can be a great you know
driver for success and and
accomplishment but it also you know
comes with a lot of collateral damage
and I think I've carried around a lot of
stress and a lot of weight uh internally
and I've uh enjoyed things probably far
less than I could have if I just would
have known that no matter what I do it's
exactly what I'm destined to do and it's
good
enough isn't there that fear though that
if you felt like you were good enough
enough when you were young that you
never would have done the things that
you did I don't know I mean that's
definitely um a fair uh assessment of
that and I definitely there were some
times and through this inner work that
I've done where I'm like well if I
hadn't have been like so competitive and
I haven't been then I wouldn't have had
this drive um but it all comes you know
it all comes with a price and I I
wouldn't change the way my life has
unfolded for one minute nor can I um but
I do
feel that um there is a
peace and a calmness that I have today
that I wish I would have had earlier in
my
life that's a good place to end it great
um so much respect for for everything
that you've built and the service to the
world but I think more than that just uh
respect and appreciation for the person
that you are like you carry yourself
with a great deal of of presence and
Equanimity and it's a tribute to all the
work that you've done like I can feel it
sitting across from you like you're
you're here you're who you are you feel
like integrated you're authentically
yourself and that's a reflection of all
of these things that you that you've
done an attribute to um to that work and
I think ultimately it's only going to
benefit everything that you put your
energy into thank you yeah I appreciate
it man that's been great um madefor
get.com is the website right that's
correct get.com and you're easy to find
on the internet just at Blake mosy if
people want to find the um the kind of
mini book series thing is that that's on
your website yeah it's on Blake mos.com
cool yeah right on man cool all right
thanks dude let's do this again sometime
okay right on I want to interview you
next time anytime dude blance
[Music]