Our next guest is on a mission to help
us all realize that we are enough.
Capital letters. Blake Macowski is an
entrepreneur, a founder of the popular
shoe brand Toms. After selling the
company back in 2019, Macowski fell into
a deep depression, he says, and then he
set out on a healing journey that led to
his next venture. And that's what we're
here to talk about today. He's launching
enough bracelets designed to serve as a
reminder that we are all enough. 100%. I
want to say that again. 100% of the
profits from this bracelet will go to
mental health organization. We're very
glad to say that Blake Macowski joins us
live and in color in the studio. It's so
good to see you again because I remember
you back in the day,
>> man. It's been I think a decade since
I've been here, but I'm so glad to be
back.
>> I know. So, let's think about this.
2019, you sell the company. It had to be
financially lucrative. Tom's is still
doing well. It was under a couple
Christmas trees at my house. So, the
brand was still the legacy that you set
for us still continues. So, you sell the
company, you think financially
lucrative, you must be on a high, but
that's not what you were feeling. What
was happening? What was going on?
>> I think what happened is I sold the
company, I accomplished everything I was
told I was supposed to do. You know, I
built a business. I helped all these
children get shoes. And um when I sold
it, I thought I'd feel great. And
actually, I started to get depressed. I
lost my purpose. I lost my community.
And I realized that nothing I could do
externally would would help me with this
wound I had inside. And that was I just
never felt that I was enough.
>> Yeah. But you were the guy, Blake, the
one of the reasons why the company was
so successful. I remember you buy one
and then you'd give one away. Sure. So
you were considered one of the good guys
in the business community.
>> So what did you try to do to get better?
>> I mean, I did everything. I mean, I went
on retreats. I meditated. I did therapy.
I went to a hospital to have my brain
zapped. I mean I mean it did everything
because I got so depressed that I didn't
even want to be here anymore. It's
really scary.
>> And I'd never you thought about taking
your own life?
>> I did. I actually had a plan and thank
God I got help and that's what I would
say to anyone is like if you are in that
state just reach out to someone. Um but
the thing that helped the most is I
really did some work around this core
wound of not feeling enough. And I
realized that it had been with me all
the time. And so I started meditating
and doing a daily mantra of I am enough.
I've always been enough. And ultimately,
I created this bracelet um as a reminder
to wear every day for myself, but also
to give to other people because I find
that when I give the bracelet to someone
and I look them in the eye and there's a
little poem that goes with it, I say,
"You are enough. Yes, Gail, I see you.
The you behind the you, not for anything
you've done, but anything you're going
to do." Like, that's what it's about.
And so as I started saying that to
myself, I realized that my next mission,
maybe the whole reason I went through
the depression at all
>> was so that I could then help others who
might be feeling the same way.
>> Help people understand like that
somebody could accomplish all that you
have done and still not feel good about
themselves.
>> It stems from something.
>> I think that that's it's it's cultural.
I think we're told so much of our
self-worth is tied to our
accomplishments. Yes. And so the I think
the reason I did did get suicidal was I
achieved everything that I wanted and I
didn't feel any better because I was so
focused externally. And so that's what
I'm really trying especially with young
people is trying like high school. I
went to back to my high school spoke in
my high school the other day and I was
like you can it's great to achieve
things but if you tie your self worth to
achievement you're you're always going
to fall short.
>> But what I like is that you buy the $58
>> you buy one and then you say give one to
someone else.
>> Yes. So that's one of the things I love
is that, you know, Tom's was about one
for one. You buy one, we give one. This
is one for you, one to give. And I think
when you rare the bracelet, it's a great
reminder for yourself, but then you get
to give it to someone and then you
create a bond with that person. So when
you're having a hard day or you're
feeling lonely, then you know someone
else has that bracelet and you're
wearing it together in unity.
>> Life's always better when shared. I'm so
glad to see you. You're doing great. Got
a great girlfriend, too, Leakowski.
Thank you. Thank you so much.