Yeah, I always say like more connection,
less performance. In business, I always
say go for meaning instead of marketing.
I really think that businesses that
focus on marketing usually don't really
break through. Businesses that focus on
meaning
>> are the ones that change the world.
We're just trying to create more meaning
in people's lives. And if we do that,
people will buy it or whatever we're
doing.
>> Yeah.
>> Part of being a creator is like how do
you market your story in some ways? and
how do you connect with people in an
authentic way? And so I think it's to
remind people that, you know, really
like try to kind of bring it back to
like what's the most meaningful to you
because if you're really focusing on
what you really care about, then the
right people will probably care about
that as well. But if you're trying to
like predict what other people care
about,
>> that's when you get yourself into
trouble.
We live in a complex and everchanging
world, a place that is maybe harder than
ever to [music] successfully navigate.
The answer is surely to be brave, but
it's also to seek and be open to
guidance. Mentors are the one consistent
throughine in the lives of all
accomplished people, myself included.
So, welcome to Mentor Buffet, a feast
for those like me curious about who
helped the most successful among us
succeed.
Blake Mikoski is the founder of Tom
Shoes. This episode is so full of advice
from his dad, from Sarah Blakeley, the
founder of Spanx, from his therapist,
Dr. Dan, and more. We talk about what it
means to live a meaningful life and what
purpose-driven business has looked like
for him. Blake shares what it means for
him to be enough and what his healing
journey has looked like since he's come
out of the lows of depression. He's so
honest. There's something here for you.
Here's my conversation with Blake
Mikoski.
[music]
>> It was actually the first time I ever
interviewed someone.
>> You know, I've been interviewed a bunch
with Tom Shoes and I was asked to
interview Ted Turner at the United
Nations and Ted Turner was the founder
of the CNN. Um he's the youngest person
to ever start a cable television network
and the first news network
>> and you know billionaire very successful
won the America's Cupman sailing like
very accomplished big big personality
was m married to Jane Fonda and several
other people and so anyway so Ted Turner
I'm getting ready to go on stage and he
looks at me he goes Blake I can tell
that you're going to climb the mountain
I was like okay and like Tom's was
starting to take off so people knew
about Tom's and he said you're going to
climb the mountain and at the top of the
mountain there's a chest and it's really
beautiful and you're going to climb that
mountain. You're going to get to the top
of the mountain. You're going to look in
the chest and you're going to see that
the chest is empty.
I've done it. I've climbed the mountain.
The chest is empty. And even though that
I just told you what you're going to
find, you still need to go climb the
mountain yourself.
>> And then we walked on stage and it was
like the whole interview I was like
thinking about the mountain, the chest.
And I think in some ways that was quite
prophetic because that's what happened
in my life with, you know, building
Tom's. You know, I started Tom Shoes in
and in eight years we were the fastest
growing shoe company in the world. We
built it to almost a billion dollars in
revenue. We gave a hundred million
children shoes. And when I sold the
company, I thought I was going to be
happy. And
the exact opposite happened. like that's
when I started to get depressed for the
first time. That's when I started to
isolate. And so that little tidbit he
told me. Um even though he told me that,
I still had to learn that lesson.
>> It's so interesting having like a
foreshadowed
wisdom in your head and still
understanding you have to live it
yourself. And also probably quite
valuable when you get there and have
that moment to know that you weren't the
only one. Yeah.
>> Right. Olympians feel the same thing.
>> And until recently, no one prepared you
for it. Right. And so you got there and
you were like,
>> you know, you assumed you were the only
one experiencing this odd dip. Yes.
>> Right. And now I think that people know
about these things. Even though it's
hard to go through these things, at
least you're not alone. And going back
to that moment that you got that wisdom
right before going on stage, can we just
talk for a second about what it what
it's like in the in the world to receive
wisdom that you know you have to
experience for yourself? Because people
you hear it all the time like you
graduate college or you finish college
sports and everyone's like it's going to
be a transition or like you're going to
go through struggle or you're or you're
going to have a breakup and and yet you
still have to live it. And so I just
wanted to like zoom out and talk a
little bit about what it feels like to
get a piece of wisdom that you, you
know, may inevitably be true for you,
but you still are going to keep living
the journey with that in mind.
>> I think it's like say when the student
is ready, the teacher shows up,
>> right?
>> And I think that sometimes
you're just not ready for the wisdom.
And so it might go in the back of your
head and maybe someday well it kind of
at one point I remembered that you know
it wasn't like I was thinking about that
for 15 years but then when I realized
like oh man like I did climb the
mountain it was empty and yet I still um
put too much hope in that it wasn't
going to be empty you know and so so
sometimes I think it's like you just
it's good to pick up these pieces of
wisdom along the way and sometimes
you're ready for them and sometimes
you're just not. Well, also, isn't it
true that the wisdom was not meant to be
a red light?
>> No. No. If anything, he did it with a
smirk like like like enjoy the ride,
Blake. Like, I have this tattoo right
here. It says, "Enjoy the ride." And uh
I have a bunch of tattoos with little
sayings on them.
>> But yeah, it's like like that's just
part of the human journey. Like I
actually think about like the depression
that I went through, which was about
seven years long, which is a very long
time. I mean, I'm 49 now. So,
>> and only two years of it was, you know,
dangerous. Um, so five years kind of
mild depression and then it got so bad
that I almost took my life. Like it was
really intense. And and I think about
that now. Um, I look back on it and I'm
thankful for it in a weird way.
>> Like I'm actually like, oh wow, like
that had to happen. It almost is like an
answer to prayer of like, you know, if I
wanted to be able to have another sense
of purpose in my life and I wanted to
heal the things that would really give
me actual peace, not fabricated peace
through external, you know, validation
and whatnot. You know, I actually had to
go through that. I hope I never go
through it again. And God, if you're
listening, I don't want to go through it
again. I learned the lesson hopefully.
But but sometimes like with these ideas,
these lessons that we're looking for is
is you know, they're not always easy.
like sometimes they're really [\h__\h]
hard and that's because they're meant to
do that to drive you to go inward to
find, you know, the answers and the
thing that you need to learn.
>> And so, you know, I'm sure that there's
a lot of mentors that you've had and I
know there's some that I'm thinking of
that I've had that, you know, aren't
necessarily like, you know, hugs and
cuddles.
>> Yeah. And they're not preventing you
from falling down either.
>> Yeah. And you were saying these are
things I had to learn. And it's it
really puts an underline on the word
learn of like learn actually doesn't
just mean someone tells you a piece of
information and then you know it. Like
that can happen with facts. Yeah.
>> But it seems like this kind of learning
is is growth, right? And it's true
confidence and knowing how to navigate
or how to see your orientation with
yourself and with the world. And it
seems like no one could have told you
what to do about the empty chest. Just
that you will get there and then you
will have to find your way with support
and love of course. But it's really that
you don't want to avoid the journey
because the the journey is the um is the
growth that makes your human experience.
And it it's encouraging because it's
saying like we don't want to avoid these
hard moments. We just want to be not
alone when we get there.
>> Yes.
>> And so tell me I mean that's a long time
to be like my post Olympic depression
was not as long as yours.
>> That's a long time to wrestle with
something that difficult.
>> Yeah. I mean you know thankfully it
wasn't persistent all year. Usually it I
would have these depressive episodes in
holiday time, you know. So like um and I
was also living in Jackson Hole because
I had a dream of being snowboarding
every day. So when I sold my company, I
moved to Jackson
>> and I and it gets cold and and in dark
early in Jackson. So I had like that the
isolation. And so really I was
experiencing it pretty much every winter
for about five years. And then
>> you know I think the the my soul said
no, we got to turn up the volume here.
You're not you haven't learned the
lesson yet. And so then it got and then
it got really really hard. And it brings
me back to like one of the things that
you know in terms of advice, right? In
terms of like what are some of the I was
thinking about the moments before coming
on the show that really like okay that
changed my life that conversation,
right?
>> And I had a conversation with my dad
>> and it actually came from I was on the
I'll back up for a second. So, I was
flying home for Thanksgiving and I was
reading Esquire magazine and on the back
of Esquire magazine, they used to have
this thing where they'd have a celebrity
and they'd ask him like popcorn
questions, like 20 questions d and then
one of them was always like the best
advice you've ever had. Mhm.
>> And so I don't know who it was, but it
was a male actor and he said, "The best
advice I ever got was don't wait until
your parents are really old to interview
them about their life." Because if you
do it early in life, you can learn from
their mistakes and the things and then
you can apply them to your life. So you
have the wisdom of your mom or dad
before you can act when you can actually
do something about it.
>> So I was like 32. Tom's was really
starting to take off and you know I
don't know how old my dad was then but
you know he's probably 50some and um all
the kids are out of the house and so I
said dad I want to interview you know my
dad and I have a great great
relationship but you know at that point
I don't think we were as vulnerable as
we are now
>> and um and so after Thanksgiving we went
down to this little pool house and I
said dad and I interviewed him with
everything about his life and it was so
fun and he was open and it was great all
these things beautiful at the end of the
interview I said, "Okay, last question."
I said, "Do you have any regrets?" Now,
my dad was a orthopedic surgeon. You
know, he's been married to my mom now
for 57 years, like three amazing kids.
Like, he's lived a really great life at
the and at that time he was, you know,
seemed very happy. And he paused. He
looked at me, he goes, "I have one
regret." And I was like, "Oh gosh, what
is this?" And he was quite serious. And
he said, you know, when I was in high
school and college and then medical
school, I had a lot of guy friends and
we did trips and played golf and all
these things. And then, you know, after
residency, I started my practice, got
married to your mom, had you. And for
the last, you know, 20 plus years, my
whole life has been my work and my
family. And I'm really proud of my work
and my family,
>> but I've lost touch with all my guy
friends, or most of them. And now you
guys are out of the house and I'm
getting closer to retirement and I don't
get invited on the golf trips. I don't
get the opportunity to, you know, hang
out with guys the way I see other male
friends of mine.
>> And [clears throat] I'm lonely and it
scares me. And I was like, "Wow." And I
could see my dad like the pain of this
to share this. And so the next day I got
on the plane, fly home, and I emailed my
nine best guy friends.
>> Wow. And I shared the story with him and
I said, "Guys, we cannot let this happen
to us." Like, we're all starting off in
our careers in different places. And I
said, "Every year we're going to go on
an adventure together." And um I'm going
to propose the first one is my parents
have a condo in Colorado. Let's go on a
fly fishing trip camping and we can
spend a couple days at their condo. And
so the nine guys came and then the next
year was let's all go down to Bise and
fish there. Fishing was a big thing at
first and then it became surfing and
that was we've been doing it now for 19
years. It's called it has a name. It's
called the Rugged Adventure Club. Um
there's 14 members. So and we text every
day. So beyond the one trip a year, we
literally like that is our social media.
We texting everything from advice about
parenting to advice in relationships to
one of my parents is getting old my you
know like we are there for each other
like nothing else
>> and literally that in piece of advice
from my dad and that investment in this
in these trips every single year no
matter what we do not miss it. It saved
my life. It really did. When I was
suicidal when I was not able to think
straight they would just show up at my
house in Marin. They helped me get to a
treatment facility to get off all the
pharmaceuticals I was on. They helped me
rethink, you know, different personal
decisions in my life that I need to
change to feel better. And um and yeah,
and so for anyone, you know, listening
that that might relate to, like
investing in friendships, like real
friendships, like the kind that you can
is like the best investment you can
make. uh especially for men, I think,
you know, and the time to do it is in
your 20s and in your early 30s because
you're you might don't think you need it
then, but you're going to need it when
you turn 40 and you're going to need it
when you turn 50. And so, invest in them
now.
>> Yeah. And it's such a unique um type of
not loneliness that's different from
what family gives you, that's different
from what your relationship or some
other type of um work partnership might
give you, right? It's like a very
special kind of support.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like chosen. It's nurtured. It
doesn't need anything from you,
>> right?
>> Yeah. I mean, that's one of the things
that especially after you have success
and financial success, you kind of a lot
of your
>> new people come into your life and you
don't really know like what do they need
from me, what do they want? These guys
have been with me for 20 years, you
know, and it's that's why I say it's
like in your 20s, you know, I did that
when I was like 31. like that that's the
time to really like
>> make this a priority because if you
don't do it then you're sure not going
to do it when you're older. And that's I
think that's what my dad was saying.
It's like if I just had prioritized
this, I mean, going on one trip a year
and texting is not that big of a
commitment, but it has made such a
difference in all of our lives because
over years it's just gotten more and
more deep and more and more meaningful.
And so, um, yeah, so I think that's, you
know, my dad is definitely a mentor to
me on many ways, but that conversation
was the one that I will always remember.
>> That's beautiful.
>> That's really, really beautiful. And I
think especially during those 20s and
30s, it can be really hard to like both
avoid and the energy of and also avoid
the temptation of everything being
transactional because you're in such a
building time of your life.
>> Sure.
>> That a lot of the focus is on like
climbing and building and developing.
And so just having a a
goalless commitment to people, you know,
and like a abundant feeling must be so
powerful, especially when you're so
ambitious.
>> Yes. That kind of segus into another
piece of advice. On my healing journey,
I went to India
>> and I worked um specifically uh with
this great teacher Krishna G. and
Christian G um you know one of the
things he says is that the cause of all
suffering is obsessive selfentric
thinking and I'll say it again the cause
of all suffering is obsessive
self-centric thinking now that's not
selfishness and that's not narcissism
that's what people think initially it's
actually more nuanced than that and this
is where it comes up when you're talking
about this building mode is that
>> and I I'll use the f I'll use the frame
of when I was depressed and I think a
lot of people if you're depressed or
anxious or you're not feeling good, then
what happens is you don't want to feel
that way, right? And so what you do is
you start thinking all day every day
about feeling better. So you're only
thinking about yourself. You're only
thinking like what can I do to not be
depressed? What can I do for my
self-care? This, this, this, right? And
what he believes and they teach is that
you know when you're constantly
constantly thinking of yourself your
field of awareness is so narrowed
>> and um and so much of the beauty of the
moment is in being in thinking about
others. And so that was a big thing for
me is when I heard that I was like okay
I've spent so much time because I was in
pain thinking about how do I get out of
this pain?
>> Yeah. But if I just start thinking about
how I can serve others and how I can be
a better friend, how can I help one of
my other friends with their businesses,
how I can, you know, launch my podcast
to help other people with their
suffering. Like these were the things
and and that had a huge impact on my
healing journey as well.
>> Yeah. Because it's connectedness, right?
And it's purpose and meaning outside of
yourself. And sometimes the yourself is
lying and is ill too, right? like your
brain like when you're in the state that
you were in that I was in, it's not
well, right? And so it's not even
>> it feels like it's almost like a a a
puddle that you come across on a
sidewalk that like doesn't get fresh
water and it's like it rots by itself,
right? And
>> I remember Dr. Arpea during my healing
similarly I didn't understand cuz I was
like I'm so unwell and he was like we
need to like try to get you to keep
doing these like as much as you can like
speaking to children like doing these
appearances when you can or thinking
about your family and it really was
perplexing to me at the time because I
was like I'm not able to be there for
anyone else and he kept pushing me to
have that contact and I think it was
about staying connected to Like
obviously living for something greater
than yourself for one thing cuz when it
gets really dark
>> sometimes you will not do it for
yourself. Yeah.
>> Right. Like you will only do it for your
your dad or your you know or your kids
I'm sure. And
>> so I think that is really powerful and
it's really not something that we might
mandate for ourselves so easily because
you don't think that that's what is
going to help you.
>> Yeah. I guess thank God to those mentors
that pushed us toward that and knew that
it wasn't just a virtue. It was actually
a path.
>> Yeah. You know,
>> yeah, it's not that's a great point
because we always think about service
and helping others is like a virtuous
thing, right?
>> But actually it is in service of
yourself.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And there's nothing wrong
with that. Like I mean I even saw that
with Tom's shoes like I mean we gave 100
million children shoes all over the
world. Like everyone celebrated like
what we were doing
>> but I was always the first one to say
but like we get more than we give in
some ways. Like we get so much joy by
going on these trips. We get so much
feeling of connection with these
communities that we're in. And so, so
service really is something and it, you
know, it's and it and and it really
grounds you in that connection which is
so important for our mental and, you
know, well-being.
>> Mhm. Yeah. Cuz you're not you're not on
your own little ladder. You're like
literally have no choice. You're almost
like stuck with other people,
>> which can feel good. Like you're like,
well, I got no choice but to be I don't
know. I think about like a field trip or
something where it's like, well, I'm
connected to these other people. Like,
I'm just in this group.
>> Today, I want to share with you about my
new favorite Merryill shoe, the Hutmach
2 Slide Cozy, which are my go-to for
fall and winter. I love these shoes
especially for walking my dog, Bernini,
because they're [music] warm, they have
grip on the bottom, and I can slide into
them really quickly and then run out the
door as I chase her down the street,
which often happens. They're warm and
you can wear them with socks, but you
don't have to because they have cozy
inside them. [music] And my favorite
thing to wear them with are sweatpants.
These shoes are also good for the
grocery store, getting your mail, and
even wearing inside sometimes. I
recommend getting a pair for your
partner, though, because they're
probably [music] going to steal yours.
For over 40 years, Merryill has been a
global leader in hike. For a limited
time, we're partnering with Merryill to
give you an exclusive offer of 25% off
your first purchase using code
mentorbuffet25 when you check out on
mel.com.
>> A big part of my healing came from I had
this great therapist, kind of a similar
story to you, you know, and I was
reading your book and you're talking
about going through all these different
therapist and nothing was working and
then you found Dr. Arpea.
>> Yeah.
>> And I had a similar thing. I went
through countless therapists places and
then I found this guy, Dr. Dan. And one
of the things that Dr. Dan, you know,
really saw in me, which, you know, no
one else had really seen and helped me
see was that under the depression, under
the anxiety was this core wound. And I
didn't even know what a core wound was.
And he explained that, you know, my core
wound and that I and he helped me
realize this. It wasn't him telling me.
It actually came out in my own voice in
a session was that I never felt that I
was enough. And that seemed crazy to me
like on the on the first thing I'm like
hold I've like had all these
accomplishments I got this family you
know like I have good friends but when I
really dove down in it all of these
things that I had done in my life um
while some of them were virtuous um they
were all in an attempt to feel that I
was enough because some part of me in my
subconscious and my inner child I didn't
feel that I was enough and once we
started healing at and we did it through
this like very long mantrabbased 40-day
practice which you know I'll share that
in a second because I also think it's
something that is so powerful how you
can retrain your mind.
>> Yeah.
>> But like so once we recognized that was
it and it was very clear that all my
striving all my pressure all this you
know you know um kind of insecurity that
I had about myself was that I never felt
that I was enough. He had me do this
40-day practice, which really could be
applied to many limiting beliefs. But he
told me um for 40 days, every morning
for 20 minutes and every evening for 20
minutes, I was to set my timer and
basically close my eyes and do something
really simple. And I'd be, I am enough.
I've always been enough. I am enough.
I've always been enough. Now, I don't
know if you've done a mantra based
practice, but 20 minutes is a long time.
>> That's a long time, [laughter]
>> right? and and and to say the same
thing. And at first I hated it. The
first week went by and I was like, "Fuck
Dr. Dan." Like this is just crazy. How
is it how am I going to feel better?
Like second week kind of the same thing.
It wasn't until like the fourth week
that I started enjoying it like and it
20 minutes felt like two minutes and
then by like day 29, day 30 it was
really incredible how much more
lightness I felt in my body. And when
someone would say something that wasn't
nice to me or a piece of criticisms, it
would just kind of like roll right off
my back.
>> And I really think what happened during
that time was I literally reprogrammed
some of my neural pathways,
>> right? Because our thoughts are habits
too, right?
>> And
>> you talk about that in your book, right?
You get to take action first.
>> Yeah. Then thoughts then feelings. It's
so wild cuz I had Dr. Pay made me do a
similar thing but writing and I hated
it. I have a notebook where I write like
each and every day I'm healing in every
way and like it's like over and over and
over again and you do you feel crazy
because you're just like this is um yeah
just I felt like Matilda or something
writing on a chalkboard
>> and had another like kind of more sports
therapist team also have me do something
similar but out loud for some other
limiting thoughts I was having I guess
that were actually like translating into
how confidently I was carrying myself in
certain situations a whole thing.
>> Yeah,
>> it was so cool because it did work.
>> It did work.
>> It does.
>> Yeah, it works.
>> It's crazy. And it seems so simple.
Sometimes people come to me now and you
know, they're like, "Okay, like what's
the thing?" Like, like what did it work?
And they want some like, "Oh, I got my
brain stimulated by this thing and or I,
you know, went on this crazy psychedelic
journey and I was whatever." But
sometimes it's really these simple
things to reprogram because our thoughts
are so powerful.
>> Doesn't it scare you a little though
that we're around so many new words all
the time and that those could be so
impactful? Yeah.
>> Like if we hear the same thing over and
over again, what's to stop that from
becoming re a new reprogramming in our
minds? Well, I mean, that's why another
great piece of advice I got from Tony
Robbins, and Tony told me, he said,
"Blake, the most important thing in your
that's going to determine the future of
your life are the five people you spend
the most time with."
>> Yeah. Wow. What they say.
>> Yeah. Exact. But that's the whole point.
Like, if you choose the right five
people
>> because they're the ones who are
inputting
>> all this thought, all the the words that
become the thoughts or the fe and then,
you know, the feelings. And so, it's so
important. It's so powerful. I'm so
grateful for that healing from Dr. Dan
and how it ties back to this idea of
service actually goes back to India and
after I was with Krishna G and I was
there for a couple weeks in the ashram I
had the most beautiful download and it
was very similar to when I had the idea
for Tom Shoes but I was there and and I
think his his teaching around not having
obsessive self-centric thinking led me
to feel like oh my gosh like there's a
lot of people that don't feel enough
like our whole culture
>> I mean with social media and
compariveness And all these things are
leading us to constantly think are we
measuring up? Are we smart enough,
pretty enough, rich enough, whatever?
And our culture almost like is is
incentivized for us not to feel enough.
So we buy more things, you know? I mean,
it's it's literally built that way. And
when I was sitting there at the ashram,
I said to myself, I mean, it's so it was
so cool. It was like, okay, like you
have started to heal this and you're
feeling so much more peace. Like you've
got to go home and help others heal
this, too. And I didn't know what I was
going to do. Um, but I literally left
India and I had a purpose again like for
the first time since Tom's and I was
like I am going to do something, start a
nonprofit, whatever. And it was so
funny. I had dinner the first night. I
was back with one of my best friends
who's a really great designer and we
worked at Tom's for a while. And I was
telling him and it was actually his
idea. He's like, "You should do a
bracelet." And I was like, "A bracelet?
Why a bracelet?" And he's like, "Well,
you've always worn bracelets. I've
always had these different types of
bracelets from all over the world for my
travels. And he said, um, and he said, I
think you yourself need a daily
reminder.
>> You know, you need something you can
look at because, you know, and so here
you have this thing you look at every
day and also I think this is the message
that you want to share. So give out
these bracelets to people, you know,
give give people this daily reminder and
and I loved it. And so I went back to
India and we got these bracelets
handmade in India and they're really
beautiful. And um we came up with this
idea that you know we would give an
opportunity for someone to wear the
bracelet and then to give it to someone
else. And so I have one for you. This is
yours. You're one of the very first
people.
>> Oh my goodness. And these are it's it's
Oh wow. So there are two.
>> Yeah. So there's one for you and then
one to give to someone else.
>> I love the color green. I told you this,
but [laughter] I do love it.
>> Well, green is the mental health
awareness color. So, that's why we chose
green.
>> And it's the calmingest color, right? I
guess that's why they that's why I chose
it.
>> And then what's the message?
>> Let me see. Can I have it back? Oh, just
the message.
>> Yes. I'll give the whole thing back.
>> This is the box. Well, we have a
[laughter] We actually have a ritual.
So, I'm just going to do the full
ritual. So, if you'll put your palms up,
please.
>> Both
>> both palms out and I will I hope I'm not
>> I was like I don't want to be wearing
other things. Oh,
>> okay. So, I tied it on for anyone who's
listening, you now have the enough
bracelet on. So, the second part of the
ritual is there's a poem that comes with
it
>> and we realized that to give the
bracelet to someone. Some people might
not have the right words. So, we have
this amazing poet named in Q uh who's a
good friend of mine. I asked him to
write a poem that we always share with a
person when we give it to them. So, here
we go. Alexi, I see you. the you behind
the you. Not for anything you've done or
anything you're gonna do. I don't stop
to say it enough, but I believe in you.
And if you could see yourself from my
view, you'd believe it, too. That's why
I'm giving you the gift that I'm
receiving, too.
A message to remind you when you're lost
or feeling blue. A mantra to repeat when
times are tough because no matter who we
are, we are always enough. It's a silent
prayer I'm sending for the world's
mental health. I wear the symbol for
myself and now as a bond to someone
else. It's a blessing and a gentle push
to never give up because no matter who
you are, you are enough.
>> Thank you. You really mean that.
>> I do.
>> Yeah, you really mean it. That's like I
think not everybody knows what it feels
like to really mean that.
>> I just went out and I gave a TED talk
>> and it was lovely and fun, but I felt
like a few of the people that were there
wanted to speak to be heard
>> and not like help people.
>> And I felt [clears throat] like I could
see the people that like were not like
it was like consumed with like does my
makeup okay? Did I stutter? D because
this is their moment to like
>> just like coin a new phrase or like
whatever, you know, like these are what
these talks can do is like
>> really launch you in some way. it. I was
like, I guess I should have like
expected that feeling. And I had just
come from like this hunting trip in
Oregon where I was like very in touch
with nature and just like with a couple
guys and very like in very like awake
and honest cuz you have to be in these
circumstances
>> and it was just like it kind of sucked
cuz
>> Yeah. I was like, "Oh man, not everyone
like
is here." Yeah.
>> You know, and like that was so like you
are very here and it's it's really
awesome because you have a big audience
and platform and an ability to create
like a magnaminous wave with what you're
doing and that it's like really coming
from a real place. Like obviously what
you've been through is like so I mean
sometimes when I meet people who like
have been suicidal I'm like it's like
this special bond cuz it's like you
can't really fathom what it feels like
if you're really haven't felt it. You
can appreciate that
>> but it's a real like I don't know what
it is. Maybe it's like what alcoholics
feel with each other but there's
something about it where you're like
it's like a very intense thing and it's
weird to be like yeah I don't feel that
anymore. like I'm not going to kill
myself, you [laughter] know, but then
you still get these like passing
thoughts cuz they're never going to go
away completely.
>> I'm always in I say my depression always
be in recovery.
>> Yeah, it's always and and
so yeah, it was just that was really
powerful and like I'm just so like
encouraged by the world cuz I haven't
really met that many people like you.
Like I know I know successful people in
like a lot of ways, but like you
actually like fit into this category of
like people, entrepreneurial successes
that are able to maybe choose what
they're doing next and are choosing to
hopefully do good or other cool things
and you just never know like why they're
doing it, right?
>> And so that the why is so real is like
it just that was like a really awesome
moment for me to feel that. So, thank
you for sharing that with me and and
like I'm just so glad that you're real,
>> you know.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah, I really mean that. It's like
>> I feel that. I feel that. That was,
>> you know, it's I've tried to memorize
the poem. I almost did
>> and I got pretty close. I'm not a poet,
so it's hard to memorize sometimes, but
>> it's to really get to connect with
someone.
>> Yeah.
>> And someone who I know has
>> had moments of the same
>> Yeah. You know, feeling is like such a
gift because it it's it's healing for me
too, you know. It's like really every
time that I feel that I get to and this
is new and we're just starting, you
know, so it's like but I like that was
really special for me as well to see you
feel it, you know?
>> Yeah, I felt it. I really did. I really
felt it. I was like, "Oh man, this guy
doesn't have to do this."
>> Yeah.
>> Like you know what I mean? Like you
really don't have to like take that time
and give that. You could have like So
it's cool. It's really cool.
>> It's It's interesting. because I this is
all learning, right? And so it's someone
asked me the other day is, you know,
like, well, what do you want to happen
with this? Like, how much money do you
want to raise for mental health or this
or that? And I was like,
>> I honestly just want people to have some
of the interactions that I've had
already
>> where they really get to have what we
just had.
>> Well, I think that that was a really
Yeah, that really was an unlock of like
Yeah. the knowing that one person and
and maybe it's that that person has some
meaning in your life even if you don't
know them that well, right? Like I don't
I don't know you terribly well, but it
meant something because of like what spa
where you've been and what do you know
what I mean? It's like and so it is a
really powerful thing to have the the
gift and for people [clears throat]
>> and now you get to give it to the next
>> I know and it's and it needs to be a
very thoughtful one where like I can
really hopefully actually help someone
where I can uniquely have that message
be resonant and so I'll be very
thoughtful about it
>> and and I think the thing is like just
even seeing it on your wrist I know it's
>> is like um
>> well it's like but that person that
wears it will then also when they're
having a hard day or something, they'll
know that they have that bond to you.
>> That's right.
>> You know, so it's like that it's that
reminder that you referenced earlier in
the show of that how important it is to
not feel alone.
>> Yeah. And maybe what not feeling alone
really is is having someone there for
one of your worst fears,
>> right? Because this is a worst fear.
>> Yeah, for sure.
>> Territory, right? Totally.
>> And even if you don't know it yet, it
will be a worst fear when it occurs.
Like if I think about Ted giving you the
advice and then you being on the
mountain, right? Totally. That's the
worst fear, right?
>> We're now telling you. Yeah.
>> And so it's that like if your worst fear
occurs, which it might or you know that
you're not alone. And it's like a really
cool way to be able to actually live the
time between whether it occurs or not.
Sometimes it's not your worst will never
happen.
>> Why do we buy insurance? Why do we have
a life jacket? Exactly. You know, all
these things we do just in case. This is
kind of a little bit of an insulation.
Like a lot of the people that I've
started to give the enough bracelet to
never had any mental health challenges
and they wear it like oh I wear it you
know as a as in honor of my mom who
always makes me feel enough. So it's
like just a positive thing for them or I
wear it to support mental health and you
know friends of mine that have
struggled. But it is kind of like a like
you said it's kind of like a you might
never come to that crisis but it's
always nice to have the preparation
ahead of time. Yeah.
>> And to know that you have someone in
your corner. I think that's the biggest
thing. It's like that bond with two
people to know it's it's it's uh Yeah.
So, thank you. That was really
beautiful.
>> Yeah. Awesome. I'll be thinking about it
for a long time, too, cuz it's a special
way to deliver the message and the the
connection is very powerful and I won't
even know how powerful it is until I
need to call you one day and be like, I
need to [laughter]
>> I'm like it's happening.
>> Well, it help I think it's like just
even the room changed, you know, like
the vibration
more connection, less performance, you
know, that's something that I always
really really try to focus on with with
um and then like in business, I always
say go for meaning instead of marketing,
>> you know, like I really think that
businesses that focus on marketing
>> usually don't really break through.
Businesses that focus on meaning
>> are the ones that change the world.
>> Yeah. And so I always say is like like
we're what we're just trying to create
more meaning in people's lives. And if
we do that, people will buy it or
whatever we're doing. Try to kind of
bring it back to like what's the most
meaningful to you. Because if you're
really focusing on what you really care
about, then the right people will
probably care about that as well. But if
you're trying to like predict what other
people care about,
>> that's when you get yourself into
trouble. That's a really good advice
especially like you know in the world of
social in the world of like you know
>> social media
>> social media because it's a total mix of
like
>> personality storytelling and advertising
is like a part of a lot of it
>> and so just making sure to know that
like go back to meaning go back to
meaning
>> and um make it true you
>> yeah I mean that's what you know because
I mean look the the thing about enough
is my goal is is not only do we create
these amazing interaction that we just
had, but also that we do raise a lot of
money for mental health nonprofits. You
know, there's so many mental health
organizations in the country that are
struggling with the right financing. And
so, in order to do that, we need to sell
a ton of bracelets. I have to go back to
my Tom's days, right? And so in order to
sell a ton of bracelets, you know, one
of the biggest ways to do that is
working with creators on social media,
you know, and so I've always believed
that, you know, like whenever we used to
sell at Nordstrom's and Tom shoes, I
used to say I want them to make as much
money on a pair of Tomms as a pair of
Converse.
>> So like even though we're giving all
these shoes away, I don't want the the
the the the ways that the business is
built to have to like sacrifice. And
that's the same thing with our creators.
Like we pay the same commissions, the
same structure as any brand that might
work with them. But the difference is is
all we're asking them to do is if this
is a message that really resonates with
you and you feel this like share your
story. Like the rest will take care of
itself. Like you don't need to be like
pushing or selling the bracelets. It's
like this is I'm wearing this as a daily
reminder. And by doing that, you know,
plenty the right people will come to it,
you know? And so it's it's really about
I think that's just so important. It's
like, you know, there's nothing wrong
with working with social media and
creators and doing these things. The the
the thing is when it really works well
is someone can be authentically sharing
their story and making a living and
putting a message that helps people.
>> Totally.
>> Like it's it's so fun to do it that way.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And it's and it should
feel natural like that
>> as much as you're being thoughtful about
it.
>> Ah the sound when you pop open a go.
Sorry I'm just really thirsty right now.
Not to pause in the middle of a
beautiful conversation that we're
having, but when it hits, it hits. And
for me, I've been drinking Go Brewing
instead of soda, honestly, instead of
beer. And regretfully, sometimes instead
of [music] water because I love it so
much. For me, I've been drinking it
because I don't want to feel crappy,
which I feel when I drink beer. And
also, I like the taste. Like genuinely
would grab this over kombucha, grab this
over often water, and grab this over
soda, which is good for me. And you can
get your Go Brewing, too. You get this
flavor, you get chilada. If you go to
gobwing.com/exi,
you can get 15% off your order. Throw
these in the fridge, go run 8 miles,
come home, drink one of these. You'll be
very happy you did. I don't feel like I
need to convince you either. This is
just It's actually really, really good.
I love it. I genuinely love it. This is
Oh, it's blueberry and strawberry.
It's That doesn't even do it justice.
It's like
I would call [music] this tart and fruit
refreshing summer day. That's what they
should call it.
Try it yourself.
>> The founder of Spanx is a woman named
Sarah Blakeley and she's become a good
friend over the years and she's been
very financially successful. I think you
know one of the wealthiest women in
America, self-made. And one day we were
talking about money and like how to have
the right relationship to money, you
know,
>> and she said the best advice I've ever
heard. She said, "Blake, money should be
really fun to make.
>> You should have a lot of fun spending it
once you make it, and you should have a
lot of fun giving it away, doing
charity." And she said, "But the most
important thing is it's always got to be
fun."
>> It's really good. It really is
interesting, especially if someone has,
you know, had some financial success,
like you hear of a lot of people money
really making a mess of their lives.
>> Yeah.
>> And whether you've had financial success
or you're or you're just starting out in
your career, like to just know like if
you can approach it with fun that you're
it's never going to have that kind of
negative effect that it can have on you.
And and it's great because I found even
for myself and she gave me this advice
when I was doing
>> a ton of philanthropy post post Toms
>> and I got to a place where I found
myself kind of just writing a lot of
checks to different charities that were
very worthy but I it was almost out of
obligation like I didn't feel I wasn't
having fun with it
>> and so then like now I look at like
enough I'm having so much fun doing it
>> and we're also helping so many people
and so you could be doing the same thing
>> but it's the it's the mindset that you
have that makes all the difference in
the world.
>> I have tried to and tell me if this is
like in line with this like I've tried
to assign more meaning to like okay I
went and gave this talk. This is
actually helping me like work on a a
deck on my house that I'm really excited
about hanging out with my friends on and
like putting more like images to it has
helped me feel more like aware of the
money.
>> I like that. And it's it's really helped
me.
>> I like that a lot.
>> And it makes me feel a little more like
like it's not more in control. It's just
like more intentional and less nebulous.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and I guess more fun because I'm
like, "Okay, this is that or like even
groceries." Like that can be fun if you
think about like what is funding the
groceries? Is it, you know, totally
something that makes me like giggle? Cuz
it's like kind of odd that like that is
the thing. And even though it is one pot
of money, like I just try to have it all
have some sort of meaning almost like in
a game board. So that money isn't just
an idea.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, I think that's the problem is that
so many people think
>> like they think about money like in how
much you make and how much you have and
like this like this this accumulation
thing, but it's really like when you
think of it the way you've assigned
value to it of like, okay, by doing this
and getting these advertisers, I can go
on this vacation.
>> Yeah. or or I can help my friend or I
can get, you know, tell me. You're
excited. I love this.
>> Well, it's funny. I was on one episode
of This Is Us and it was like a tiny
little like cameo roll and it was so fun
cuz it was like a huge set and blah blah
blah, but like not a big part, right?
But I get residuals. [laughter]
>> Yes.
>> And so I'll get this check for like $66
randomly whenever it plays on TV. And I
make sure that I spend that in really
fun ways cuz I'm like, "This doesn't
exist."
>> We call that mailbox money. Have you
heard of that before?
>> No.
>> I don't have that. [laughter]
>> No. Mailbox money is when
[clears throat] you have done something
in the past that you have some type of
commission, residuals, whatever, and
you've forgotten about it and all it
just shows up in your mailbox. I've had
a few mailbox monies.
>> It's so fun. That's the most fun cuz
you're like, "Why don't there's no just
like it's just just a great bonus."
Yeah. and and I literally cannot predict
it cuz it's like I don't know when this
show is like airing again, you know, or
this episode of this show.
>> Um, but that's very fun. I like that
advice a lot. It also really does help
you not take money too seriously because
to play is is more like a game and to
make sure that in life we're not like
>> I don't know like um
>> you know that we're a bit playful with
life in general is probably like the
right way cuz money we made it up anyway
you know like it really matters but we
need to keep it in perspective too. This
whole thing is a beautiful play. They
call that in India Leia. Leah, I think.
And that the translation is it's just a
big play.
>> Oh, really? Like a play like theater or
playful?
>> Both.
>> Okay.
>> Like it's a it's it's it's just enjoy
it. Like it's going to happen so fast.
And so we've got to make the most
meaning out of it every day that we can.
Yeah.
>> And we have to really see it as like
we're all just playing these different
roles and hopefully putting on this
beautiful play.
>> Yeah. That's cool. Yes. In the next
scene of our play, we will [laughter]
move on to more advice.
>> So, here's one for entrepreneurs and
also I just think people in general,
it's do you know who Simon Synynic is?
>> Nope.
>> Okay, great. Well, I had this idea when
you talked about TED earlier because
Simon has did a TED talk that I think is
if you are starting a business or
involved in a nonprofit, like if there's
one TED talk to watch, it's Simon's.
like it is. I've learn I've I've played
it to my staff literally countless times
over the years of any business I'm
running. Had a huge impact on how I
built Tom's. But his is all about the
why. And so what he explains and he goes
through history of some of the greatest
movements and companies. I don't want to
ruin the TED talk about, you know, why
they really worked. And it always goes
back to they were not selling, you know,
features. People buy it because of the
why you're doing it. They don't buy what
you're doing. They buy why you're doing
it. And I think you res you really I
actually got that idea when you
reflected back to me that you really
felt like my why.
>> And so I think that's why we had such a
meaningful experience. And I think that
if you're starting a company or you're
working a nonprofit and you're trying to
sell something to someone or you're
trying it goes even if you're a creator
like people have to feel the why. And I
think we've gotten sometimes so focused
with algorithms and best practices and
this and that to focus on like what's
performing or what do people want or
what's our new feature of our product or
you know why is our glitter better than
others you know but then if you can
focus on the why
>> all that stuff will take care of itself
and and this TED talk I mean it is
amazing it's a short one it's not that
long um it's like early early in his
career and uh I think it came out maybe
20 years ago, but find Simon Synynic's y
talk and it is going to bless you for
sure.
>> That's the advice I needed today for my
entrepreneurial journey.
>> It's great.
>> Um it's great too because it also seems
to combat any like how to get through
the tough moments if you're even
internally, right? Because to
[clears throat] get up and do it every
day regardless of what the world's going
to think of it takes a lot of like why
energy. And it's easier to stay on the
why for a prolonged period of time than
looking at metrics day in day out. Yeah.
>> Because nothing is built overnight. I
mean like like like like you know my
sister is a great entrepreneur. Do you
know the brand Aviator Nation?
>> So that's my sister.
>> Oh wow.
>> So she started that.
>> I was like I went to a concert at that
place in Malibu and jumped in the ocean
afterwards.
>> It's amazing. Right. So fun. So
literally that business is 20 years old.
the first say seven to 10 years it was
tiny
>> but she just stayed true to her thing.
She's like I'm gonna make the most
comfortable best sweats like her style.
She built out every store. My parents
helped design like you know you know you
know hammer up the records on the wall.
I mean just she never took investor
money. She just was so focused on the
puress and then it just exploded. I mean
now she's got 22 stores. It's one of the
most valuable brands in the world. She
owns 100% of it. I mean, just an amazing
entrepreneur. But but that's a good
example of like she was able to
persevere all those years because she
really just stayed focused on why she
was doing it and what she believed she
loved and then eventually the rest of
the world woke up and loved it too.
>> That's really cool. And it's a kind of
the another side of the coin of you're
not alone. Like both with your tough
feelings and with the things you really
care about, you're probably not alone.
>> Yeah. And you don't need everybody to to
you don't need that much to be a highly
successful business. You know, you need
enough people to
>> to to feel that way,
>> but it's far less than you think. So,
here's another thing for your for your
entrepreneurial venture. Yeah.
>> So, one of the greatest marketing minds
in the world, you know, he [snorts] his
name is Seth Goden. Do you know Seth
Goden?
>> Only the name.
>> Okay, great. So, he's written amazing
books. One of the best ones is The
Purple Cow. Highly recommend that one.
The reason it's called purple cow is
like imagine you're driving down the
road, okay? And you see cows and cows
and cows,
>> no big deal. But if you drove by and you
saw a purple freaking cow, [laughter]
what would you do? You'd stop. You take
a picture of it. You look at it. You
see, is this real? Like you'd be
obsessed with purple cow. So if you want
to create a business or anything, a
movement that works, you got to have a
purple cow. It's got to be remarkable.
So Seth Goden wrote another book. I
think it's called Tribes Maybe. Um, but
basically he did the math for us that
really you only need a thousand people.
>> Whoa.
>> That's all you need. You if you have a
thousand people who absolutely love what
you're doing and really believe in it
and are willing to share with their
friends, you can start any movement in
the world.
>> Wow. That's so awesome because I feel
like the expectation would be that it
would be a percentage and that seems
like infinity. Even if the percentage is
small, thousand people
>> that it's awesome to have that in your
head. He's he's an amazing guy. He I've
been lucky enough to have lunch with him
one time. He was a big fan of Tom's in
the early day and yeah, but that's
another thing. If you're a business
person and you're young and you don't
know who, you know, Seth Goden is,
that's fine because he wrote a lot of
books a long time ago. Like get his
books. Great. Like those books help me.
I didn't go to school. I didn't go to
college. Didn't go to business school.
like his books and other books like
Richard Branson's book, you know, Howard
Schultz who started Starbucks, his book,
Mary Kay Cosmetics, her book is
incredible. Like these were my teachers,
like these books.
>> And yeah, and they're available and and
you know, you can
>> Yes, you can buy a book.
>> You can just read and listen to them. I
mean, I listen to so many books now.
It's so great.
>> I love satellite mentors like that. Like
the ones that now maybe you've had lunch
with them, but when you first met them,
it was through their books.
>> Yeah. Oh, yeah. I didn't meet any of
these people originally. It was always
your books.
>> And did you always feel like the stuff
you learned in books was like just yours
immediately? Like meaning do you have
you always had a very positive
relationship with ingesting a book and
saying, "Yep, that'll be mine now." Like
the information.
>> One of the things I like about
biographies is, you know, it's the
reason I wrote a book in 200 gosh 10 um
about about Tom's and social
entrepreneurship. It's called Start
Something That Matters. And the reason I
wrote it and the reason I love
biographies is that like once you've had
success, you you don't have insecurities
the same way you might have in your
earlier in your career. So you're
willing to talk about all your failures,
right?
>> You're willing to talk all the times you
[\h__\h] up. And so we learn so much more
from a business book, from what didn't
work than what we see publicly that's
working. You know, in some ways, like
hopefully people are learning more from
me sharing about my suffering and how I
got through it than they did when they
were just seeing me on the cover of a
magazine with Tom Shoes. And so, so I I
think that to answer your question about
do I I really do feel like when I read a
book, especially a biography, a business
biography, because that's, you know, my
trade in some ways, I do I I really take
those stories and okay, what did he
learn from that? Why didn't that work?
have I experienc I mean I really do kind
of look at it and maybe it's because I
didn't go to college so that is kind of
like my like when I read those books I'm
like studying
>> well I it's that's how I'm sure they
were intended to be taken in too like
nobody writes a book thinking like this
is only for everybody hopes it's for
everybody right
>> and so I think I just
>> um I want to acknowledge that for people
who might other themselves from other
people's stories
instead of like taking what's truly like
making it their own immediately, right?
No matter how different the story might
be, it's really about
>> like learning how people think, right?
Cuz you're probably reading these things
about people with drastically different
lives than yours,
>> but they're they're
>> they're navigating things and you're
learning how they think.
>> Totally. Yeah.
>> Amazing. Well, who else is on your list?
I've got one more is my own advice.
>> Yes. Oh my god. Okay, so now we get
advice from you. [snorts]
>> Well, it's something new I just
discovered. It's like this little
discovery. Um there's this organization.
It's a nonprofit. I think you can make
donations to it called Future Self.
>> It's a website
>> and what you do is you go and you write
letters to your future self
>> and then they come back in the form of
an email at a suggested time
>> that you suggest.
>> Yeah. You can say 6 months send me this,
a year send me, send me this on my
anniversary, send me this on my
birthday, send me this.
>> And it has been incredible in my journey
because at different times in my
journey, in my healing journey, I would
I would and this is some way of trying
to manifest growth and healing, I'd say,
okay, in four months, send me a letter
checking in about these three things.
Like, have I stayed accountable to my
daily practice? You know, am I making,
you know, this special time for my kids?
Like whatever the things are. And it's
different than like journaling and
remembering to go look back because this
just show up on your inbox. And what's
so cool is I literally feel like God's
involved in this organization because it
shows up at the exact right time. Like
I'll put like four months and then turns
out that day I was like really having a
bunch of self-doubt and I get this
encouraging letter from myself. Like
it's it's incredible. Like it's really
cool.
>> That's really cool. It's like you sent
an owl out that you can't stop. It's not
there's nothing there's no intercepting
it is what I mean
>> because they do it
>> totally totally and I have one more
>> yes
>> just a little discovery so I discovered
this app the other day called Sonia
>> and it's called emotional support
basically online therapy with AI
>> and it was really interesting because I
was at a mental health conference and
there was this guy speaking and
I have a standing therapy every see it's
every Wednesday at 2:00, right? And so
every Wednesday at 2:00 I have this this
time which my therapist which has been
great and has helped me a ton but what
about all the time in between and I just
want to like talk to someone but I don't
want to like dump on my friends or
something
>> and so I I just tried it out the other
day and it was like pretty freaking
amazing
>> really
>> like I mean like try it for 30 minutes
it's gonna blow your mind. Are you
texting? Are you talking? And it talks
right back and in a beautiful voice. You
can choose all different voices. And
it's like I know they say that um 80% or
or 75% of chat GDP questions are about
like coaching or therapeutic or like
anything around like our mental
well-being. But this is like I don't
know what they've done, but they've
somehow like made it like a therapist
and it remembers everything.
>> So like I did a session the other day.
I' just been messing around with it for
the past couple weeks and it asked me
about something from like a week ago
checking in like a friend would and I
was just blown away. Like think how many
people can't afford therapy.
>> Well, yeah. Or your proximity to it.
Like when I was in Mammoth when mine
hit, there were no therapists there. So,
I had to move back to Oregon. I had to
move back to Oregon. It was so awful.
And I like didn't want to be in Oregon,
but it was like where the therapist was.
And there was not a single one in in
Mammoth that could help me. Um and at
the time there wasn't like the tea tele
world wasn't as developed. So it wasn't
>> Yeah.
>> No, it's it's I mean that's you think
about we went from you had to be in
person to now zoom and all that. That's
all happened in the last what 5 10
years. So it's it's it's going to evolve
and you know and I don't think they're
trying to take they're saying that we
replace your therapist. are saying like
with Sonia there's so much time in
between maybe when you have a session
that that you're going to feel better
and that's why they call it emotional
supportive like just sharing things and
the other thing that's nice it's like
you're never embarrassed
>> right
>> you know like I mean that's sometimes
even with my therapist I I kind of like
do I really want to talk about this
>> there's a bit with Sonia I'm like
[laughter] just there's no judgment like
you know I share everything sometimes
especially if I'm like having trouble
with like a relationship ship. It's
really great. Like it's like if I'm
like, "Okay, here's what's going on, you
know, with my ex or here's what's going
on, you know, with this business
situation and like I'll just talk for
like 20 minutes it seems like." And then
it just like replays back to me, but
with like I know this about you and this
and anyways, it's
>> that's that's my kind of last thing I
can think about that has just had a big
impact on me in such a short period of
time.
>> Thank you for sharing that because
people are probably finding it and don't
know Don't know if there's, you know,
don't know what to think about it
necessarily yet.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> I have one last question just because
like I'm I am interested in like having
a
>> like I'm trying to next year be much
more like really really intentional with
my time cuz I'm in like a like the only
way I could describe it is like there's
balls on TE's and I'm like ready to like
hit and stuff.
>> Are you a golfer?
>> No. Um
>> just golf analogy just come natural. I
think I was thinking about softballs,
[laughter]
but like yeah, golf. Okay. Balls on
TE's. Oh, they're te's, right? Oh, yeah.
T's. Okay. Okay. Golf. And I've worked
really hard to like set some stuff up
like years, you know? And I guess I was
just wondering is there anything cuz I
don't have a lot of like
>> like business mentors, I think. But just
like is there anything about like
anything that comes to mind as as minute
or [clears throat] or big about like
just like getting my [\h__\h] done and like
doing my life whether it's like how I
spend my time or like little habits or
like anything that you found helpful to
you? Like literally anything. I'm just
like I want to make sure I'm like taking
my life seriously, you know.
>> Okay, great. I have a good piece of
advice. Okay.
>> Yeah. And it came from my dad actually.
>> Oh, great. So, we were playing golf on
vacation, and at this point, I had
started my first business, which was a
laundry business. And so, I was
technically making money while I was on
vacation as a 22-year-old. And he was
losing money because the only way a
surgeon makes money is by doing surgery.
>> And so, what he said was if he was to do
it all over again, he would have chosen
the path I was choosing, being an
entrepreneur, because I can be on
vacation and still make money. I can be
sleeping and still making money. And so
when you ask for kind of a life advice
as you look at all the things that are
doing um this is great but this is very
timeconuming you know at the beginning
of starting a business you know with
your your your glitter uh business you
know it's going to take a lot of time
but if you can build it to where it
starts to work on the flywheel itself
then that can be a nice source of income
you know whether you're doing anything
or not and so I think one of the most
important things in doing and starting a
small business and hopefully becomes a
big business is don't make it too
dependent on you.
>> Like that's really important. Like
figure out the thing that only you can
do
>> and then try to have outsources much
else. I learned that from Tim Ferrris
too with the 4-hour work week. That book
is amazing by the way. Um but uh yeah
like don't make it so dependent on you.
So like even with enough now like it's
my story that kicks it off. But like I
originally like I brought in other
founding partners like Kid Cuy's a
partner, Kevin Love's a partner like so
that other people can be out there
spreading the word. It's just not just
me doing it
>> because a business can only scale as
much as you have the systems in place to
do it. And if you want to have a quality
life and not be working all the time,
>> you know, find out the thing you can do
only and do that, but let others do
everything else.
>> That's really great advice. That's amaz
It's really really good advice because
you would think you could think like
it's the opposite, [laughter] you know?
Yeah. Like make sure you are
indispensable, you know, all that stuff.
And it's like actually make it like
derivative of your indispensability but
not um dependent on you not going
golfing with your dad on vacation
>> or going surf. For me, I'm a big surfer
and so I like to surf and so I don't
want my ability to not go surfing in the
morning because I've got to be doing
this and this. So, it's really it's
really hard to do it first, but if you
can do it in the beginning, it's easier
when it gets bigger.
>> Yeah. Well, it's a good I think it's a
foundational
>> That's it. Yeah. It's a foundation,
right? And so, that's that's really
great cuz I was going to be like, "Tell
me to drink orange juice every morning."
And you're [laughter] like, "No, no, no,
no, no. We're going to take two steps
back." Um, totally.
>> So, Oh my god. Amazing. Well, I'm I'm so
grateful. This was like, again, it's
like Halloween candy where everyone's
going to be like, I want this one. I
want this one. I want this one. And
there was so much wisdom and truth and
also like your story. I can't say enough
about how awesome it is that you are
like just like a a mindful real awake
person
>> crafting your life but also kind of like
a um observing your life at the same
time
>> that you know I feel like there's people
who just are so maybe one or the other
and I think that
>> is the dream for any of us is to like
feel agency and then feel vulnerability
at the same time. Um, so thank you and
I'm so glad to be um in your life and
you in mine.
>> Thank you so much. This is awesome.
>> Amazing.
>> If you're enjoying Mentor Buffet, follow
Voicing Change for [music] more
inspirational and truly lifeaffirming
content from shows like Soul Boom, The
Proof, Feel Better, Live More, and The
Rich Roll Podcast. Just go to
voicingchange.mdia. [music]
That's voicing change.m media for a
beautiful selection of productive and
positive [music] shows.