it was one of these moments and I didn't
even have this moment when I started
Tom's a lot of people asked me when I
started Tom's like did you have like a
Tiffany was there like a vision was
there note from God like what was it
that caused you to go from like an
entrepreneur or just starting businesses
to make money to like I want to create a
company to help people but this moment
is the moment that people been asking
about my whole life if I've had and now
I can say I did have it and that was it
got off the phone I shut my laptop and I
just knew that that someone was me
[Music]
sidenote I don't love guns in fact I
don't think I've fired a gun since I was
17 years old on a camping trip with
friends out in Joshua Tree just like
you're shaking I'm gonna get on this
finger off the trigger just like that
remember you want to take your front
sight and put it in your rear sight
it'll look something like this just
glance out with your eye there you go a
nice bend in the knees
[Music]
I've heard you tell the story but maybe
you could retell it here about why now
is the time to take a stand and as a
company as a branch or get behind trying
to eliminate gun violence yeah
I mean I don't think it was I know it
was in the case of like determining now
is a good time and more a very visceral
spontaneous response to a tragedy that
happened close to my family so you know
I remember when parkland happened and
just in and watching the Parkland kids
on the debate on CNN and just how just
like how strong their voices were for
needing a change and having gun
legislation really looked at in a more
sensible way and I remember watching
that and thinking good for those kids
I support they do I signed up to get the
text messages you know that was that
then I remember hearing about the next
shooting and the next shooting and I
remember feeling a feeling of like this
is this is kind of like a really
horrible thing that's going on our
country but it never was a personal
thing to me it never was something like
oh I'm gonna go get involved in that
right and then in November 8th so you
know not that long ago there was a
shooting in Thousand Oaks which is about
2015 20 minutes from my house and I
didn't know about it because I had
happened that night and I was on my way
to work the next morning and my wife
called me and I was in the back of the
uber working on some emails kind of
pretty focused on work and so I answered
the phone and she's like really really
emotional and she says did you see the
news and I said no and she said there
was another shooting you know this time
it happened literally just down the
street from us and I'm not taking our
son to school today and I was like why
he's like I don't think it's safe there
was been shootings in schools there was
one in yoga studio there was one in the
synagogue like how do I know that
someone is not going to come into his
preschool which is a Jewish preschool
and pull out a gun
and I was like whoa babe we don't you
don't know that but you can't like you
know make every decision out of fear
because of this happen close to us and
then I started really understanding like
where she was was probably where a lot
of people were at this point because it
had gotten so many shootings that their
proximity was by 15 minutes from a lot
of people well it's just so pervasive so
ridiculous so so we so she gets off the
phone and she says to me she says you
know someone has to do something about
it and it was one of these moments and I
didn't even have this moment when I
started Tom's a lot of people asked me
when I started Tom's like did you have
like a Tiffany was there like a vision
was there a note from God like what was
it they caused you to go from like an
entrepreneur or just starting businesses
to make money to like I want to create a
company to help people it was actually
like a creative idea it could be
interesting let's make 200 pairs let's
see what happens in experiments yes
experiment but this moment is the moment
that people been asking about my whole
life have I've had and now I can say I
did have it and that was a Gotha phone I
shut my laptop and I just knew that that
someone was me I didn't know why I
didn't know how but I knew that like I
had a platform and Tom's as my business
had a reach that could make a difference
in this topic I didn't know how exactly
that I knew that we needed to do
something like because at Toms we have
given so many shoes and so many people
their eyesight through our sunglass
program but we've been like itching for
the past couple years to do something
bigger to do something different it
didn't take a stand on something and so
it was already kind of in my head like
we need to do something that is relevant
to the issues of our time and there was
just all this is like this is it like if
there's a time let's do it now now it
was incredibly inconvenient because it
was a week before Black Friday and Cyber
Week our biggest sales week of the year
and it was also very inconvenient
because you know we our business was not
in a place where we could just afford to
give up sales to dedicate all of our
attention to and again violence sure but
I just knew that this was something we
had to do so I sent an email to our
board
to my partners to our CEO and said guys
like if not us who if not now when you
know that a great Jewish proverb and and
and over about three or four days I
convinced them that this you know by no
means I was convincing that this would
be great for business
but I knew that it would be the right
thing for our staff because that mean
happened so close like I think they were
feeling very much the same way my wife
was and I knew that it would be a way
that it would reengage a lot of the
people who maybe were with us in the
beginning of Tom's because we were truly
an activist brand and I think we started
as an activist brand we were very
radical as you said no one was doing
this and then six years later we were a
big brand and everyone was doing some
form of giving everyone jumped on the
back and so this would be a way to shock
the system and be like holy [\h__\h] like
toms is really going out there now on a
limb and and and I knew that we needed
to do that like something in my gut just
said this is what we need to do and I
knew he could be impactful because I
learned about some of the things that
were happening in the in the gun
violence space specifically I learned
about universal background checks and I
learned about that on day two and when I
learned about that I recognized okay
there is a very moderate non-political
because ninety percent of Americans are
in favor of universal background checks
way to approach this I want to go back
to when you approached the board about
yes because there might be some lessons
or nuggets there are other people who
are trying to you know maybe go against
the grain or buck this system or
something different
what kind of pushback did you get and
how hard did you have to wrestle like
did you have to did you have talked
about numbers like we're gonna lose this
much but it's worth it because or like
did you just have to say this was the
right thing to do I know what my gut
yeah guts don't really work real well
we're boards yeah so specially financial
partners so unpack that a little bit so
so others can learn sure same kind of I
think the the biggest thing was the
board questioned and I think they were
they were mistaken at first in thinking
that we did not have the right or there
were
the or the credibility to play in the
space so they basically said look there
are every town and and March for our
lives and mothers demand action and
amazing nonprofits that have dedicated
tens of millions of dollars in years to
trying to have sensible gun legislation
yeah you are not a political person I'm
not at all
like I didn't even know who Mitch
McConnell was when the start like I mean
that's how non-political I am so like
you're not political Tom's is not a
political brand like we've never done
anything about gun violence how do we go
from giving shoes to kids to take me
astounding oh it's like I just don't
understand how the customer is gonna
understand this and and and that was
their position and so they said like
personally we totally agree on this like
actually some of our board members are
really big donors to every town and
other organizations right but I just
don't think out Tom shows up here well
and it does sound like a fair and
logical are yeah it was a good but my
argument back was Tom's is not a shoe
company we are a movement when we are
best and we exist for a better tomorrow
it's in our name it's a reason I started
Tom's I just use shoes for the last 12
years to fund the idea that we can
create a better tomorrow through and I
believe that if we take a stand and make
a big contribution which turned out to
be the largest contribution in the
history of the United States to this
issue that we can create a better and
safer tomorrow and that's the business
that were in
and so that's ultimately what I had to
convince him that our business was
bigger and it had and had permission to
engage in a topic like this even though
it wasn't obvious like when you looked
at it on paper and I think the only
reason that I ultimately want it was
going back to the gut thing which I say
is not the thing I led with because no
one only has a good argument but
ultimately we had to look your chair in
the eyes and I said guys you're invested
in me and you supported me up into this
point and I've never in the relay
because I've been these partners for
four years I've never said we have to do
anything I've actually changed some of
my ideas and strategies and philosophies
based on your guidance I said
this is the time I might be the only
time where I'm telling you every single
thing in my body says we have to do this
now not only because it's the right
thing to do but because it will
re-engage Andry motivate this movement
and and I think that conviction was
stronger than their conviction of I
don't know if we can play here you went
to the mat went to the mat I love it
yeah the first thing I heard about it
it's it struck a chord right away for
two reasons one because I've got kids
and and that's one of the main yeah it's
been on my mind constantly sure and the
other thing is about ten years ago I had
a gun violence experience where it was
right when I was starting my production
company we were in this small little
studio space there's like eight o'clock
at night four or five of us were in the
office just sort of editing I hear this
loud crash locked out front kind of the
front lobby area to figure out what it
was three really big guys all tatted up
no masks or anything come barreling in
with guns guns a-blazing the gun was put
right to my forehead told me that you
know get her out all of us into this
room put us kind of execution-style on
the ground and for a minute I thought
okay I'm gone like I just sort of made
some generalizations like no no mask or
cover-up okay these guys don't care who
sees them does that mean I'm going to
die 10 hi yeah yeah and I remember we
kind of looked at each other on the
ground thinking should we do something
up and fight for our life that or she
was cool and it was it was a moment of
you know very surreal is the best way to
explain it sure but also terrifying but
at that moment I sort of felt calm like
just chill out and like yeah yeah just
let them take what they're gonna take
anyway so and it was terrifying too
because they took my ID and they read it
out loud and they said you know my name
and the read off my driver's license my
address and if you call the police we're
coming to get you all that good stuff
and I was like boy
you know it was heavy but you know so
ever since you know that was a moment
every time I see one of these shootings
happen or
I sort of think about that and I think
how terrifying it is and how awful it is
that this is still such a big problem in
the United States yeah and I'm so happy
you know I signed up on the site I went
you know did my post card right thank
you so tell us what the vision is yes so
you're now gonna go in this sort of
Caravan right yes yeah it's wrapped and
I mean so yeah so we recognized with
this idea that universal background
checks was a very simple very moderate
kind of the least political polarizing
part of the ending and violence
initiative is a good place to start yeah
because it basically keeps felons from
buying guns yeah
people who are domestic abusers and
people have mental health issues like
that's it like if you're not one of
those three then you will pass your
background check and you can buy a gun
yeah but that was three contribute to a
lot of gun violence and so especially
the the felons aspect and so one of the
things that we recognized is every that
this was going to be legislation that
would be presented in the house in 2019
and the only way that it would get
passed in a bipartisan way which is
going to potentially allow it to become
a law is if Americans in every state and
every territory made their voices heard
hey I'm a proud gun owner but I'm also a
father to a young son and I don't want
him going to school scared so if you're
like me you're like 90% of other
Americans who want universal background
checks I just saw a statistic that said
there were 307 mass shootings in the
last 311 days in our country which is
terrifying and devastating and as a
proud gun owner myself that's a right
and a privilege that I take very very
serious as I know a lot of you guys do
too but I think we can all come together
and all agree that something has to
change it's unacceptable we shouldn't
have to walk out of the house and live
in fear anymore
so let's come together as a country
let's do our part Tom's is doing a
really cool campaign right now to raise
awareness for universal background
checks and I know there's a lot of
factors that's going to go into really
making some change but this is an easy
thing that we can all do and when I
spoke to different people because I had
no political background at all I said
what can we do what can TOMS do
we're gonna get five million dollars
largest contribution ever to these
nonprofits but what can we actually do
to to affect the politics of this and
one of the people that I was speaking to
he said postcards
he says old-fashioned postcards he says
when those representatives get a lot of
postcards and they're from people in
their constituency they listen so I just
had this vision of Miracle on 34th
Street where they come in and they pour
all the envelopes yeah from Santa is
that the intention yeah that's the
intention so what we started with was we
built a simple technology on the website
on the home page during Black Friday and
Cyber week so we gave up a lot of sales
to have this as the main real estate and
in 30 seconds or less and still today
for the next couple weeks you can still
do it I did it it is yeah yeah you go to
the website you put in your name and
address it's all basically turned kids
super simple so in 30 seconds you can do
it so we've had seven hundred and
sixteen thousand Americans and yourself
do post cars that's I mean phenomenal I
mean that's a massive amount of people
to speak out so clearly about something
well and so quickly
yeah and so in eight weeks yeah you
mobilised yeah almost a million people
in eight weeks that's it there's that we
did without any marketing either I mean
this all happened virally like we were
literally I launched it on Jimmy Fallon
and he sent the first postcard which
helped because then 50,000 people did it
immediately yeah
but then from those 50,000 it just grew
and and so we'll talk about signals I
mean that's that's a signal right yeah
like the people of spoken kind of yeah
so now what and I take no responsibility
for this great idea this was the this
was the creative team at Tom's they said
you know what to send 716 thousand
postcards is gonna cost us you know like
a quarter of a million dollars what if
we drove all those postcards across the
country in hand-deliver them to the 500
representatives in Congress that would
be more impactful and it would cost us
less money yeah that's it and you create
a spectacle yeah
and so that's what we're doing so we
launched it today on the tour is gonna
go on for about two and a half weeks
we're gonna be in Washington DC February
5th and so if you're watching this right
now and you want to come join us please
do we hope that there'll be thousands of
volunteers that will help us
hand-deliver these
postcards on February 5th and and we
believe because that's gonna be about
two to three weeks before the vote so we
believe that will be a really important
indicator in influence on many of the
votes that will happen for universal
background checks that's amazing it's
been fun
well of course know we're going to have
support it
[Music]