I think that life is all about
connection and community. It's all about
relationships [music]
and finding ways to connect with people
deeply. Invest in those connections and
never lose
sight of how important that is. Make
sure you really prioritize daily
connection.
Welcome [music] to the Midlife Chrysalis
podcast with Chip Connley, where we
explore how midlife isn't a [music]
crisis, but a chrysalis, a time of
profound transformation that can lead to
the most meaningful chapter of your
life.
Welcome to the midlife crysis and this
is Chip Connley. Blake McCausski has
been a friend of mine for about a
decade, probably a little bit more than
that. Um, we first met, I think a dozen
years ago when I was on my festival
kick. I was studying festivals, going to
festivals, and Blake was sort of
noticing what I was doing and saying
like, "Damn, that's a great job. That's
like the most interesting person in the
world kind of job, Chip."
And then over the course of time as he
ultimately uh sold half of his interest
in Tom's shoes
and then started to evolve into other
things, we were able to start comparing
notes a little bit because we both went
through challenging times. My biggest
challenge happened before I ever met
Blake. Um I am gosh 15 16 years older
than Blake. And so in some ways I became
a little bit like his big brother
because I actually I could relate to
what he was going through. You know, the
identity of being a high-profile founder
and CEO and then moving on and then
having some emotional and mental
challenges and a little bit a little bit
of suicidal ideiation. Um all of that
was a bonding experience for me and
Blake because in many ways I could be
his support having gone through some of
the things he was going through. So this
is a deep emotional and you know really
important uh episode especially for
those of you who are dealing with
friends or or your own life and you're
addressing depression and um other
issues that uh deserve love and care.
Hope you enjoy it. Blake Macausski
>> Chip Connley [laughter]
>> welcome to my podcast and then soon
after this I'm going to be on your
podcast.
>> We are some efficient human beings. We
are. And you just were teaching at our
campus in Baja, but you're here at the
Santa Fe campus of MEA. Um,
>> I had a great week last week. It was it
was so nice. I mean, just the group was
small as 12 people. So, it was very
intimate. People just day one got super
vulnerable, which is to me every
vulnerable.
>> I got very vulnerable and uh just the
connection was awesome and uh we had a
great time. We missed you. That was my
first time to teach without you there
next to me. I know.
>> So, it's like I I've gone off, you know,
you sent me off into the wild.
>> You're good. I think I think you're I
think you're just
>> But I missed you, but it was good.
>> Well, I I'm glad we get to spend some
time together here.
>> Me, too. So, boy, there's a lot to talk
about and I didn't even script uh
today's episode because I just felt like
we have a lot to talk about regarding
midlife, regarding
identity, regarding mental and emotional
health, regarding entrepreneurship. So,
let's first dive in. For those who don't
know the Blake McCauski story, give us
the short version of
what led you to creating Tom's and then
you know what happened after you sold
50% interest in Tom's?
>> Yeah. Well, I mean what what started
Tom's was um I'd been an entrepreneur
since I was 18. A lot of people don't
know that. I dropped out of college
because I started a laundry business
called Easy Laundry. Uh, I ran that for
a number of years. Then I got tired of
doing people's clothes every day for a
living and moved into the outdoor
advertising business and then I started
an online driver's ed company. Then I
started a television network. I was the
youngest person next to Ted Turner to
ever start a cable network. Uh, and it
was called re called Reality Central.
And the reason I started that was that
was when we had the huge reality TV
craze. And my sister and I were on a
reality show called The Amazing Race.
And so we raced around the world for 31
days and after 31 days we lost a million
dollars by four minutes.
>> Oh no.
>> I mean, but yeah, but it turned out
okay. But I think what that led to was
me seeing like what it felt like to have
the 15 minutes of fame and that there
was so much extra potential from the
reality stars and reality shows that
wasn't being kind of monetized by the
networks because they would move on to
the next show. And so I partnered with
the founder of the e channel and we
started this channel called reality
central and uh ultimately we got crushed
by Rupert Murdoch and Fox because they
came out with Fox reality and they
obviously had much deeper pockets. So
that business failed.
>> You introduced like like famous reality
TV stars like that guy the naked guy
Richard from Survivor. Was he part of
this?
>> Yeah, he was. So we do is what we do is
we would buy the the second runs of
Survivor and then we would have Richard
Hatch host it like almost like a mystery
dinner theater. So he would be like so
this is why I really screwed over that
lady was so that I could get her off the
show and then take you know get this
person to my alliance and people loved
it. Like when we did the pilots people
thought it was so cool because they got
the inner workings. Yeah. And we could
buy the content for nothing because they
had there was no other market for it. It
was one of those situations and it's a
great business. It's probably one of the
greatest business lessons I ever learned
and it actually informed how I built
Tom's and that is I don't ever want to
be in a business where there's only five
or six decision makers in the world that
that basically choose your fate. So what
happened is we had amazing programming
that the advertisers wanted to advertise
on because we were reaching that 18 to
34 demographic. We had tons of people
wanting this content. People were
obsessed with reality television then.
But what the only way that people are
going to see this content is if we could
get deals done with, you know, Time
Warner Cable, Chartered, Direct TV, all
the cable operators. They're like at
that time they're like six or seven in
the country. They didn't need a new
channel. They have 400 channels. So they
had no economic incentive to really add
us to their lineup. Even though their
customers wanted it and advertisers were
going to spend money on it. And so that
business, we went bankrupt. It was my my
most public failure. Uh it was painful.
I was 27
when it went at under. We were we were
we we were at it for about 3 years. But
what I learned was I'm never going to
start a business where my fate is in so
few hands. Yes.
>> Because if you don't get those seven
people, you're out of business. Whereas
when I started Tom's, you know, I could
sell to thousands of mom and pop
boutiques,
>> you know, and then I could also sell the
big ones like Nordstrom's. But you could
really focus on all these small ones
first and if 10 said no it didn't matter
because there were 10 more down the
road.
>> So talk about Tom's.
>> Yeah. So Tom's Tom started so I I had
had the failure of u reality central
which was pretty painful and then um I
during that failure I had the idea for a
online driver's ed company and then that
was kind of moving along and I decided
to take a little break because that was
a kind of a it was the first online
driver's ed company and it was full
startup mode and I was exhausted once we
launched. So, I went down to Argentina
to take a little vacation. And when I
was there, I was staying at this like uh
polo camp. I was learning to play horse
polo, which a lot of people don't
realize, but that was one of the reasons
I went. And that's how I met my original
partner, Allejo. And um on the way from
the city to the polo farms, we had to
drive through some really like tough
neighborhoods, like some really
impoverished parts of rural Argentina.
and there were all these kids on the
streets and you know and they didn't
have shoes and it just they didn't look
like they're in good shape. And so when
I asked one of the people, you know, why
aren't these kids in school? They
explained that
the families didn't have enough money
for the school fees and also for the
uniforms which were required and shoes
was part of the uniform. That's why they
didn't have shoes. And so um there was
this shoe that all the farmers and kind
of gauchos were wearing uh called the
Apriata. And I bought a pair like in the
I think the grocery store, you know, not
fancy at all. And I started wearing them
and I loved them. And so I just one day
had this idea sitting on the farm before
Polo practiced. And I said, you know, to
Alleo, I said, "What if like we sold
these shoes in the States?" And every
time we sold one of these, we could
afford because they're cheap to make, we
could afford to give one to one of the
kids in this area so they could go to
school and have the proper uniform. And
it would be called the Tomorrow's Shoes
Project. It wasn't even a business. It
was like it was the first time in my
life when I thought of something and I
did not think of a way to monetize it at
all. I And this is so interesting,
right? Like so I had you didn't think
about monetizing it. Didn't think of a
business. It's going to be the tomorrow
shoes project. Every time we sell one,
we'll give one away. And we made 180
pairs in this guy's garage. I mean,
literally handmade them, brought them
back in like one duffel bag. And I was
going to sell them to my friends and
then go back at Christmas and give 200
kids a pair of shoes. And that's how we
started. And and it's funny, everyone
asked like, why is it called Tom's? That
was probably the next question. And so
we were calling them tomorrow shoes. And
then when we were trying to create the
little tag that would go on the back of
the shoe, tomorrow's wouldn't fit. And
[clears throat] so like just not in the,
you know, very impromptu decision. I was
like, let's just call them Tom's. That
that fits. We put Tom's on the label.
And uh we said, if you buy a pair today,
we'll give away a pair tomorrow. And
then Tom's shoes. And then, you know,
people have been calling me Tom ever
since. Were you the first to do the one
for one? So, no one else had done that
yet. The idea the idea that you buy
something and you in essence in the
process of buying your your your
investing in whomever is going to be
getting the shoes.
>> Yeah. And what's interesting is we
didn't even think like we even call it
one for one. Like later people were
like, "Oh, that's one for one." And we
realized, "Oh, that's good. Let's
trademark that." You know, and we just
that's just what we did. We're selling a
pair so we can give a pair. you know, we
weren't even thinking about making money
or anything. It was just like, let's
just like sell enough so we can give
these shoes away. And then later as the
business grew and the cost went down and
we were like, oh wow, we can make a lot
of money and do this still. And then
that's when we were like, and the whole
model is one for one. And then, you
know, that became our thing and you
know, then so many other businesses did
it after, which was great. It was a hell
of a ride.
>> So it grew really quickly. the fastest
growing shoe company in the world for
four years, beating Nike, Converse. I
mean, it went, when we say quickly, I
mean, we went from zero
>> to 700 million in sales in seven years.
>> And so much of that was because you were
a master at PR, right? I mean, you knew
you had a great story and you knew you
were very telegenic. you were like
somebody people just said, "Oh, I want
to invest in that company because I I
like him." Well, no, I mean, it's has
nothing to do with looks or anything
like that. Still a good-looking guy, but
it had a lot to do with just the sense
like this guy's got charisma and he's
got he's got values, a values driven
business. The product's affordable. It
made people feel good. And so, you know,
at some point then you decide that
you're going to sell uh a portion of the
business to Bang Capital. You know, who
knew that they were into the shoe
business.
And what was that like? What was the
process like of
your identity having been the face Yeah.
>> of this company and then all of a
sudden, you know, you're still the face
for a little while, but you're starting
to ease yourself out of this. And you
know what was was there an abyss?
>> It's interesting the the selling 50% to
Bane and in the process of that bringing
on like an incredible CEO. That part was
amazing. A lot of people get this part
of the story wrong. So I'm glad we're
talking about it. Bane was an incredible
partner. I had so much fun just being
the founder for those years and not
having the day-to-day pressure of being
the CEO. And I had the the the, you
know, financial freedom that I had never
had before. So I was much more relaxed.
Those years were great. It was towards
the end of that period when no matter
what we did and we worked really hard to
kind of really turn around the business
because the business started going you
know we the sales started declining and
it wasn't because of Bane it wasn't
because the CEO it was just that you
can't be cool forever you know when
you're making a single shoe you know
fashion comes in and out and so um after
I sold the business that the timing just
wasn't good for for the second half of
it and it it was really hard and it was
hard to see because I really thought
when I sold to Bane, we were going to be
able to do all these other things and
other categories and we were looking at,
you know, Tom's water and all these
different things with the one for one
model. But because the business was
shrinking in the shoes, we had to put
all our attention there. So, it kind of
stopped becoming fun. Not for any reason
of my partners, it's just that, you
know, the the market got really tough.
But what really got hard was at the end
of that cycle was when then another
group came in and and bought it and took
over. And then it was time for me to
step aside and let them do it because
the business really was challenged. And
that's when I was in the abyss because
>> And when was that? How long how long
ago?
>> That was um gosh that was 200 like
18ish. So yeah. So now we're Yeah. Seven
years ago. Eight years ago. And that
really, you know, was the beginning of
my verse depressive experiences. And I
think that I look back now and it was
one, I no longer had my community
because so many of my friends were
people I worked with at Tom's. I didn't
have purpose anymore because I didn't
have something I was waking up every day
like excited to work on or a challenge.
And what I thought was my dream of
moving to the mountains turned out to
not be good for my mental health because
it got dark at 5:00 p.m. you know half
of the year.
>> And this was in Jackson
>> and this is in Jackson Hall. So even I
was living in my dream house in the
mountains
>> um between not having purpose, not
having community and getting dark. I
started experiencing uh depression for
the first time.
>> So So let's that's that's the primary
thing we're going to talk about here. I
mean a lot of people are interviewing
you and they want to get just into the
entrepreneurial story but
>> yeah the first part of this has already
been told many times. It has been and
and you know having Tony Shay wrote two
of the forwards for two of my books and
I have a lot of friends who have who are
entrepreneurs who have been challenged
including some who've taken their own
lives and so talk about what that was
like Blake you know you're the golden
boy and like you know you've made a good
lot of money and you you know you've got
the outward trappings of a life that
everybody is dreaming of and And you
know, inside it's you're getting darker
and darker. What what were what were the
initial signs of a mental and emotional
health crisis that was starting to
arise?
>> I knew I was going to be emotional being
here. So, um, so after I after I exited
Tom's and I was in Jackson and I started
feeling depression around the winter
time, I think closely related to it
getting dark earlier. I think I panicked
in some ways because I um I didn't want
to feel that way and I never felt that
way you know I mean you say golden boy I
mean my you know my we joke that my
parents call me the golden child like
like I I I really lived this big larger
than life and really connected life and
beautiful life and then I started to
feel depression and I didn't know what
to do because I'd never experienced it.
I did what probably a lot of people do
who have a bunch of money and that is
like okay I'm gonna spend my way out of
this like what can I do to distract
myself from these bad feelings and so
built some crazy house went on
ridiculous vacations like you know
started collecting classic cars like
anything climbing mountains racing cars
I mean I did it all I mean I literally
tried everything when I say when it
comes to what to external I got divorced
I got remarried I got divorced again I
mean I made a total mess of my personal
life.
>> Would you have called this a midlife
crisis? Would or does that just like
does that feel way too cliche um for
what you were going through?
>> I think that feels too cliche for what I
was going through. It was ironically
during my midlife and we'll talk about
the happiness index and all that because
I could be my face could be at the
bottom of that the exact year
but it but it was but the one thing it
was is it wasn't hap it wasn't severe
yet and it was cyclical. So I'd kind of
like go through a hard season, then I'd
find some new hobby in the spring, you
know, find new some new thing to focus
on and and then I'd kind of feel good
through the spring and summer and the
fall and then we'd come again. And this
put a lot of strain on my first
marriage. And after about four or so
years, um it did so much strain that I
got divorced
and and I started having bigger swings
of these periods. By the way, during
that time, um, I came down to visit you
in Cabo and you were you were go you
were golfing naked. Um, if I if I'm not
mistaken,
>> that might have been the midlife crisis.
>> Yeah. Um, you did some golfing naked on
on the course and I could feel the
strain of you and and your and your now
your your ex Heather
and also I could feel a little bit and
this was before it got really bad. I
could feel this sense that Blake was
seek searching for something.
>> I was searching hard. Yeah. Yeah. And I
searched really hard but I was mainly
searching outside of myself like looking
back now I was really looking for what
can what who's what teacher what guru
what psychedelic can I take like
anything like you know and and so it was
like that for four or five years and
then about three years ago and one of
the things I did to try to feel better
is I moved my you know girlfriend at the
time my e ex-wife and my kids all to
Costa Rica and learn to become a great
surfer. And that actually was pretty
like
cathartic in a way or numbing maybe
depending on how you look at it because
I was surfing all day every day then
with the kids in the afternoon after
school and that kind of worked for a
while and then in when that stopped
working is when we moved back or moved
to California went to the bay but when I
got to the bay is when it really got bad
because now I didn't have surfing I
didn't have my community again and
didn't still didn't have purpose I was
also at that time put on a bunch of
pharmaceuticals I was misdiagnosed as
being bipolar. And so then I was totally
numb from these mood stabilizers and
antiscychotics they had me on. So I
found myself basically three years ago
living in in the Bay. Um and I started
downward spiraling and I started getting
so dark that I would get out of bed. I
wouldn't call my friends back. I
completely isolated. Uh and then the
worst part of it was I started getting
really suicidal. And that was just like
I mean I think back of those times and
now it's like a movie. I mean I can't
even imagine that I was the lead in cuz
I would just wake up and I couldn't get
that thought out of my head of like I
don't want to be here anymore. I my best
days are behind me. I'm totally trapped.
There's no way I can get out of I can
never redeem myself from the personal
you know mess that I've made of my life.
like you know my kids are going to I
mean every negative thing anyone has
ever said to themsself I said to myself
all day every day and as you know like
physicality has been a big part of my
life surfing doing things like I didn't
want to surf I didn't want to work out I
didn't eat healthy I started drinking a
lot and it was just not my thing at all
never been a thing for me so I was like
you know having a couple beers starting
at like 3:00 in the afternoon basically
until I could go to sleep
>> and you were on medication during this
And you were also doing psychedelics.
>> No, no psychedelics during this time.
>> Okay. Okay. So, you're on heavy
medication. I was texting you. We were
talking. Um, you actually came here a
couple years ago before we actually
opened and and you even said to me
earlier today here on the rants that you
you you're a you're so foggy about that
period of your life. Yeah.
>> You don't even remember it all that
well.
>> I remember coming. It's funny. I was
telling some people earlier this morning
like I remember coming here cuz I was
just like Chip I just I just got to get
out of the house and I got to just I
just want to come talk and walk and we
did but I don't even remember it much of
it. Like I just remember like it was
like a nice day to get out of San
Francisco for the day and just have a
reprieve from all the pressure I was
feeling at home. If you're enjoying the
conversations we've been having on the
midlife crystis, I have a valuable offer
for you to consider. My book, Learning
to Love Midlife: 12 Reasons Why Life
Gets Better with Age, is a national
bestseller. And right now, you can get a
copy for just the cost of shipping. It
offers stories, research, and practices
to help [music] you move from a midlife
crisis to a midlife catalyst. And see
this stage of life not as a decline, but
an opportunity to flourish. Claim your
copy today at
meawwisdom.com/midlifebook.
>> So,
who is helping you during that time? Um,
>> beside yourself.
>> I was I was
>> Oh, but I mean in seriousness like I I'm
so grateful and I mean there's one
message that I would love to share is if
someone's listening to this and they're
really suffering like the most important
thing you can do is to tell some people
about it. you know, because I thankfully
for whatever my soul knew that I could
not keep this alone when once it started
getting really bad. I isolated a lot and
didn't tell a lot of people until it got
to the place where it was really dark.
And then I, you know, say, "Hey, can I
FaceTime you, Chip?" And we'd say,
"Yeah, call me on Tuesday." And we would
do a FaceTime and I don't remember what
we talked about, but we did. And then
I'd come here. Or I'd have a friend come
up, you know, and we'd go hike in Mir
Woods. And I even though I was a shell
of myself, at least I was telling people
like I'm suffering. Like make sure I'm
going to be okay. And that was um and
that to me still is the thing that
really is the difference between me
being above ground today and not because
I've lost some friends to suicide now.
And it's so sad. And this only common
denominator I see is that everyone in
their life was like I never knew it was
as bad as that, you know, but in my life
people knew because I was saying like I
am not in a good place. I am not myself.
And so I think just talking about it is
something that truly can be life-
saving.
>> You made over time a shift from the
pharmaceut pharmaceuticals. you did some
plant medicine
>> and you did some other kinds of um both
physiological and and therapeutic um
treatments. What what worked for you?
>> I did a ton of things and that's and
that's actually my podcast that you're
going to be on later is called No Magic
Pill because what I realized is there
was no one path to me getting back on
track. like there were so many things
that all kind of helped in incremental
ways and I think that when you are
really depressed you're hoping that
there's going to be a magic pill but I
just don't think that there is and so
some of the things that worked really
great that I would recommend
specifically for suicide out let's say
start there ketamine treatment amazing
because it somehow just knocks you out
of it you have such an out-of body
disassociative experience with you know
the cosmos universe whatever you want to
call it that when you come out, you just
have a calmness. It's almost like you've
seen death in a way and then you're and
you but you're still alive and it is an
incredible agent that we have available
to us now. You know, it's legal in the
United States. So, I would say that's a
great first line of defense. I highly
highly recommend that. Now, ketamine has
also become abused um you know,
recreationally. You have to be very
careful. But, you know, with a clinic,
with a practitioner, great idea if you
know or someone in your life is
suicidal. The second thing is
transmagnetic stimulation.
>> Explain that one.
>> Yeah. So, uh I will do my best. Um
basically, um this was actually invented
in like the 70s, but um it was they have
a magnet that they do an fMRI on your
brain. They can see where there's
certain neurons that are not firing and
that should be firing. So, think of like
a muscle that has atrophy. So, because
those aren't firing, you're not getting
the release of the positive hormones
that you need to not be depressed. And
so when they see depressed people, a lot
of this area is not firing. So they're
basically going to stimulate it with a
magnet. Almost like remember those
cheesy ads where they had the little
electropads on the abs. Yeah. And you
have them like in the Sky Mall magazine.
Like if you just shock your abs, you're
going to have abs like Have you seen
those?
>> It's a way to get a six-pack. Yes.
Right. I I never tried. I don't didn't
know if it works. But that idea is what
they were doing. So if they shock that
part of your brain enough, they kind of
wake it up and then that gets you
potentially out of that.
>> So it's stiffer than electric
electroshock therapy though. I mean
>> very
because that's something from Yeah. And
I never think that's like one flew over
the cuckoo.
>> Yeah. And I thankfully never got that
desperate. I thought about it though
like I actually it was on my list of
things to try. Okay. Okay. But it was
luckily that but this is and so TMS for
many many years you had to go for 15
minutes a day for 60 days straight. So
you had to literally live like right
next to the hospital and you're in kind
of a huge part of your life. So this
amazing uh doctor Nolan Williams
unfortunately who has passed recently
which is so sad because he was a friend
and my doctor um he invented this thing
called the Saint protocol and he figured
out how to do 60 days and five days but
10 hours a day of this. So not not the
most pleasant experience of your life. I
mean, you're just like all you want to
do is sleep because it's so exhausting,
but you get 10 minutes of stimulation,
40-minute rest, 10 minutes of
stimulation, and it is also it is has
miraculous results for people who are
suicidal, getting them out of it. Um,
some people they'll do it once and
they'll never be depressed day in their
life like like like truly magic. Some
people like me, it helped me for about 3
months and then I had to do it again.
Um, so it kind of like tur it kind of
like um almost like a car battery. It
got it going, but my battery still
needed to be replaced by all the
internal healing and therapy and stuff,
but then when the battery went dead
again, it got it going again. So those
were two things I would say in terms of
if you're if you're suicidal I would say
in terms of other stuff that I did and
the thing that really had the most
transformative effect for me was I
started doing a lot of deep therapy and
really kind of looking at every kind of
decade of my life and and really trying
to understand you know like where did
certain feelings come from and and and
and in doing that my therapist asked me
if I wanted to do a psychedelic journey
with them. And I had done IA and Iane
and a lot of big psychedelics when I was
feeling great. And they were amazing for
making me feel more connected to people,
more of a steward of the environment,
me, you know, even kind of knowing how I
can be a better dad. But I wasn't able
to do psychedelics when I was on all the
pharmaceuticals, right? And so after I
got off all the pharmaceuticals, which
was a whole another thing we
>> And you went to program for that. Yeah.
>> In Sedona called Alternative to Med
Center, which was amazingly one of the
reasons I'm also here. I got off all
those. I did a a light San Pedro drink
and San Pedro comes from the cactus. A
lot of Native American, you know, First
Nation peoples have used this for a long
time. And we used a very light dose. And
this is what I think is really
interesting is like it was not some huge
psychedelic journey. It was a light dose
where I was totally with it, totally
conscious, but it really they say it's a
heart opener. It really opened my heart
and with my eyes closed and some light
music and the guidance of my therapist
on his couch in Sedona, I was able to
hear [snorts] some messages that I had
never really heard before. And were
these messages from God? Were they from
my inner child? Were they from myself?
Who knows? But the medicine opened up
this big realization. And this is the
thing that kind of really changed
everything for me. And that was that um
my whole life my suffering had come from
a core wound. And the core wound was
that I never felt that I was enough. And
so I was able to go back with him and
see different experiences in my life,
some bullying, some conversations that
were really challenging when I was young
that that made me not feel enough. And
that and what this message told me was
until I really heal that I was never
going to escape this constant pressure
and these cyclical depressive episodes.
That was like just the most profound
experience I had. It didn't heal me, but
it gave me the awareness of where is all
this coming from. And that I think is
was such a gift. And from that, I
started a real healing journey. And that
was in January. So not that long ago. J
>> and we're talking about January of 2025.
>> So yeah, so a year ago basically is when
I had that. And then from that
realization with my therapist and and
medicine doctor, we create a whole
program to how I could retrain my uh my
neuropathways,
get rid of this limiting self-belief,
which is I know something you guys talk
a lot about at Modern Elder and and it
was the beginning of this healing
journey I've been on for the last nine
months.
>> So what does it mean to you about I am
not enough? Because for me, I I say, you
know, I I take a shower as as most
people do every morning. I stack some
habits. I I I say three prayers. I say
the serenity prayer,
>> the St. Francis prayer, and the seventh
step 12step prayer. The seventh step
prayer in the 12step program. And then I
say six mantras three times each. But
some of my mantras relate to what we're
talking about here. Two of my mantras
are, I'm lovable for who I am, not what
I do. And I don't have to prove that I'm
lovable. I have something special to
share with you later.
>> Okay. Does do those sound sound familiar
to you?
>> Totally. Yeah. Very familiar.
>> Talk a little bit more about what does
it mean to feel I'm not enough or I have
to go prove that I'm enough.
>> Yeah. So, I think what's interesting is
so much of this is at the subconscious
level. And so, when you talk about
mantras, that was the first thing that
really helped me heal. So, he actually
gave me this mala. He made it for me,
handmade it when I was with him. and and
he said, "Uh, for the next 40 days, when
you wake up in the morning, before you
get out of bed, you're going to set your
phone for a 20-minute timer, and you're
going to put one hand on one bead, and
you're going to close your eyes. You're
going to say, "I am enough." And then
you're going to put the hand on the next
bead, and you're going to say, "I've
always been enough. I am enough. I've
always been enough." And you do that for
20 minutes in the morning and then 20
minutes before you go to bed for 40
days. And Chip, when I started it, I
hated it. I was like, "This is so silly.
Like, I'm still depressed. How is this
going to help me? Like, I I don't think
I'm not enough. What do you like?" And
now that I was outside of the the
medicine open heart, I was kind of
closed off again. Like, I'm fine. Like,
I don't need to do this. And like, I but
I was still suffering so much that I was
desperate to to to heal this. And I
really trusted this man. Like, I really
said like, "I'm putting my hands my life
in your hands." And so I, you know,
second week goes by, I'm still not
enjoying it. On day 28, and it's funny,
we had, we talked about this so much at
the retreat last week at MEA that our
group was going to be called the 28th
day, but we we changed the name. But on
the 20th day, it was like magic
happened. I just I woke up that day. I
started doing it. The 20 minutes felt
like it was went by in two minutes. And
then later that day, I was walking
around different. I was not feeling
pressure. I was not like beating myself
up for my divorce or whatever. And I
just started feeling more like myself or
even like a self that I hadn't felt like
since I was a kid. And then that night I
was excited to do it. So I did again 29
day, 30-day. And honestly by the 40th
day I my I was not having that limiting
belief hardly at all or if at all. I was
feeling so much like myself and and I
was so excited to like share this. But
at the same time when I was really
suffering I had committed to going to
India because one of my friends who also
had a very near case with suicidality
what got him out of it was this amazing
pilgrimage he took to India and this
program he did at this ashram. So when I
was really suffering I called him one
day and he's like just promise me you
won't do something that's irreversible
until you go to India. And I was like
when can I go? He's like the next
program is stop for six months. And I
was like oh my gosh. He's like, "So, I
have to make it six months." He's like,
"You have to make it six months." And
so, even though I was feeling better
after doing this mantra and really
working on this limiting belief, I still
went to India. And in India is where the
healing really solidified. And and I
really started realizing what I am
enough means is that I am enough. You
are enough. We are enough. This moment
is enough. And it and and like I don't
need to there's nothing else I can add
to this moment to make it any more
enough. like like and I started
connecting to like like you talked about
the birds this morning just the birds
the fact that these birds are chirping
and singing is like is that's all I need
today like you know and I started seeing
how to was like the greatest you know
kind of greatest you know for someone
who doesn't feel enough it was like the
greatest solution but it was temporary
and it was external and it wasn't s I
couldn't source it every single day and
so um in India I really saw that that
this was the way I wanted to live like
this is this was true freedom for the
first time in maybe my life since I was
a little kid I really felt free and then
when I was in India I also realized that
I'm not the only person that feels this
way like this is like a cultural
sickness unfortunately with all the
compariveness because of social media
all the pressure that so many kids are
receiving from their parents because how
competitive things have gotten with
digging into schools to you know just
capitalism in general like at telling us
we need something to be enough, you
know, and I saw that that was and it was
very clear to me. It was like kind of
like the Tom's day. It was that when I
had the idea for Tom's, it's like you
need to go back and you need to create
an organization to help people feel
enough and to show them that there's so
much freedom with this single
foundational feeling. And I didn't know
what I was going to do or how I was
going to do it. But I came back to from
India being determined to use my
suffering and make sense of my suffering
by creating an initiative that would
help other people maybe not suffer in
that way.
>> And you're launching this initiative.
Um, and let's talk about it. And there's
a little box here on the table.
>> Yeah, the box. I'll let you open it. So,
but but before you do, before you do, I
want to it's it's really cool how so
many important people in my life have
been there at the right time. So I get
back from uh from India and I'm telling
my best friend John who's a clothing
designer and he was also our eyewear
designer at Tom's. I was telling him the
idea and I was like I just want to find
a way to take this message out there and
a way to have like this daily reminder
that I could have every day that I am
enough and that and I can share it with
other people. And we're sitting there
and he looked at my wrist and he goes,
"Do a bracelet." And I'm like, "What do
you mean a bracelet?" He's like, "You've
always worn bracelets. I mean, ever
since I known you before it was cool
like and 20 years ago and there you got
them from Argentina and Guatemala. You
give shoes to kids in Cambodia to bring
back a bracelet and you've always you've
given bracelets away for your 40th
birthday to all of us. Like we've all
had bracelets because of you. Then do a
bracelet. And I was like, you're right.
It could be like my daily reminder. So
we actually made this bracelet in India.
It's hand beaded with these glass beads
and it says enough on it. And the idea
is you wear it as a daily reminder. So
every day when I kind of see it, it's
like my reminder like take a breath, do
the mantra, whether it's in the shower,
whatever. I am enough. I've always been
enough. But as importantly, it's
something that we can give to others to
share this message. And so as so I he
gave me the idea, we started making the
bracelets, I started wearing one myself,
but the best part about the idea came a
little bit later when we thought, let's
not sell the bracelet by itself. If you
want to buy one for yourself, you have
to buy one to give to someone else.
Yeah. So, yeah. So,
>> let's open this up. Okay. So, it's a new
one for
>> says you are enough uh on the front and
then you've got one for you and one to
give and they say enough. And 100% of
the profits go to mental health
organizations. They're transforming and
saving lives every day. Um the URL is we
are enough.org.
And there's actually a little statement
from you or actually it's a letter from
you. And let's let you read this.
>> Yeah. So this is what I was so excited
to read to you, Chip, as I give you a
bracelet. So I'm going to give you a
bracelet. This is a ritual that we do.
Hand out your hands. Open, please. Okay.
So put it on here.
And
I am enough. For those who are who are
not watching this uh and just listening,
I am now enough. I am enough. enough
given grace. And now the ritual really
is this poem. So this poem was written
by the great poet. Do you know InQ?
>> Oh my god. Yes. My friend Kevin used to
actually
>> uh be the agent for ENQ.
>> Okay. So ENQ's real name is Adam. He's
been a dear friend of mine forever. He
was also one of those people that knew
what I was going through. And when I
told Adam about this, I said, "Look, we
want to be able to give the bracelet to
someone, but not everyone's going to
know the right words to say." you know,
because you might be giving this to
someone who's suffering, but you might
be giving to someone who's always helped
you feel enough and you're thanking
them. And so, help me have the perfect
words to say that I could either, you
know, read to them or even just hand
them. So, when you get the box, the poem
is in there, the inc's written, but
there's also an envelope with another
copy of it. So, if you want to, you
know, send it in the mail to someone,
you can send them the bracelet. But
here's here's the way we officially give
the bracelet. Now, you bet it's on your
wrist. Chip, I see you. the you behind
the you. Not for anything you've done or
anything you're gonna do. I don't stop
to say it enough, but I believe in you.
And if you could see yourself from my
view, you'd believe it, too. That's why
I'm giving you the gift that I'm
receiving, too. A message to remind you
when you're lost or feeling blue. A
mantra to repeat when times are tough.
Because no matter who we are, we are
always enough.
It's a silent prayer I'm sending for the
world's mental health. I wear the symbol
for myself and now is a bond to someone
else. It's a blessing in a gentle push
to never give up because no matter who
you are, you are enough.
>> Oh my god, this is like Dr. Seuss for
mental health. I love that. Um, so this
is a it's a for-profit venture that's
really not a for-profit venture.
>> It's a nonprofit.
>> And so the way it works is We Are Enough
is a nonprofit. 100% of the profits go
to mental health organizations in order
to sell bracelets at retail and stuff.
We have a for-profit that's owned by the
nonprofit, but 100% of the profits go to
mental health organizations that we say
are transforming and saving lives every
day. So, some of the organizations are
really helping in crisis and some of
them are helping people don't get to
crisis because there's so many people
that you and I know and that you you
serve every day at MEA. They're just
really dissatisfied with life and often
midlife. And so, there's organizations
that are trying to get in the front of
that to help people with their mental
health as well, not just ones that are
serving people in crisis. But, you know,
I I think we're going to raise millions
and millions of dollars with this. Like,
I'm so fired up. Well, I think, you
know, the times are such that it's
needed. I mean, the mental health crisis
that we're in at all ages, especially
young people. Um, we are doing our first
MEA workshop uh for millennial
exclusively millennials and and Gen Z,
partly because the the U curve of
happiness, which we alluded to earlier,
which had which showed frankly between
45 and 50 is the low point and 47. Yeah.
Right. Right. your exact age when you
were at the lowest point. I mean I
literally exact point
>> what's happened now is that frankly
younger people who are 18 to 25 are have
a a level of life satisfaction that's
lower than that and and so looking for
new ways to help people uh to deal with
a world in which
some of the kinds of support that we
used to have whether it was the church
and I know you you're a religious guy
and you you were a big fan of Richard
Roar uh one of our faculty members
There's
it does feel like there's a real need
for in society for us to create new uh
safety nets for people. Yeah, I mean
that's the thing and that's why several
of the organizations that we're making
donations to with the sale of the
bracelets are are working in high
schools because I really have started to
see that this feeling of wholeness. You
know, really knowing that you are enough
at your core is almost kind of like the
foundation of mental health because so
many of things, let's talk about
addictions. Like if you talk to people
in the addiction, you know, community,
so many of the addictions start because
people don't feel enough. They're trying
to fill something up. They need to feel
something more than just who they are.
And so that and then and then so many of
whether it's depression or anxiety, it
all kind of starts with this feeling of
not doing enough. So if we can get in in
the high school level and get in early
and create opportunities and programming
so people can really understand how
important it is to source this from
within, then I hope that we're, you
know, ace a, you know, we are at least
contributing to the solution of the
mental health crisis that we find
ourselves in. I went to my high school
the other day. It was cool. went back
for the first time in 30 years to share
this message to give out some of the
first bracelets and it was like one of
the most powerful experiences of my
life. I mean hearing these kids' stories
and and and I mean they were so open
with their stories and then I one of my
favorites was I the one of the girls got
the box and she put the bracelet on and
and there were all her friends around
and I'm like well who you going to give
it to? She goes I'm going to give it to
my dad tonight. He's been struggling. he
will never admit it, but I think he's
been depressed for 10 years and he is
more than enough." And I was like, "Wow,
I wish I could go home and see that
experience." Can you imagine her reading
the poem to her dad, you know, like I
mean, it was just so powerful. And so, I
think what we're, you know, hoping is
that we will be the catalyst for some
conversations and and experiences that
really transform relationships because,
as you know, it's all about our
relationships in our community. But in
doing that, we'll give people that daily
reminder. And we'll also, you know, what
I'm also excited about is like, let's
imagine you're in line at Starbucks and
you're wearing your bracelet and then
there's some, you know, 22-year-old, you
know, woman's wearing her bracelet.
Normally, you would have no reason to
say hi to her or talk to her or
whatever. And you might say, "Hey, how's
your day going? I got one, too." you
know, and so that's that I'm hoping that
that are some of the things that
happened which we saw very much in the
early days of Tom's when two people were
wearing Tomms and not everyone knew
about it yet because if we can create
more of those just little touch points
and connections and kind of like I got
your back I think that's going to be
really cool.
>> I'm looking for the etm I'm going I'm
doing chat GBT while we're doing this.
The etmology of the word enough it comes
from
the meaning it's geno I don't know what
it's a it's an old English word um and
it's means sufficient adequate plenty uh
it's derived from sufficient and
abundant there's a Germanic element to
it
and
the poetic reflection about it is it
means to have re reached sufficiency
you're sufficient.
>> It's interesting. I'm glad you brought
that up. So, one of our mental health
adviserss is this amazing woman named
Kristen Nef. Have you had her on the
podcast?
>> No. She's I'd like to get on the
Introduce us.
>> Okay. She's amazing. So, she wrote this
book, Self-Compassion, which is
incredible. So, she joined the Enough
team, I don't know, maybe a month ago,
and she was one of the people I really
wanted to get on. We also have had Young
PBLO join as one of our adviserss. So,
we have a great team. And she said,
'Blake, one thing you have to do when
you tell people about this is when you
hear people talking about like enough
being like, "Oh, it's sufficient."
They're going to think, "Well, if I'm
enough, I won't be a high performer
anymore. Like, I won't have motivation.
I won't have drive. Like, like I don't
know if I just want to be enough. I want
to be more than enough, you know?" And
she said, she said, "You've got to tell
them about this study I did." So, she
did this study with NCAA athletes and
she basically took half of them that
have that hard inner critic that's
constantly like you can't miss a shot or
like don't miss this or you got to win
this game or like all this pressure that
they think is keeping them, you know,
training hard and performing hard to
replacing that with what they would call
the inner coach. It'd be someone of
self-compassion. It' be someone say, you
know, you're not defined by the fact
that you lost that game like really
gentle. What she found was is the inner
critic is actually keeping athletes and
executives from one of the most
important states we can enter and that's
flow. So when we're in flow, you know
flow flow from Holly check me high. Mike
took me he and you know his when I was
writing my book emotional equations and
there was a chapter on flow. Mike, who
who was the guy who popularized the idea
of flow, said, "I want you to come up to
Montana with me and my wife and spend
three days in our little cabin and we
can walk along paths along rivers and we
can talk about flow." And I got to do
that for three days with, you know, the
guy who and unfortunately he's passed
away in the past year. But go ahead.
>> So you you know about flow. So what she
said is that with that inner critic or
not feeling enough is actually keeping
you out of flow because you're feeling
pressure and it's very hard to get into
a flow state if you're self-critical or
or or have this pressure. But when you
have self-compassion and you can relax,
that's when you enter the flow state. So
these NCAA athletes actually perform
better because they're able to access
flow better. So it's so important to me
and I'm so glad that she taught me that
because I do think there'll be some
people that hear this message and
they'll say, "Well, this isn't for me."
like I I want to be more than enough.
You know, that's great. Blake feels
enough now, but like but but actually
feeling enough is like a hack to high
performance. And I've noticed that as
I've been building this. So now when I
go to meet with, let's just say, someone
super famous and asking them if they'll
wear the bracelet and share the story.
That was the Tom's days, I would have
had all this pressure. I hope I say the
right thing. I hope they like me. D. And
I would almost come like out of
desperation. Now I'm like, I'm enough.
we're enough. Like if you want to be
part of it, great. If not, that's fine,
too. And that energy now is like a
magnet. Now, everyone seems like they
want to wear a bracelet and be part of
it because I'm in this like flow state
now because I really feel that I'm
enough and it's so cool. I haven't
enjoyed working more ever in my life.
What kind of path are you carving
through midlife? Our free midlife
pathfinder quiz helps you discover which
of eight archetypes best describe your
approach to this stage of life and what
that means for your next chapter. It
only takes a few minutes and your
results may surprise you. Find out your
archetype now. It's quick, it's fun, and
it might help you see your journey in a
whole new light. [music] Take the
Pathfinder quiz at meowwisdom.com/quiz.
[music]
I've witnessed you over the last two,
three years and it's been hard. You
know, it's it's hard to be the friend of
someone who is having suicide ideation.
I had my suicide ideation ideation in my
late 40s. Um, and then I had an NDE,
which you know was really helpful for me
to realize, okay, I can die. I went to
the other side.
So what would what would what advice
would you give to people who have a
spouse, a family member, a friend who's
going through a a deep dark depression?
>> I think the first thing is and it's
interesting because one of my mantras in
life is carpadm and I'm always about
positivity. That is not what to do with
someone who's really depressed. It's not
about telling them carpadm. It's not
telling them that they can get through
this. It's not reminding them how lucky
they are. that is like and unfortunately
I was around some of that and it made me
worse. So my always am first to say is
like it's it's about listening. It's
about holding space. It's about being
you know really
honoring that what they're going through
is no different than someone who just
got in a car accident. It's an invisible
illness you know to so many people. And
so really honoring of like hey like no
we need to get help like let's let's
help you get help as if you just got in
a car accident because your brain is
bleeding out if it's thinking about that
is not natural like there is something
wrong with the wiring and let's get
help. Now help could look a lot of
different ways depends if there's
substance abuse and that's one there's
not substance abuse like in my case I I
didn't have a drug or alcohol problem
but I was on all these pharmaceuticals
that was causing problems let's figure
out the best way to get off that. The
other thing is is really encouraging
them whether it's with you which might
be the person or with other people to be
on a daily basis saying this is how I
feel today. This is this I'm feeling
really bad today. I need to be around
some other people today. And really
treat them as if they're, you know,
recovering from a a major injury because
they are injured. And so I think that's
one of the things that I hope that we
can do through this is like just like
raising awareness of like mental illness
is often invisible and then to really
look out for the signs of it getting
worse. So isolation, another one is
either loss of appetite or eating way
too much. Another one is they stop
enjoying the things they love. like I
went to this the most epic surf break of
all time like during that period around
the time that I came and visited you to
do anything to feel better and I didn't
even want to surf and that's where my
friends are like we got to get you to a
center or somewhere that can like this
is this is beyond our hands and so I I
recognize that I was so blessed because
I had the resources to go to some of
these places uh and a lot of people
don't have that and so it can be really
hard the good news is there's a lot more
online resources that are free that can
help people. But I think the most
important thing is really watch those
signs so you can kind of get ahead of it
to not try to like you know you know
kind of you know positive selft talk
them way out of it and to and to really
just um be there to to be with them as
they think through it. I think there's
another thing I'll say a book that
really really really helped me. Uh, it's
called Thank God for Depression. And it
was written by this guy. I think he's
early 30s. He was like in a punk rock or
not punk rock up. I forget the name how
he would say his brand or his band, but
um I've gotten to know him since then
because I literally thanked him. I was
like, "Your book maybe saved my life."
But this book is really great and it
really helps you understand and almost
kind of self diagnose what where is this
depression come? Is it coming from
you've never felt enough and you put
your whole life on all this pressure and
and you've attracted a relationships
that also trigger that and all these
things like for me or is it you know
something totally different but I think
it's really important to try to
understand you know what is depression
trying to teach me because I really do
see now that depression is and Jim
Carrey says this he talks about like you
know like you know depression is
basically your soul saying I don't want
to play this avatar anymore, you know,
and I really and now I actually can
thank God for my depression because I
see had I not gone through that had I
not I would not have made the changes in
my life to now have the personal
integrity that I now have to now have
purpose to now be able to help people.
Um I had to go through that and so
oftent times it is about helping gently
guide the person if they're in that
state. Now, if they're if they're really
in a bad state, I'm saying ketamine,
TMS, center. But if they're if they're
stable and now they're just heavily
dissatisfied with life, not feeling joy,
you know, really if they can take some
time to like read this book and kind of
go through, okay, really get what what
what is not what is not happening that
should be happening or or what what
decisions have I made that I feel like
I'm trapped, but I'm not really trapped.
That's what I like to also tell people
is you're never really trapped. Like I
mean no matter what your situation,
economics, whatever, like if you you
know you're waking up, you have an
opportunity to make some changes. Now it
might create a lot more pain and and the
pain might be more intense for the short
term. Mine sure was, but then ultimately
um you're never fully trapped.
>> Two last questions.
emotionally
you it's you've been on quite a roller
coaster and you are seemingly in a
really healthy place today and feeling
great about this business this and this
nonprofit.
Do you ever have fear of like, "Oh,
shit."
>> Yes. This is
>> this is gonna come back.
>> Of course. No. I mean, I think that's
Yeah. When if someone who's really
struggled how I have, I think for the
rest of my life, I will have PTSD around
some of those times. Um, that comes up
for sure. And occasionally what that
will be is I'll wake up uh like 3:00 in
the morning and I'll have like a bad
dream that I'm back in there. And then
I'll wake up and I'll not really know if
the dream is real or not. And they'll
have anxiety around it. And what do I
do? I I sit down and I put a hand on a,
you know, thumb to a finger. I'm enough.
Thumb to the next finger. I've always
been enough. And it's simple, but it
just kind of like breaks that pattern or
that negative limiting belief or fear.
But yes, I that comes up and I think
that will come up, you know, the rest of
my life. I mean, I just think that this
is I'm in recovery, you know, in a
sense, just like anyone else. And so I
really have a lot of one day at a time.
And so, and I'm not every day I'm not
going to feel great. And that's okay.
That's that's human. like I should be
anxious sometimes or I should be sad
sometimes or regretful. But what the
difference is now is it doesn't consume
me and then and then take me down the
spiral because I know I mean it sounds
cliche know what I'm doing. I know that
I'm enough. I know that this day is
enough and and my kids are enough and um
and that's the other thing. I mean for
all the parents listening, this has
totally transformed my relationship, my
10-year-old and my 8-year-old. I mean
they feel so much less pressure by me. I
didn't even know I was putting pressure
on them. But when you don't feel enough,
you innately are probably making other
people not feel enough around you. And
so once I started talking, we do this
thing at dinner where we look each other
in the eyes and we say, "I am enough."
And then we put our hand out to each
other, say, "You are enough." And we put
our hugs around each other, say, "We are
enough." And then we eat. That's our
prayer. And we've been doing that now
for six months. And my kids are
thriving. It's amazing. And it's and the
relationship is so cool because I'm not
putting any pressure on them. And I
think if there's any message we want to
give our kids is that they're enough
however they are. So so that's been
that's been really great. So that's one
question you said you had a second one.
>> Last question is normally I ask this but
I think I know your answer already. Um
and that's if someone younger than you
came to you and said Blake give me a
wisdom bumper sticker of
a some kind of distillation of what
you've learned along the way in your
life.
Uh, and the origin story, my guess is it
might be you are enough and the origin
story we've heard, but if there was
another one,
what would be this distillation of the
wisdom you've learned along the way?
What what would you like Blake who
started Tomorrow's Shoes,
>> Tom's shoes, to have known back then
that would have been would have served
you so well and maybe even taken away
some of the the pain and suffering
you've had to have along the way.
>> I think that life is all about
connection and community. It's all about
relationships and finding ways to
connect with people deeply. You know,
I've always enjoyed that about our
relationship because it's never been
talk. It's always been real.
And even when even when it was really
intense and difficult, it was still
real. And now, even though we're both in
great places and I'm feeling so great,
it's very real. I think invest in those
connections and never lose um sight of
how important that is because when I
look at what happened as I started to
get depressed, I think one of the causes
of it was isolation because I was living
in Jackson, no longer had my community.
But then what made it worse was I
further isolated and you know now I'm
connecting with all these people doing
this photography project.
>> Doing a photography project where you're
going around to 78 people and
photographing them as part of a book.
>> Yeah. For my 50th birthday for your 50th
birthday. So,
>> so that's been a great way to reconnect
with people. Now, getting the
opportunity to give the bracelet, read
the poem to strangers, to people. That's
a way to connect. But, yeah, I would say
make sure you really prioritize daily
connection.
>> I love you.
>> I love you, brother.
>> Yeah. Thank you for coming here.
>> Thank you. Yeah,
>> that was awesome.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. We are enough.
>> You're enough. Exactly.
I wish you could have been in the room
with me uh as Blake and I talked because
I could just feel a very palpable sense
of
some of the trauma that he's gone
through, but also the joy he's now
feeling. I want to start by saying um
there's a there's a relatively new
suicide and crisis line just like 911,
but it's 988. So, if you know anybody or
if you are in a a state of distress and
disqu, feeling a sense of emotional
crisis, just call 988. Um, and you'll
get immediate help no matter where you
are in the United States. If you're
outside the United States, there may be
other numbers. Uh, I'm sorry that I just
have the the US number. My takeaways
from my time with Blake
are number one, if you're going through
a very troubled time personally, it
affects everybody around you. And Blake
has had two marriages and kids. And I do
know that one of the biggest challenges
for him in his disqu was the fact that
everybody around him wanted him to get
better, but they couldn't help him get
better. They could just love him as much
as they could. Um, so this idea of like
being there, the the being caregivers
and and social support to people when
they're going through a hard time is
just essential. And uh thankfully uh
Blake got to the other side of it and he
is now he's teaching again at MEA uh
which is wonderful.
But I was there for him during that
time. I was texting with him late at
night sometimes and when he was really
in in the throws of his suicidal
ideiation and I will just say for the
caregivers out there um just know you do
the best you can. The serenity prayer,
which I like to call the wisdom prayer,
is not a bad thing to be saying daily.
You know, God grant me the serenity to
accept the things I cannot change, the
courage to change the things I can, and
the wisdom to know the difference
because when it comes to people who are
going through challenging times, it you
there's some things that you can control
and most you can't. So, all you can do
is just show up and influence people the
best you can. Uh, number two is
getting your meds right. uh Blake
because he was going through a lot and
his doctors didn't know what to do for
him, they had him over medicated for a
while and with a lot of medications that
that maybe really were not working for
him. And so ultimately
going through a program which highly
recommend if you're actually addicted in
his case, I don't know if it was
addicted as much. It was he was reliant
upon
some psychological medicines that you
have to titrate off of if you're going
to try to get rid of them. And so the
fact he got professional help for that
was really essential. It did then open
him up to feel more clean. He ultimately
has gotten sober. He's no no longer
drinking and he feels really good about
that. He used some psychedelics along
the way that were helpful. But I think
he also found at some point that the
emotional overall reliance on
psychedelics can can be another form of
an addiction. Um, so I would just say
for those who are challenged right now
in life and finding that you're addicted
to sleeping pills or addicted to
something else that is your way of
trying to anesthesize yourself,
get some help and explore the
possibility. Again, this is not advice.
This is just me reflecting what I heard
from Blake. um explore the idea of can
could you potentially operate without
some of the medication that you're on
because I know for my mom my mom was was
you know I I don't want to say what she
was on but she was on uh a kind of drug
that actually she got addicted to at
some point and it had you know almost a
lethal effect on her. So just be careful
with the kind of pharmaceutical
medication that that people might or
that therapists or psych psychiatrists
might might give to you. So that's my
second observation. I think my third
observation is that um Blake is a
naturalb born entrepreneur. He's been
doing this since his teen years and he
had a failure in his mid20s. uh he had
Tomms which was an enormous success and
built a lot of wealth for him. Um he did
have uh you know a a company that didn't
go well after that called made for a
beautiful had a beautiful mission. And
what I really appreciate now about
enough uh this idea of you are enough is
that this is a it's a it's a for-profit
business but it's rooted and owned by a
nonprofit. And you know, as we get
older, if we're lucky enough in our
life, we have a calling and we have a
sense that what's most important in our
life is not the return on investment. Uh
that was very true for him with uh
Tom's, even though it had a beautiful
mission, but it becomes the ripple of
impact, a different form of ROI.
You know, I can see in in just seeing
how just smitten Blake is by this new
passion of his that I think this is very
lifegiving for him. Yes, it's helping
other people, but for him personally,
it's life-giving. So, um I hope you
enjoyed the episode. I hope if you have
anybody who's going through some deep
disqu or depression or even suicidal
ideiation, please remind them about 988.
Thank you.
>> Thanks for listening to the Midlife
[music] Chrysis. This show is produced
by Midlife Media. If you enjoyed this
episode, help us spread the word by
subscribing and leaving a review on your
favorite platform.