Two years ago, I started waking up at
3:00 in the morning and I want to kill
myself.
Underneath all of it was this [music]
belief that I'm not enough. The reason
I'm bringing this up is it's the most
important thing anyone can do who is
suffering is If you think that you don't
have [music] mentally what it takes to
lead a company, this guest is going to
prove you wrong. We're talking [music]
to Blake Mycoskie who built TOMS, but
maybe you don't know that he started out
probably just like you and I. No cash,
no credentials, and started not one
company, [music] but a ton of them.
After I sold TOMS, I got super
depressed. I built like what I think is
the perfect company. I gave 100 million
children shoes. I made more money than I
ever could imagine and I felt empty. No
matter what I did, no matter how much
success I had, I just never felt that I
was enough. When you feel enough, you
have so much peace because then you can
actually just be. In 3 days, we sold
$100,000
worth of laundry services. Boom!
Everyone signed up. No big deal.
>> That's wild. How many times do you think
you've been rejected? You can think of
any celebrity that has had a mental
health challenge. I have cold called
every single one of them now and I only
have six founding partners.
>> [music]
>> You want to call one of them out
publicly?
>> [laughter]
>> One of my favorite things about you
actually that I didn't know is what
you're not famous for actually, which is
all these other businesses that you
started and a lot of them you didn't
even have a lot of money.
Some of them you maybe have money today,
you don't use money as like the main
driver for growth. So I wanted to ask
you
for somebody listening today who wants
to start a business
but thinks I don't have the cash to do
it, I don't have the credentials to do
it, what would you tell that person?
I mean, first thing I would say is I
often think a startup having money is
like a detriment.
Yeah, like I never have raised money in
any business I've started and I've
always felt like if you can bootstrap it
and prove and get customers and make it
work, well then you have, you know, a
better chance of success. But I mean,
TOMS, the entire company was started
$3,000.
I know. I mean, my laundry business I
started I started it for $500. My online
drivers ed company that I started maybe
was
I don't know, $1,500.
So like I've never actually Actually,
the one business that I started that
didn't work, I spent a couple million
dollars on it. Now that I think about
it, yeah. I started a habit formation
company called Made For with a good
friend of mine,
a Navy SEAL, amazing. We had Andrew
Huberman as one of our advisors. Like it
was locked and loaded and I put 3 and
1/2 million dollars in it. Zero today.
Yeah. I love that cuz it's we bootstrap
all of our companies and I kind of think
the same thing. It's like you, you know,
if you put a bunch of fuel on a fire
that's going the wrong direction, it's
not very good.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah. Were there things that
you believed back then that now through
multiple exits, still own a business
for, you know, 50% at a 600 mil
valuation,
multiple businesses you started that
you're like
that was such a lie that they told me
starting out in business and now I know
this to be the truth. I think one of the
things is that um I don't think that
having experience in an industry makes
you more likely to have success because
when you have experience, you kind of
know the rules so you don't have like
the courage to break them.
And you're limited. You already start
with a set of beliefs that are limiting
the innovation that you would have. Like
I started you know, a cable television
network, no experience in that. Drivers
ed company, zero experience in that. You
know, TOMS, obviously I had never made a
pair of shoes before I was sitting in
Argentina. You know, enough. I mean, now
like I've never made bracelets and
accessories. Like so I actually think
that's one of the biggest lies we're
told is is in a small business is or
entrepreneurs is that you need to have
experience. And then the second thing I
learned, which I learned the very much
the hard way at TOMS, is that once you
grow and you get to a certain size you
need experts. That's the biggest bunch
of [\h__\h] ever. I mean, literally like
the number of people that I brought in
to TOMS later, like once we were like
couple hundred million dollar business,
that quote had like big company
expertise
did not help. If anything, it it
affected the culture in a negative way,
caused more complexity. They wanted to
bring their own systems in, their own
teams. It created like way more overhead
than we ever needed. So hey, you don't
need a lot of experience to start and if
anything, having experience might limit
your innovative thinking. And then if
you are lucky enough to build something
that really starts scaling, when they
start telling you like oh, you need to
bring in this expertise I don't I don't
think it's true. And I think my sister's
a great example of that. My sister, you
know, runs Aviator Nation and you know,
she owns 100% of the company, has never
brought in quote the experts and she and
a small group of really passionate
people built an incredible brand.
Yeah. What did your parents feed you
guys?
Why are you both so successful? That's
so cre And my brother, too. My brother
has I love you all My brother has this
amazing online golf company called
MyGolfClub and basically it allows
people to get by far the lowest prices
of any golf equipment on the internet
and through a membership model. And so
he hasn't been as like well known in the
media, but he's also crushing it. What
like what do you attribute that to? Like
what is it parenting or genetics? I
think our parents were like always just
like if you can believe it, just go do
it. Like we didn't have a We didn't have
any fear growing up of failure. And I
think maybe cuz, you know, we grew up My
dad was a doctor, my mom was an author.
She did very well. He did well. Like we
had a nice safety net. So a lot of
people don't have that. You know, a lot
of people, you know, don't have the
luxury of just going for it. But also I
just think from a psychological
perspective, our parents were always
instilling confidence in us and always,
you know, encouraging us to like really
go for what we believe in. Can you
remember a moment where like
it was
it really made you who you are as a kid
because of what your parents did? Like
were were there moments where you You
know, my mom basically put my dad
through medical school.
And then, you know, years later I think
I was 15 at the time, my sister was like
11, my brother was like seven.
She decided she wanted to write a
cookbook. And she was like, you know
what? I have this idea for this
cookbook. I think it'll help a lot of
people lose weight. It's about cutting
the fat out. It's good for your heart.
This whole thing. She had, you know,
didn't go to college. Had no experience
writing books. Like my dad bought her a
word processor at Walmart and she wrote
this book and it became the number one
best-selling cookbook in America for 3
years. Wow.
And she made millions of dollars. So
it's like just do things.
>> Yeah, yeah, just do things. Like they
Just like if you have an idea, just try
it. And what, you know, and so I think
that really
created that entrepreneurial spirit in
my brother and my sister and I. Yeah.
You know, and you've told me even just
our short time hanging out here a bunch
of stories about how you get people to
get excited about a product or business
without having a bunch of cash, which I
love. So like
I want to talk about You were talking
about two companies you're interested in
right now. And one of them you're like,
you know how we're going to we're going
to get everybody into this. And then you
told me your strategy. Will you tell
them the strategy for the chair company?
>> Yeah. Well, I think one of the best
things to do for a company is to try to
find a way to be integrated into natural
conversations. And it's also like like
it's also the thing that like Seth
Godin, the great marketing genius who I
love, you know, he writes about the
purple cow. And the purple cow is it's
like if you're driving down the highway
and you're looking at cows and then you
see a purple one, you're going to stop.
You're going to take a picture of it.
You're going to tell everyone. So it's
got to be remarkable. So first off, when
you're starting a business, like if the
more your product itself can be
remarkable, but then it's like how do we
naturally integrate it into where
conversations are happening? So this
chair company is called the Pivot Chair,
P V O T. Okay? So Pivot Chair, these
guys are engineers from Nike. They're
there for like 30 years and they
realized that sitting is the new
smoking. Like like we we were way too
sedentary. And so they developed a chair
that has It's the only chair in the
world and they have all these patents on
it that literally has two axis points.
So it moves this way and it moves this
way. And so when you sit in the Pivot
Chair, if you're not prepared, you'll
fall over.
But if you're prepared and you engage
your core a little bit, all the pressure
goes out of your lower back and it's
like the most amazing experience ever.
You can sit in it all day. It's not like
it makes you sore, but it engaged you
enough that it's like the equivalent of
thousands of steps. And everyone's
looking to count steps, right? And so
what my idea to them was is I was like,
guys, like because we're getting ready
to do an investment round. The company
launches in July and I said, you know, I
think the only people we have invest in
this next round are podcast hosts
because they sit in a chair big part of
the day and then their guests sit in the
chair. And so rather than them have to
like do an ad about it, just have the
guest sit there and for the first 5
minutes of every conversation it's to be
what the [\h__\h] am I sitting in? And then
naturally you're going to talk about
like why this is so good for us. And so
I that's a good example of like taking
something that might be hard to explain
and that's when you need a lot of money
for marketing and advertising and just
letting someone experience it in an
environment that's naturally going to
get people talking about it. And so
that's and like we have no marketing
budget for that company. We don't need
it because it's just if people sit in
it, they won't want one.
How do you come up with ideas like this
that don't take money but just
creativity? Like do you have a creative
process?
I think the creative process is I just
love people. I love talking to people. I
love meeting strangers. I love asking
people what you think. I love playing
pranks on people. Like I mean, I just
like just anything to do with people and
I feel like the more I'm around people,
the more ideas get generated. What
doesn't work for me is like sitting in
a, you know, in an office trying to
figure it out or like having endless
Zoom calls, you know, because everyone's
posturing whatever. Like it's actually
like let's just get out there and mess
with it. Like for instance, when I
launched the Enough bracelet, what I did
was I just started giving them to
people, you know, and saying, "Look,
like I really struggled not feeling
enough and for many years and this has
been like a daily reminder for me and
I'd just love for you to have one and
just see what happens." Or ask people
like who in your life helps you really
feel enough. And they start opening up,
"My mom." "Okay, here's one for you and
go give one to your mom." You know, so
like and then we had all these ideas
about that and then that leads to,
"Well, what if every person that
receives one now has a little code on
their on the packaging where they can
scan it and send one to someone else?"
Oh, that's cool.
>> So, what a great marketing idea, right?
Like everyone that wears a bracelet is
also a giver of a bracelet and now it
just goes on forever. But that wouldn't
have come had I not been like on the
street like passing out bracelets
talking to people. That's such a good
point cuz I think
in this age of AI, everybody's really
worried about their job and what's going
to happen and will somebody take this
away from me. Yeah.
And one of the things that I think lasts
is something you talk about a lot, which
is really taste and creativity, right?
And so like you're obviously a guy with
taste. You're like cool dressed. Yeah,
you got all this stuff. TOMS was like,
you know, one of the first cool shoe
companies I remember. Thank you. And so
I guess my question for you there is
like
does everybody have taste? Can you
develop taste as an entrepreneur? Can
you hire people with taste?
I definitely think you can hire people
with taste. Like I feel like when I'm
meeting with someone, I kind of know if
they've got it or they don't.
>> can you tell? Just their personal style
choices, their their attention to
details, their Instagram. I mean, as
silly as that sounds, like even to that
to some degree. I mean, it's gotten a
little bit harder because everyone's so
hyper-focused and everyone kind of
follows what everyone else is doing. But
but originally early day Instagram like
back when like I was running TOMS, you
know, 10-plus years ago, Instagram was a
great way to see like when we were
hiring people like cuz it's it's
interesting like they say like if you
really want to know someone,
you know, look at their camera roll. You
know, it's like what are they actually
taking pictures of? And if they're
taking pictures of like cool
architecture or like a really cool
restaurant or whatever, even if they're
not posting it, it's like that's how you
can kind of see what are someone
thinking about, you know? And I think a
lot of taste is also about curiosity.
Mhm. Like taste I don't necessarily
think. Actually, I want to change this.
I care more about someone having a sense
of style
>> Mhm. than taste. And I don't care if
it's my style or not. Yeah. Like they
could be hardcore cowboy. Great. But if
they lean into it and like that's them,
I respect that.
>> You know, or they're really into, you
know, vintage cameras and like that's
their thing and they've got this camera
and they tell you exactly about it and
why they had this leather strap and what
this viewfinder does. Like that's a
sense of style, whereas taste can be a
little bit kind of like following
whatever's cool in the moment. But I'm
more interested in style cuz that tells
me independent thinking, that tells me
curiosity, that tells me confidence that
they don't care if everyone else has
their style, you know? So Yeah, that's
it. I think that's something that's a
little bit more interesting to look at
when you're looking to hire someone
because if someone has a specific sense
of style, I think that that can be
applied to other styles. So like if
they're very specific in their personal
style, then they can figure out like
what is the right style of how we want
to, you know, merchandise or or stack
these bracelets. Yeah, it's a good
point. Yeah, it's funny. I was actually
talking to David, my podcast producer,
because I was like, "I got to get like I
got to get a little bit more swag." Like
I was like too serious, you know, cuz
I'm ex-finance. And he's and he is known
for, hopefully I can say this publicly,
sometimes he'll paint his nails. Now the
internet knows. And he's like yeah and
he
>> paint my nails before. See, I was like,
"David, I don't know about that." I was
like, "I don't know if that's what we
And he was like, "Listen, bud, you got
to get you got to go cool. You got to
get on my level." I I paint my I paint I
The reason I did it is for years I was
trying to stop biting my fingernails.
>> Okay, that's reasonable. And so I
thought if I paint them pink and green
and all these random colors, then it
like brings like a conscious attention
to them and if I have attention to them,
I'm not going to want to hurt them.
Yeah. Did it work?
>> didn't really work as well.
>> [laughter]
>> But but it did make my kids think I was
like super embarrassing, which
ultimately that's why I stopped doing it
cuz my daughter thought it was cool when
she was like four and five and we went
to get manicures. Now that she's eight,
it's like if I painted nails, I'm not
invited to any school assemblies.
We're talking about all these incredible
things you do with business and these
big businesses you've started. But there
are a bunch of businesses nobody I don't
think knows that you started. And so I
want to talk about them in a couple
different ways. One, I want to talk
about Easy Laundry, which you were on.
>> Great. First business.
>> Yeah, tell me about the business. How
much money did you start it with and
what happened? 500 bucks. I broke my
Well, not broke. I had I had torn my
Achilles tendon. Oof. I was a tennis
player in college. I was on crutches. So
all of a sudden, I couldn't carry my
laundry to the laundry facility, which
is in the bottom of the dormitory. So my
laundry is piling up. I can't carry them
down. My roommates kind of giving me a
hard time. We go home for Thanksgiving.
His dad was an entrepreneur. I didn't
know what the word entrepreneur was at
this point, right? My dad's a doctor, my
grandfather's doctor, my uncle's a
doctor, my aunt's a nurse. Like they're
my whole family's medical.
And his dad, we were talking about the
fact that I couldn't do my laundry and
he said, "Well, you should just have
someone, you know, come and pick it up."
And I was like, "I looked in the yellow
pages." And this is how old I am, right?
So I looked in the yellow pages.
>> Which by the way was a directory of
listings like the internet back in the
day. Remember that? For anyone who
doesn't know what it is, it's basically
imagine if Google was printed.
>> [laughter]
>> But literally
>> But local. Local. So anyways, I I told
him I was like, "I looked in the yellow
pages. There's no [\h__\h] people to pick
up my laundry. No one will do it." He's
like, "That sounds like a business
opportunity." I'm like, "A what?" He's
like, cuz I'm a jock. I'm just a pure
tennis player. It's all I do. And he's
like, "I think maybe you guys should
start a laundry business." Oh. And I was
like He's like, "Yeah, people would
Sure, people would." I went to a school
SMU in Dallas, a lot of rich kids. And
so he's like, "I think you charge a lot
of money for this." Great. So literally,
we go back, we buy a FedEx truck for
$500. An old, I mean, like literally
doesn't work. We had to get the engine
replaced. But like the shell of an old
FedEx truck at like a junkyard, $500. We
paint on the side E Z Laundry.
Red and blue. And we decide to start
going around to fraternities and
sororities and like pitching our
services. Now, I've never even done my
own laundry. I mean, I grew up very
sheltered. My mom was like Miss
Homemaker. So like I'm like now figuring
out how to like hire people to do
laundry in the middle of the night at
these places and we just figured it out.
It's amazing. I was I was like 17, 18
years old.
>> How'd you sell it? It sucks doing your
laundry. And like and so, you know, if
you pay us this, we'll come pick it up
every week. But here's the whole thing
and this is such
and I really hope if someone takes from
this podcast, this was like such an
incre like one of my first most
important lessons of marketing. So we
had this great service for, you know, I
don't know how much it was. Like say 20
bucks a week, we'll do all your laundry
for you, okay?
No one signs up.
I mean, I don't think we had one
customer. We went to fraternities,
sororities. First off, the sororities
are like, "We're not giving you our
panties, Blake." Like this is the last
thing you could do. I mean, they all
knew me.
>> like, "Not this boy." They're like
exactly, not this boy. You know? But so
the sororities are like, "This is just
no way." And then the guys are like,
"What are you doing? Like why why are
you playing golf or goofing around
drinking beer? Like you're doing
people's laundry?" Like I mean, just the
kids the kids who needed it didn't
weren't the customers.
But who was the customer? Their parents.
And the parents who were the most the
customer was the incoming freshman. So
we sold no laundry services for a
semester. We go home in summer. We're
thinking about basically quitting. It's
just not working. And then we get a
booth at orientation for the next year.
In three days, we sold $100,000
worth of laundry services.
Because the parents assumed when they
got there, you buy the books, you sign
up for the laundry, you get the meal
plan. Boom! Everyone signed up. They
didn't question the price.
It was nuts. I dropped out of college
and never went back because of this
moment in my life. Because of laundry.
Yeah, I literally it was the craziest
[\h__\h] thing. Like literally we just
were in the we just had the right pitch
to the right customer. So sometimes you
have the best idea,
you're just selling the wrong person.
Yeah.
>> And it wasn't the kids. Even though the
kids are the ones who are benefiting
for I don't know why. They weren't the
ones that were thinking they want to
spend $20 on it when they only have so
much money for beer or whatever. But
their parents who are thinking my kid is
maybe never done their own laundry or if
they have, they don't do a great job.
And I just bought the books for,
you know, $900. Might as well spend $500
a semester to make sure they don't ruin
their clothes. And boom! $100,000 in
sales, three days. Next day I call my
dad, drop out of college, never go back.
That's so smart. What's true because
these days I feel like people
overcomplicate marketing so much.
>> Yeah.
>> like the demographic, the avatar, the
analysis.
>> hate marketing. Right.
>> People hate when I say that, too. I I
just I just made some real enemies
already. I know.
I put this on I put this on Instagram
the other day and like four people that
work for me in marketing at TOMS reached
out to me like, "Really?"
>> [laughter]
>> "Really?" Like I hate you and I want to
>> I helped you build a $600 billion
kill you.
million dollar business, you hate
marketing? Come on. But it's true
because it's
>> just don't like the the formal concept
of marketing. I think when you're trying
to like concoct a way to convince or
manipulate someone to buy something,
it's just it's just not what I what I'm
about. Like it's like no, like we were
giving something great. We just once
again, right place, right time, right?
Goes back to the chair. Like the chair,
if we get the right people to sit in it
in an environment where a lot of people
see their amazing kind of remarkable
experience, it'll spread like wildfire.
What do you call that? Like have you
named that? Is that like trigger point
marketing? Is it like
cuz I think that's a really useful
framework for people to think as opposed
to, you know, "Oh, I spend X percentage
of my revenue on PPC with Zuckerberg."
You know?
I think it's like showing the utility. I
mean, even with the Enough bracelet,
what's been really fun
is, and I know I keep referencing it,
and eventually we'll have to talk about
it, but
but but the thing is is like it's really
about the utility of like So, it's it's
not even the fashion of it, or it's not
even like that we'll raise a bunch of
money for mental health charities. It's
like, what does this actually do for
someone? And so, yeah, so anyway, so
I've just launched this,
um and it came from my own my own
journey. After I sold TOMS, I got super
depressed. And you actually even before
I sold TOMS, I started to get depressed,
but it got much worse when I sold it cuz
I thought, "Okay, once I sold it, I have
all this money, all this freedom. I can
live in the mountains. I'm going to be
so happy." And then I wasn't. And then I
was like, "Oh, [\h__\h] Now what I do?
Like, I built like what I think is the
perfect company. I gave 100 million
children shoes. Like, you know, I made
more money than I ever could imagine."
>> You're friends with all the celebrities.
>> Everyone is, you know, every single
thing. I mean, covers of every magazine
for a while. Like, and
I felt empty. And I felt like I didn't
really like know like what the second
half of my life would be like, and
the depression got worse and worse over
7 years as we talked about. It got
really, really bad a couple years ago.
And in part of my healing journey, my
therapist really helped me see that
underneath all of it was this fear, this
this belief that I'm not enough. And it
started when I was young, and I tried to
feel enough by winning tennis matches,
then I tried to feel enough by starting
businesses, then starting a business
that would help people, but no matter
what I did, no matter how much success I
had, I just never felt that I was
enough. And then after I did everything
that the world tells you will make you
feel enough, and I still didn't feel
enough, that's when the depression
because it was like I didn't know where
else to turn, which ultimately forced me
to go inward and learn me and help me
really realize and heal this idea that
I'm enough, you're enough, we're all
enough. But our culture
lies to us all the time and tells us
we're not enough. And if in social media
is great at showing you and making you
feel comparison to everyone else and
stuff how you're not enough. And so, I
decided after I started feeling better
at about a year ago that I want to help
people feel enough, and my best friend
told me to make a bracelet cuz he's
like, like, I have all these tattoos,
right? So, they all have these different
sayings. Like, one says, "Be present."
One says, "Do the work, speak the truth,
enjoy the ride, carpe diem." And so,
he's like, "Instead of getting an I'm
enough tattoo, which I can see that's
what you're going to getting ready to
do."
He's like, "Most people aren't going to
get that tattoo. So, why don't you
create something that everyone can
participate in? And And you like
bracelets, why don't you make a
bracelet?" So,
went to India, got these bracelets are
handmade by women in India, and the idea
is it's just a daily reminder just to
look down and kind of be like, "I don't
know. I'm always enough. I've always
been enough." And like, [\h__\h] everyone
that tells me that I'm not enough. You
know, cuz so much of that pressure is
coming from all around us. And when you
feel enough, you have so much peace
because then you can actually just be,
and you can be present, and you can be
connected. And so, the utility of this
for me is, you know, that it helps
remind me, but the utility of this for
someone else could be different. So, for
instance, we 100% of the profits from
Enough goes to mental health
organizations. So, a lot of people I
know that are wearing the bracelet now
are wearing it cuz just they want to
raise money for mental health. The same
way like the Livestrong bracelet raised
money for cancer, right? They're like,
"No, I I know someone that struggled.
Maybe they lost someone to suicide." You
know, I mean, and they're like, "I'm
going to wear this in honor of them or
to raise money." And And that's why they
wear it. But it's we're giving the
utility. And so, you know, yes, I talk
to my story and I and I share other
people's Enough stories, but also I show
that like there's utility to this. And
then the other thing, which at the end
I'm going to give you one, is you have
I'll show you right now, a little
teaser, is we only sell them in pairs.
So, when you buy one for yourself or
you're given one, you get to wear the
first one, but then you get to think,
"Who do you want Who in your life do you
want to give the second one to?" And so,
that's utility. So, in terms of this, I
would call it utility marketing. Like, I
really think that's the thing is like,
"What utility does the Enough bracelet
do for people besides raise money for
charity? What utility does the Pivot
chair do for someone who's sitting all
day, who might have back pain, and who
wants to live a more active life?" What
utility did the laundry business do for
those parents? The utility wasn't even
the clean clothes. Utility was the peace
of mind we gave them. And it's so true.
So, think about utility. Speaking of
insane marketing ideas, did I ever tell
you one of my favorites? I actually
started my entire business with a
newsletter. Literally sending emails
built my entire business from zero to
nine figures in four years, which is
wild. So, if I could recommend you one
thing, it would be to start a
newsletter. Write about anything in the
world that you're curious about, your
business, your customers, your ideas.
And my friend Tim Ferriss is on Beehiiv,
and he writes an email each Friday
literally only about his five favorite
things. I actually switched all of my
newsletters to Beehiiv because I wanted
to grow, and so they helped me see where
my audience come from, who reads, how to
send stupid simple but like beautiful
emails, and then the growth tools are
all totally built in, which works for
me. So, it recommends my newsletter in
front of other people's audiences. So,
I'm finding readers I never even would
have reached. Now, I'm obsessed with
this team. The founder Tyler is
literally the most relentless,
mission-driven founder.
Just like Blake, actually. He He's the
most relentless one I've ever worked
with. Uh it's fascinating to watch their
team. They ship product and features and
solve every issue that I have come up.
In fact, these little wizards just spun
up a new landing page for me in two days
because my other one was terrible. So,
if you want to share your ideas with the
world and make money on it, go to
beehive.com/cody
and use code cody30. You'll get 30% off
3 months. That's beehive.com/cody
for code cody30. Also, drop your
newsletters on Beehiiv when you start
them in the comments. I want to see what
you guys are writing. I'm looking for
new ideas and brilliant people, and I'm
hoping more people like you get into
this game of newsletters because it very
simply changed my entire life. Again,
that's Beehiiv with two E's, two I's, no
third E. What You guys will figure this
out. You know you'll remember Beehiiv,
won't you?
You know what we should do? If
somebody's listening right now and you
have your business, but you don't have
your utility marketing,
>> Yeah. why don't you comment for us? And
I'll pick one and send it to you.
>> Deal. And then we can give them a
response. Oh, that'd be sick. I love
making videos. Okay.
>> Tell my team all the time. It's like,
you want to get a hold of someone, just
let me make a video. Like, the other
day, it's so funny, our PR person was
trying when we were launching Enough,
you know, he was like, um he was like
talking about how everyone to launch it.
And then Gayle King came up. And I was
like, "I was on the CBS show with Gayle
King like a decade ago. Let me just make
a video." He's like, I don't know. I'm
like, "Trust me."
"Hey Gayle, it's Blake. 10 years ago,
you helped me launch TOMS. I'm launching
Enough. I would love to come on the
show. What do you think?" Sure enough,
we launched it with Gayle King. Like,
sometimes the simplest thing is just
like just make the video, you know? You
know, ask the person to buy it. Like, I
mean, just like it's simple things.
Yeah, I mean, we definitely don't ask
enough. That is for sure. And I think
>> I say something to that?
>> I would love that.
>> No, because this is something that I
feel so grateful for in my life right
now. So, when I was building TOMS, you
talked about celebrities involved. We
had a lot of celebrities. A lot of
people supporting TOMS.
But I felt so much pressure whenever I
would go to a meeting or pitch someone
like, "Will you wear our shoes?" or
whatever, because my personal identity
was tied to whether they said yes or no.
So, every rejection, which you're going
to get a lot of rejections as an
entrepreneur, was like personally
painful. So, it caused me stress,
anxiety, all these things. Now, because
I really do feel I'm enough, whether you
like the bracelet, whether they like the
bracelet, whether anyone likes the
bracelet, I know that there's someone
that this is really going to reach and
is going to touch them, that now I have
no problem asking anyone anything
because if they say no, it's no big
deal. Cuz it's not my personal identity
is whether they like it or they say yes
or whatever. And so, that's coming
That's been so fun for me. Because now
as I'm going out to different, you know,
Kid Cudi is one of my partners. I cold
called him. No big deal. That's wild.
>> cold called him. You know, I mean,
literally, I, you know, had a friend
that knew his manager, and I had read
about how his he had really struggled
with mental health and had suicidal
ideation, like a lot of the same [\h__\h]
that I went through, and he just seemed
like a real like genuine guy. And so, I
talked to her, and she's like, "I can
get it in front of him." She got it in
front of him. A day later, he's like,
"Hey, can I do a Zoom with Blake?" All
of a sudden, Zooming with Kid Cudi. And
then a week later, he's one of our
founding partners of Enough. Yeah,
that's wild.
>> But if he would have said no, I wouldn't
even thought 10 seconds about it. I
would have been onto the next. You know
what else is cool? I don't think I mean,
I just learned this. You You can go to
IMDb, sign up for their premium thing,
and see every single agent's every
single famous person's agent.
>> Yeah, they're going to hate this.
They're going to hate this. Yeah,
they're going to like delete this part.
Yeah, whatever. That's your job. That's
why you get paid the 10 to 20%. Deal
with it.
>> Exactly. Um but I I think the the cool
part is, and what I hope people take
away, is that even though you've had
this huge career and you've built all
these big businesses, these are actually
little micro things that anybody in the
world could do. Cuz I mean, how many
times do you think you've been rejected?
Like, in your life? Just with Enough.
I'm not going to put some celebrities
and athletes on air
or their agents, but like,
you can think of any mental health any
any celebrity that has had a mental
health challenge that has talked
publicly about it. Or any Olympic
athlete that has a huge platform about
mental health. I have cold called every
single one of them now, and I only have
six founding partners. There's hundreds
of them. So, that means that there I'm
I'm still waiting to hear back from
agents of hundreds of these people who
say mental health is the most important
thing in their life and I'm saying you
can help us raise tens of millions of
dollars by just wearing the damn
bracelet. Nothing. You want to call one
of them out publicly?
>> [laughter]
>> That is Yeah, but that's the game.
>> Yeah. So I think
>> You know what I'd like to do? I want to
give you a list and in the show notes,
cuz I don't want to call them out, but
I'm going to say this is my top dream 30
people to be ambassadors of enough. So
if anyone is watching or knows their
manager or knows them, cuz all these
people it's not like I'm asking them to
do something they're not already doing.
They're already saying I really care
about mental health. I got through this.
I want to help other people. So in the
show notes, I'm going to give you my
list of my top 30 and hopefully someone
can get us to one of them and we'll have
a new founding partner.
>> I love that. That would be huge. All
right, let's go YouTube. I like this.
Okay, I also want to talk about you you
seem to have this like you I don't care,
you know, [\h__\h] all these people, [\h__\h]
whatever they think. But you have had
numerous like what my dad would call
dark nights of the soul.
>> Yes. Where you have like looked at the
darkness in the face that I think all of
us have felt either just as a [\h__\h]
human, but also as an entrepreneur.
Yeah.
And I think it'd be interesting. I don't
know which one you want to share, but
like I'd love to hear about a night
where you just head in hands didn't know
what to do next and then how you got
through that. For maybe the person
that's listening right now with their
head in their hands. Yeah, I mean
I think the scariest thing for me
was when I started getting depressed and
then it got worse and I started trying
to do all these external things to fake
you know, built the dream house, moved
my family to Costa Rica, you know, got
divorced, got remarried, got divorced
again. Like I did a lot of things to
mess up my life.
And there was a time and in doing that I
you know, had in this you know, I I
didn't have as close a connection with
my kids and and and and I didn't went to
a psychiatrist who told me I was
bipolar. And then I got put on all these
meds and I mean like my journey got went
from bad to worse to worse to worse
to
2 years ago I started waking up at 3:00
in the morning and
I want to kill myself. And it was so
[\h__\h] scary because I knew logically I
would never do that to my kids. Like I
knew like but I couldn't stop thinking
like go to your boat you you know, that
you lived on when you started TOMS. That
was your happy place. Do it there.
They'll never find you. Someone else I
mean like that's the level of detail.
And I was dealing with this every single
day and I was keeping it
I was so ashamed because like look, I
have money, I have a wife at the time, I
have kids, like like what who am I to
like want to leave this earth?
And so I wasn't telling anyone and the
thing I did which I'm
reason I'm bringing this up is it's the
most important thing anyone can do who
is suffering is tell your friends.
Just like there's never judgment, you
know, I think mental health has had a
lot of stigma. I think it's getting less
and less, but just find at least one
person today to be like it's this bad
and don't hold anything back. Like
literally be like this is what I'm
thinking. This is what I'm feeling. This
is what I'm planning.
Because I believe what happens with
people who become suicidal or at least
for me, my experience and others I've
talked to and some that I've lost
is that it's like the brain's broken.
You know, I mean literally it's no
different than like a huge car accident,
but it's invisible to everyone. And so
think about it like how are you ever
going to go to the hospital? How are you
ever going to get the surgery? How are
you ever going to get the PT if people
don't see you mangled on the street?
But if you're in that in that dark of a
place, you are mangled your brain is
mangled. It's the neurons are not firing
cuz it's cuz it's not normal for us not
to want to live.
You know, and especially me I had tons
of friends. I you know, I mean all these
reasons.
But the most important thing I did and
the most important thing anyone can do
is just reach out for help.
And yes, there's great crisis text lines
and there's all this mental health, you
know, Project Healthy Minds is one of my
amazing partners with enough. They have
all these resources on their website.
But I still think the most important
thing is tell someone really close to
you.
I told my friends. I told my mom.
Now I hated that I was putting this on
my mom, but I was also like I just need
to get through the next 6 months. Like
and and and over time they helped me,
you know, make some very important
decisions in my life, helped me get off
all the pharmaceuticals, helped me go to
a treatment facility. Like I I mean my
journey really was
largely supported by the people that I
shared. Um
and also something about just talking
about it, you know, kind of takes the
pressure away from it. It it takes a
little of the energy out of it.
So were you falsely diagnosed bipolar? I
think so. I mean some people might
Who knows? Who knows? This is one of my
favorite tattoos. So if you can see this
one this is my
um Who knows? This is my partner in
TOMS, okay? Right? And so for those of
you who are just listening, I remember
not everyone's watching this, then you
should maybe we'll post a picture of
this. But
this is Alejo. He started TOMS with me.
He's wearing a beret? What's that?
>> So he's wearing a beret?
>> all these Argentine gauchos wear this
hat. It's like a gaucho Yeah, yeah,
yeah. But anyways, um
he in a very funny way, I won't tell
that story cuz it'll take another half
an hour. But he basically get spoke for
20 minutes with certainty about all the
things in his life that he saw through
this vision and this whole thing after
some psychedelics and then he looked at
me and goes, but who knows?
>> [laughter]
>> Is he Argentinian?
>> Yeah. That is a very Argentinian
>> And the thing is the reason I tattooed
it on my forearm is I think it's like
one of the one like it's literally like
the Buddha talking to me. It was like so
smart cuz it was like we don't know.
I don't know why I got depressed, but I
know that it led to my next purpose.
You know?
I don't know why I was in this
relationship, but it led to me having
kids, you know, like like who knows if
it's good or bad, you know? And so for
me, I don't know. I just I I really look
at life with just a marvel now and to
not be and now let's look at this for
people's journeys. Like someone
difficult in your life or maybe
someone's not treating you well or
whatever, like
who knows why?
Do you think
it's hard to be in a relationship with a
founder?
I think it's a hard to be in a
relationship with me.
>> [laughter]
>> Do you?
Maybe not so much anymore. I think it
different period of my life it was. I
mean I I think it was very hard be in a
relationship with me when I was building
and growing TOMS because it was my first
love, you know? I mean it really was. I
mean there's just, you know, we were
traveling around the world, we were
giving shoes to kids. I was I was
getting the external validation that
someone who never feels enough needed,
so I was getting it constantly, you
know? And so, you know, it's hard to be
in a relationship cuz in a relationship
you mess up, you forget to take the
garbage out, you're late for dinner.
Like you're not exactly getting external
validation every time you come home. But
if you're getting it outside as a
founder, especially if you have success,
it's really hard. But then the
interesting thing now is I'm in an
incredible relationship with an amazing
woman and and you know, she's been part
of the whole enough, you know, building
all enough and it's going great. So I
think a lot of it is is I wouldn't say
it's a founder, I'd say maybe first time
founder, you know, I don't know. But I
do I do think that there are sacrifices,
but I think the person
knows that going in and they're either
in for that ride or they're not and
that's why you got to make sure that you
have the same vision for
you know, what you're doing. Cuz right
now helping people feel enough and
raising money for mental health is
outside of my kids like the most
important thing going on and if I was
with someone that didn't also share that
passion, it probably wouldn't work out
very well.
So now when you get into a relationship,
do you set it up different? Like I think
I just got incredibly I think God threw
me a bone on this one.
You didn't sit her down and say
>> Just like Is she here? Is she listening?
Oh, yeah. Hopefully No, she's You're
doing this and she's not even listening.
We'll have to send it to her later.
>> Yeah, that's how independent she is.
She's just like I'm doing my thing,
you're doing your thing. No, but but I'm
curious. Like I think we have a lot of
people who ask questions about
relationships Yeah. No, I like it. I've
I've watched some of your videos on
Instagram about it. Yeah. Well, I don't
I'm always like I have no [\h__\h] idea.
Talk to people when I'm 80. Who knows,
right? I have no Yeah, who knows? But I
was curious like
for entrepreneurs or somebody going into
a relationship or trying to find their
person
>> Yeah. Like what what would you fess up
with somebody that you're in a
relationship with now? What questions
would you ask, you know, the person?
What would you tell them? Well, I think
the first thing is is just being
radically honest about what your
priorities are.
You know, the the hard thing is
especially for someone who didn't feel
enough cuz I is that you kind of tell
people what they want to hear so they'll
love you, right? Versus like what who
you really are and what you're really
about. And I think so I was kind of
doomed and I think my romantic partners
were doomed because I never felt that I
was enough. So in sense I was looking
for them to tell me that I'm enough or
to fill this hole that only I can fill,
right? And so
maybe I'm not leading with how important
my business is or my purpose is because
I want to say whatever it takes so that
they're going to tell me I'm enough.
Once I healed this
then I was able to I think attract a
relationship and be really honest about
hey
my kids are my number one priority right
now. I spend half my time with them.
Next to that, I am on a mission to
literally change the world's mental
health. Like I want to raise more money
for mental health through enough than
anyone in the history of the world. Like
I'm not like that's how big of a goal I
have. And that's going to require me to
go on a bunch of podcasts, to travel the
world, to do speaking, to do all these
things. And so, most of our days are
going to be living in a suitcase.
And when I'm not in a suitcase, I want
to surf.
>> [laughter]
>> And I met a woman from Hawaii that
surfs. Oh, that's perfect.
>> Yeah. But But it was like very clear,
like when I'm not doing that,
I really want to be surfing. And if you
really like the idea of either surfing
or being in a beach town, and also
traveling around the world on this
crazy, you know, enough enough ride,
then great. And That's such a good
>> But it was But it was so much easier to
be clear and honest honest
because
I wasn't looking for that external
validation anymore. I was getting it for
myself. I was really believing I am
enough, whether this woman is excited
about being on this ride with me or not.
And then, therefore, I also attracted
someone who they felt they were enough.
And so, they were able to be honest
about what's important to them and what
their needs are. And so, I think it's
hard being with a founder, being with an
entrepreneur is is is not for everyone.
But I also think it's really hard if you
struggle with what I've struggled with
and you're founder to not really kind of
sell a vision of a life that's really
not what you want. Yeah. Well,
>> That's what Sorry. That's also what
causes depression. I mean, I'm I'm
convinced that one of the largest causes
of depression is just not living in
integrity with yourself.
You know, for so many years, I was
living the life that I thought everyone
else wanted me to live.
And I wasn't living the life I wanted to
live.
And I think so, that's what catches up
to us as we make all these little
compromises.
Largely, I did it so that I would
receive love.
And then you wake up and you're living a
whole compromised life.
And that you don't want to live, and
that's where your soul is like, "Well,
I'm going to get depressed and feel
horrible until you make major decisions
to get back in alignment."
And then you get back in alignment and
everything feels at peace again. That's
so true. I also think the universe
doesn't give you things when you're
unclear. Yeah.
>> So, you know, if you're like, "No, no,
I'll take whatever love I can get."
That's not actually what you mean, then
things go sideways. So, it's so
important, even the way you set goals is
really interesting to listen to. Cuz
you're like, "I wanted this woman that
here are these things that are really
important to me." And so, they can
decide one way or the other. And the way
you set goals, you know, my husband and
I were talking the other day about how
we were looking at like the greatest men
of all time. You know, if you look in
throughout history. And not one of them
>> best-looking? Yeah, [clears throat]
exactly. You and your husband sitting
around? I think he's hot.
>> Chris would not like that. He would not
be interested in that. He's like you,
he's an he's an ex-Navy SEAL surfer.
Okay. Um but so, he's a dude's dude, but
we were like, "None of these men have
actually achieved their goals fully."
Like, you know, if you go to Napoleon,
if you look back, you know, throughout
history and you look at the biggest
leaders in the world, they never achieve
their goal. And yours is interesting cuz
your goal was not, "Well, I want to sell
a million bracelets." You know, it's "I
want to do more for mental health than
anybody's ever done or to raise more
money than ever." Do you think about
goals a specific way? Is there like a
right way or a wrong way to set goals
for Blake?
>> I would definitely now. I'm glad you
brought this up. So, in the same sense,
I'll say I hope that enough these
bracelets, you know, every person on the
planet wears one and we raise more money
than anyone in the history of mental
health. And
if I just help one dad tell his teenage
daughter that she's enough and read the
poem that's in there to her, and that
creates that tighter bond, we've had
success.
Like, I literally both goals This
actually the dad-daughter one is more
important. And And And And that sounds
like a great thing to say on a podcast
or in a press thing or whatever, but I
actually believe it. And the thing is is
already, we've only been doing this for
like 2 weeks now. We've gotten the most
incredible stories of, you know, teenage
girls giving it to each other and it's
like their new friendship bracelet. You
know, one had been really struggling
with depression. She's like, "Hey, I
want you to know, I always got you and
you are enough." Or I did hear about
this dad and daughter. I heard about
this son that gave it to his dad and
said, "I recognize that my dad's been
depressed probably for like most of my
adult life." He's a guy in his 30s. He's
like, "But I never knew how to ask him
about it or talk to him. And I gave him
the bracelet and it just opened up a
whole conversation and now my dad's
going to therapy." Like, I mean, it's
like So, so when I say goals, I can have
You can I believe you can set goals
that are
you know, not mutually exclusive. Like,
I hope that this becomes huge, but if it
doesn't, even if we touch a few people
and create some interesting
conversations and important healing,
we've had success. I I think there's
been talk about like you set a goal and
then you hold on to it very lightly.
That's like So, you don't have the
pressure of the goal. Like, goals are
great because I do believe what you put
out into the universe is often what you
get back. So, if you don't tell like you
said, if you don't tell the universe
what you want, how the hell are you
going to get it? How's it going to give
it to you? And if you put pressure like,
"Oh, I'm only going to feel this project
was successful if we raise a hundred
million dollars." Well, that's just a
silly thing. But a lot of people do that
and a lot of founders do that. I mean,
they set goals financially. Like, "Oh, I
need to sell my company for 40 million
or 50 million or I need to do this or I
need to do that." But really, the ones
that build the great businesses are 100%
focused on something that is not
necessarily measurable and more
cultural. Big goals loosely held. I love
that.
>> Big goals loosely held. So good. Also, I
think, you know, I think about that a
lot with everything we do and it's one
of my favorite things about the
businesses you've built before, but you
know, we started the beginning of the
podcast with me saying, you know, I try
to always think about like one person
specifically who listens to this. Cuz if
you think about it, you hold something
precious in your hands when you're
taking somebody's attention. That's
their life.
Right? That's That's lifespan. That's
very precious. We don't get very many of
those. And so, if you imagine that we
get millions of views a month across all
the social channels, what a travesty if
you and I don't give them something
really worth spending their life on.
Like, that would hurt me a little. Amen.
>> Yeah. And so, I remember like we've
we've haven't had very many, but we had
two podcasts we had to kill because I
was like,
"I got stuff out of it. Thank you so
much for coming. But like,
a million hours on this, it's not
enough. It's not good enough." And so,
I think um one other thing I want to
talk about, which is like why we put up
the tree. We were struggling beforehand
with this, you know, if you guys are
watching us, you're like, "Why is there
this giant tree that looks so beautiful
behind us?" We were struggling with what
>> setup.
>> Yeah.
it was supposed to be.
And then you told a story about wisdom
and the Buddha that this reminded you
of. Will you tell us that story?
>> Yeah. So, when I started TOMS, um we we
grew beyond shoes into eyewear. We
started selling sunglasses. And then we
made a deal where we said, "Okay, if you
buy a pair of our sunglasses, we'll pay
for a cataract surgery to someone who's
blind." We found out that the greatest
cataract surgeons in the world are at
this hospital in India, in Lundini. And
we decided to go there and watch people
get their eyesight back. I mean, it was
literally one of the greatest
experiences in my life. I mean,
literally, I saw grandparents that had
never seen their grandkids and see them
for the first time because of a surgery
that someone got because someone bought
a pair of sunglasses on on, you know,
toms.com or something. I mean, it's
crazy.
>> how much does that surgery cost then?
>> It cost like
$16 back then. Yeah. Yeah. So, yeah.
>> Yeah, so with one pair of shoes, you're
able to cure eyesight.
>> no, with eyewear. We just sold eyewear
for a hundred hundred fifteen bucks and
$16 of it was went to paying the
surgery. So, anyway, so we go to Lundini
and they didn't tell me this until we
got there, but also Lundini is the
birthplace of the Buddha.
And I looked over and they're like,
"That's the tree." Now, whether that was
the tree or not, who knows, but it was a
tree that looks just like this. And I
have a photo, I have to find it,
probably we can get it for the show, of
me sitting underneath the tree. And I
remember sitting there and
this was this was before I got
depressed. This was like when TOMS was
really taking off. I was in my flow. I
was very connected to it for all the
right reasons. I wasn't putting all the
external pressure. And I just remember
thinking like, "If this is it, if
there's nothing else that happens with
this this this idea." Like, and I'd just
seen some eye surgeries. I was like,
"That's all that matters."
And I think that's like the way I want
to live my life each day, each week,
each month, going back to goals. Like,
at the end of the day, I come and be
like, "Okay,
if that's the last one, I'm okay with
it." You know? And after the week and
after the month, if that's it, I'm okay
with it because that's again about
living in alignment, you know? And for
me, having gone through such a scary
time where for days I thought it was
going to end very soon, I just feel like
I have like this, you know, they say new
lease on life. Like, I feel like this I
get this like second chance. And so,
that's why I'm spending all my time
trying to help others not feel the way I
felt. And really connect people because
at the end of the day,
I mean, that's all we have are
relationships and our own mental health.
Cuz if we don't have mental health, it
doesn't matter what physical health you
have. Yeah. So, what do you do now?
Like, if you're feeling down, not even
going all the way back, but if you're
feeling down or you want to feel
reinspired, Yeah. what what do you turn
to? What activities, what books, what
readings, what quotes? So, okay, this is
silly, but one of the things I'm doing
right now, it's not as silly, it's just
it's just I don't have I don't know how
people respond to this, okay? I like
this. Yeah, I know you're going to like
this. So,
about 2 months ago,
I started using AI therapy.
Now, a lot of people ask ChatGPT mental
health stuff. But there's this app
called Sonia. Uh-huh. sonia.ai.
And I met the founder at a mental health
conference. And he was giving a
presentation and explaining how it works
and how it's, you know, built on the
LLMs, but they've basically taken, you
know, every therapist, every case study,
every book ever written, put it in there
and tried to design.
And they called it emotional support. I
think for legal reasons they called it
emotional support instead of AI therapy,
but it's AI therapy.
>> [snorts]
>> And so,
>> [laughter and gasps]
>> and so, anyways,
I was like, "Well, I've done a lot of
therapy. I mean I mean if anyone's done
therapy, I mean I've done a lot of
therapy." And one of the things that's
really a bummer with therapy is
if I have a panic attack, it doesn't
happen at 2:00 on a Thursday at 2:00 on
a Thursday.
It happens at 4:00 [\h__\h] in the
morning.
And my therapist, I don't care how much
money you have, no therapist is
answering your call at 4:00 in the
morning.
And so I was like, "Wow,
I can because I still have struggles
with anxiety. I still have these issues
that come up and especially with like
launches of new things and you know,
just am I always thinking am I being
enough, good enough dad, all these
things I wake up and I have stress
about. Oh my gosh, I didn't do this or
that.
And so now it's like boom, it's right
there at 4:00 in the morning and I don't
have to do a whole hour session. I could
do it for 5 minutes, 10 minutes. And it
works. It works unbelievable. So what
happens if you go, "I'm panicking?"
Yeah, so literally, so you know, you go
in and you get to choose like I like to
be talked to like like I like a
therapist that is like really direct or
I like one that's more like light or one
this. Like you get you kind of fine-tune
it. It takes like 10 minutes.
And then of course that's memory, so it
never forgets anything. And you tell
them what's going on. Mhm. And like I've
started off saying like this is my core
wound. I never felt that I was enough.
And so this is what I've done, this is
what helped me. I had this mantra-based
meditation. I do these things. And so I
taught it that. And then I teach it, you
know, like okay, you know, one of my
biggest sources of stress is this in my
personal life or this. And so it starts
figuring all this out and so then when I
say I'm having a panic attack this
morning,
>> Mhm. it knows what to check in about.
You know, well, how did you sleep for
instance? One of the things that I have
is like I have a really high like focus
on sleep. And if I don't get a good
night's sleep, I can feel off and it it
feels almost like like if I ever have
jet lag, it almost feels like
depression. Like they kind of feel the
same to me. And so it'll check in on my
sleep and then it'll be like, "Okay,
well, like one of the things that we've
recognized, we like me and the
therapist, it's so funny how it talks to
you, is like that you know, you really
um
have a trouble when things get too
performative.
So when you're having to out there sell
or do too much press or too much of
that, like that's the old Blake. And it
will call it like that's the I mean
we've talked enough or it's like that's
the Blake before all the all the growth.
The new Blake likes connection. So are
you having enough connection? And this
week, what are you doing this week to
have more connection?
>> That's great. So it doesn't just do what
like chat GPT does which is like, "Oh,
you're great. You're perfect."
>> yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, no, no, no, no, it's
like so specific. And then it will be
And then if I say, you know, what I'm
doing on Thursday this week to have more
connection, I'm going to commit to, you
know, going on a run with my friend Pat.
It'll send me a text message Thursday
morning and say, "Hey, are you doing the
run with Pat today?" Are we investing in
this company that's happening?
>> I want to. I want to. I mean literally
right now, I literally just working with
the founders. I'm One of the things I'm
also trying to do a lot now is mentor
young entrepreneurs, especially if
they're building businesses that can
help people with their mental health.
And so when I met these guys, I was
like, "Hey, like I don't know I get I
first off I just want to try it myself."
And then it was working so well and then
they know the Tom story and and then my
I presented at the mental health
conference and they're like, "Hey, like
can you help us some?" And so I've been
mentoring them. So I might invest, we'll
see. But I mean who knows where this is
going. I don't even know if it's going
to be legal. But right now it's free.
And so you go to sonia.ai, so you can do
it right now it's legal and it's free. I
don't know if it will be forever. But um
yeah. What about our business? That's
really helping me. And
and I guess the point I bring that up is
is I think what helps me the most is to
have
um a dependable tool.
And every tool that works for someone
else. So some of my friends, one of my
friends who's a recovering alcoholic and
still deals with a lot of anxiety,
starts to get, you know, out of sorts,
cold plunge. You know, cold shower.
That's his tool. Just boom. He doesn't
He won't even like allow himself to call
someone or talk to a therapist until he
does that first. You know, right now
this Sonia thing is my tool. And I you
know, everyone has a tool, but I think
that's the thing I would say is if
someone's struggling, find a tool that
can interrupt the rumination, the
negative thinking, the you know, all
that stuff. And so that's that's really
a big tool for me. And then my other
tool is my bracelet. You know, I just
have it, I wear it, I talk about it. I
you know, give it out to people all the
time. Like tools are important.
>> That's a good point. It's a pattern
interrupt.
>> Yeah, that's what we need cuz I think
when we get out of sorts,
you know, when we start feeling negative
thoughts, when we start ruminating, when
we you know, you know, it's all just a
pattern. It's our brain. Like you know,
it's just like the brain is sending I
mean for years, for 40 something years
my brain told me I wasn't enough.
And so what I did for 40 days is I did a
mantra-based meditation,
20 minutes in the morning, 20 minutes in
the evening where I simply just said,
"I'm enough.
I've always been enough." And I'd like
laugh cuz it was so silly. And it felt
stupid for the first couple weeks. And
then it started working. I started
feeling it. But all I did was just
change that pattern.
>> I love that. Yeah, I just I just had
Tony Robbins on the podcast.
>> Oh, great. I love Tony. I I I you know,
we've met briefly once. We've never
spent any time together. I want to have
him on my podcast cuz he talks a lot
about feeling enough.
>> Oh, yeah. And he has one of I think like
the most intense presences than anybody
that I
met. So I was at his house and we spent
a good amount of time with him and I
remember like when he walked in the room
I was like, "Whoa." Like that he's a big
guy, right? But we've had a lot of big
you know, there's a lot of big guys.
>> Yeah. Um
but what really took me away is like
that man is locked in. I was like, "Oh
[\h__\h] he knows what's going on in here.
He's like so locked in." And then
um kind of similar to you, he was like,
it was a lot of curiosity which you seem
to have the same thing. Like why are you
this way? Why am I this way? And then
once I figure it out, how do I put a
tool in place to figure out the solution
which I think is is really interesting.
But he would be great for your podcast.
Um I one of the other things I wanted to
ask you about
like now it's so interesting to me that
you could have ever been in this dark
place because the way you come off is
like so so much joie de vivre, so much
like, you know, big huge energy for
life.
>> Crazy. And so I was wondering like
today, what has you
what has you so excited? Obviously this.
>> Yeah. But like when you wake up in the
morning, is it that you're going to go
surf that day? Is it that you get to
build again? I I think what has me most
excited about life right now is is
service. It's like it's just like I'm
getting to help people again. You've
always been.
>> I know right now this podcast, there's a
1,000% chance that there's someone
listening who's really in a tough place.
There's also probably people that
feeling stuck, feeling uninspired,
feeling insecure. Like I I felt those
things. I mean for years, I didn't have
one business idea for 7 years. For 2
years, I was a shell of myself. My
friends say literally they look in my
eyes and there was no one there. I mean
I didn't I couldn't even raise my voice
to this octave for 2 years. And so
because I felt that way
and
it was so scary and it was so recent
that I think I wake up now and I'm kind
of like
>> [laughter]
>> How do you engineer your life? Like it
almost seems like you've adventured your
entire career. It's one of the things I
struggle with.
>> Adventure? Yeah, like
>> Oh yeah, I do. I I always make time for
adventure. But how like so in my
business, we were just talking about
this. I'm like, "Man, when I'm in my
little entrepreneurship grind, it's kind
of all I do." Like I'm so deep in it. I
talked to a lot of people that's the
same. They're just like they grind every
single day. And you seem like a type of
person who has always integrated sort of
the rest of life into it. How do you do
that?
>> Two things. One is I really schedule
joy. So I believe that like a lot of
people hope for joy or awe or these big
moments to come to them. Like I put it
on the calendar the same way you have a
board meeting. Like I'm like, "For 1
week a month, I'm going surfing."
Now I'll still You can't surf all day
long. So I'll surf from 5:00 in the
morning till 10:00. Get my joy. I'll do
Zoom calls from 10:00 to 4:00. And then
me and my lady will go for a walk on the
beach. We'll have a nice dinner. We'll
do, you know, a sunset. And that's my
day. And that is like as important as
the press week in New York last week.
And so I really really schedule that and
that's, you know,
that's nice that I can go somewhere say
where there's surf or whatever. Not
every person can do that. But what is
that for you? Like what is that joy? Is
it taking guitar lessons? Is it learning
something new on YouTube? Like what is
that thing cuz if you don't schedule
that,
then like what's the purpose? You know,
what's the point? Because Do you do that
every day, too? No, I wish. I wish. I
mean if I'm really really like operating
at 10 out of 10, then I'm like making
sure I protect a couple hours, you know,
early in the morning to, you know,
usually it's physical activity or it's
playing golf like nine holes at sunset,
you know, with my son or with my friends
or whatever.
>> Yeah. So but it's at least once a month.
So but once a month I try to schedule
it. Now it's don't know I always get a
week, no. But I definitely get at least
a four day four days. There's there's
not a month that goes by that I don't
have four days where I'm just like, "See
you."
And do you always do something weird
like like going to India or like surf
It's not just like
it seems like there
>> That's more my personality than I think
what I would share like going back to
how do we help the person who's
listening to this and focusing on them.
Like yes, I do a lot of just crazy
adventures cuz that's just always how
I've been. Like you know, I've always
been, you know, racing cars or climbing
mountains or I mean I just I like the
adrenaline of those things. But also I
think you can schedule this, you know,
if someone's just like, "I love reading
and I'm going to schedule four days
where I go could be like the, you know,
you go camping. It costs nothing and I'm
just going to sit and read the books
that I've been waiting to read for 2
years. You know, or I'm going to go and
just like one thing I did that was I
guess it was a little bit out there, but
very simple was I hiked the Camino trail
for a week with Alejo this summer.
So, we just walked for a week. I'm a
big walker. Yeah, we just walked. We got
up, walked, ate, walked. Like it was the
most boring thing I've ever done and one
of the most profound. Because of my
whole nervous system reset and I was
able to process
the depression and all the things I went
through and the pain I caused others and
the pain others caused me and I was able
to forgive them and forgive myself and I
was like, man, this is better than any
therapy retreat I've ever been to. And
all I did for a week was walk. I love
that.
>> and so so I think it could be I could
have done I did that in Spain, but I
could have done that, you know, in Moran
where I live, you know? Yeah.
>> So so I think that Actually, I did Yeah.
I just looked up. This is so funny, but
my hobby this year is literally more
walking because I like thinking
>> a lot while walking. But do you know
that there are 52 trails in the US where
you can do more than a 7-day walk that
are supposed to be seen as highly scenic
Yeah. and you can camp along them. So,
like if you chat GPT it right now
anybody listening, totally free, maybe 7
12 bucks to camp.
>> Yeah. And then you can go for a walk.
Maybe we can start walking all around
the country and having beautiful ideas
while you do it and not being sedentary
like your chair.
>> Exactly. So, that we can get all our
steps in.
>> Sitting is the new smoking. Who knew?
Blake walking episode.
>> Here's the Here's the slogan I'm
pitching we're talking to a chair
company and I'll see what you think as a
business person. Really simple.
Never still.
Oh god, that's true. Plus I'm into that.
I don't like being still.
>> Yeah. So, now when you're sitting the
other thing about the chair thing, not
to make this all about that, but they're
going to love this.
>> [laughter]
>> This is this is how you got here. Is So,
they thought it was to help, you know,
with get people, you know, not being
still, you know, help with the back
pain, help with the you know, but what
they found like the biggest hack is
people with ADHD.
Because what happens do you? Totally.
Okay, so you know how like when you're
if you really focus on something, you
kind of need to be doing something else.
>> Oh, totally.
>> You like to fidget, you like to doodle,
you ring. So, they've shown that you can
really focus. Well, we've done all this
research to show that by sitting this
chair, your body is just doing this kind
of you barely see it and it allows you
to hyperfocus on whatever you're doing.
I'm sold. Yeah, you're getting one for
sure. Totally sold.
>> hopefully all your guests will be
sitting in one. Okay, so I want to leave
the person listening here that like just
needs to listen to Blake today. Like
your parting words. So, like there's
that person out there you know you have
something to imbue to them. What comes
to you first? What do you want to leave
the listener?
I just think that
what I want to say is that
it will pass.
You know, no matter what you're going
through, no matter how hard it is,
like just it will get better. It always
does if you just hang on and
you take the steps to do the things. So,
go out for the walk, you know, you know,
reach out to a friend, you know,
journal for for 30 seconds. Not even 5
minutes, just just 30 seconds of
something that you're appreciative of.
But
no matter how hard it is, it will pass.
I didn't think it was going to pass. I
thought I was trapped. I thought I'd
made too many mistakes. I had too much
shame.
And that's why I had such dark thoughts.
But looking back now,
I'm like
it was always going to pass. I just had
to hold on. I just had to start doing
one thing at a time. I just had
McConaughey on my podcast and he talks
about one in a row. Just get one in a
row today. And so that would be my
advice is like knowing like or not even
advice, just like just I want you to
hear that it will pass and it will get
better, but you got to do the work.
You got to put it in.
Blake, who would have thought the least
interesting thing about you is that you
sold your company for 600 million bucks.
Least interesting. Thank you so much for
being here today. I'm Oh, hold on. Got
to give you a bracelet before we're
done. Oh, we're going to do it right
now.
I love this.
>> So, here we go.
So, we take one out. This one's for you
and it says So, you got to make sure I
do this right.
Yep. So, open your palm. Okay. Okay, and
for those who are listening, I'm putting
enough bracelets
Matches my outfit today. I didn't even
wear green on purpose. And
>> I love this. I'm going to read you
something. Okay? So, this is a little
poem. Do you know the poet NQ? Mhm. So,
he's an amazing poet, friend of mine and
I said, how do I share this with someone
besides just giving to him? Like what
like if I really want them to feel this
this then what can we say? So, here it
is.
So, Cody,
I see you. The you behind the you.
Not for anything you've done or anything
you're going to do.
I don't stop to say it enough, but I
believe in you.
And if you could see yourself from my
view, you'd believe it, too.
That's why I'm giving you the gift
that I'm receiving, too.
A message to remind you when you're lost
or feeling blue.
A mantra to repeat when times are tough
because no matter who we are, we are
always enough.
It's a silent prayer I'm sending for the
world's mental health. I wear the symbol
as my for myself and now as a bond to
someone else. It's a blessing and a
gentle push to never give up
because no matter who you are, you are
enough. Ah, so good. Beautiful. Also,
why you're a marketing legend. Blake,
thank you so much for being here today.
>> Thank you for having me. Um where can
people go to find you? Um weareenough.co
is the website for Enough and then I'm
on Instagram at @blakemik and the pivot
chair p v o t. Yeah, we'll put all the
links down below. And the 30 people that
I would love to be our ambassadors, I'm
looking to your community to help me get
to them. I like it.
>> love this idea. And we'll ping somebody
uh with your brilliant market I
marketing ideas, too, and help them find
that. What did we call it? We called it
utility marketing.
We got a little trademark for Blake to
do.
>> I think I want to do 10 people. Woah. 10
people. I love it. 10 people. Tell us
what you need help with utility
marketing. What are they going to
comment? So, they're going to comment on
YouTube. Basically, just tell us what
your product is and And then I'll just
make them a video of my idea. Ah, I love
this idea. All right, you're the man,
Blake. This was so great.
>> [music]