[Music]
I started Tom's I guess nine years ago
now it's hard to believe when I was
living on the sailboat with the simple
idea that you know I saw many children
around the world who didn't have shoes
and they weren't allowed to go to school
because of that and I wanted to help
them get the shoes that they needed for
school so we created this one forone
model where every time we sell a pair of
shoes we would give a pair to a child in
need and since we started that years ago
we've helped about 38 million children
it's been much more uh successful and
effective than I ever imagined and since
then we've been able to because all of
our travels and many of them Heather and
I have been on together seen so many
other ways that Toms could help through
our through our business model through
one for one so a couple years ago we
started uh designing beautiful
sunglasses and every time we sell those
we helped pay for uh cataract surgery
for someone who's blind or give children
the prescription glasses they need to go
to school and so that's been uh really
gratifying to get to see how we've moved
from shoes to helping people their
eyesight and then most recently we
launched a coffee company we realized we
could by getting in the coffee business
really trade directly with the farmers
and help improve their lives by allowing
them to trade directly with us and not
have to go through the big export
middleman company so it's been great
we've opened up cafes and Chicago New
York La Austin uh Portland we just
opened up London 3 weeks ago and we have
a store in Amsterdam and our coffee sold
in all the Whole Foods and then we also
launched a line of like tote bags and
backpacks to support U maternal health
issues so it's been really fun to kind
of use the one forone model uh to go
beyond shoes and helping these other
ways
[Music]