originally it it started nine years ago
uh I was uh traveling in Argentina on
vacation um and and when I was there I
was noticing I was there for about a
month that there were many children uh
in the streets and in different areas uh
walking around Barefoot and in
conditions that you wouldn't want to be
barefoot so it was not by choice I could
tell uh and then later in my trip I I
met some women that were doing some
volunteer work and when I asked them
about what they were doing uh we were
chatting in this Cafe they they said
that they were doing something called a
shoe drive and what that meant was they
were collecting slightly used shoes to
give to children in some of the towns
outside of Buenos Iris um because in
those towns the children were required
to wear a uniform to school and part of
the uniform was a pair of shoes and the
shoes was the most expensive part of the
uniform and many of the families could
not afford the shoes especially as kids
feet grow so quickly that you're
constantly having to buy new pairs
exactly and so what we we found was
there were children that desperately
wanted to go to school but they were not
able to because they didn't have the
proper shoes and to me that just seemed
ridiculous you know and so um I got to
know these women and and they invited me
to come with them and I went had this
great experience uh giving shoes that
day it's so joyful and and the kids were
so happy I mean you would have thought
it was it was Christmas day it was
amazing but um but but what I my
question was and my concern was is the
sustainability of the program when it
was based on charity based on donation
because the only way that we that they
could continue to give shoes to the kids
that need them every you know four or
five months as their feet grew was to
get another donation and that didn't
seem very dependable so my background um
you know has always been as an
entrepreneur I started my first company
when I was 19 and so before easy laundry
easy laundry man oh I mean Bill Clinton
has nothing on you look at that um so uh
but I will just point out that Blake did
you launched like really Mega companies
before you did Tom you are you are a
social entrepreneur but you are an
entrepreneur that is correct I love the
idea of using business to solve problems
before Tom's the problems I solved were
were had nothing to do with Charity or
or a social aspect they were just just
everyday business and consumer problems
but um but yeah so so when I saw this
this problem of children not having
shoes to go to school my mind thought
about entrepreneurship not about charity
and I think a lot of people have asked
me and said that seems like such a crazy
idea or or or or you know was that was
so disruptive or these things these
words they've used to describe it to me
it was actually very simple very natural
and and and and and very common sensical
and the the way it was is like if I can
afford to buy a pair of shoes how great
would it be to be able to buy a pair of
shoes and give a pair of shoes I mean
it's you know not not rocket science
like you buy a pair you give a pair you
you can afford it someone else can't so
now you're helping someone at the same
time time and so it was it was really a
very simple idea it was to help 250 kids
in one town in Argentina um nine years
ago and um you know it took off so um I
think the thing I like to talk about
with people you know is that is it it
even if it would have only stayed a
simple idea in terms of only helping 250
kids every time you know for their whole
school year uh it still would have been
worth the idea you know so sometimes
times ideas become big things and
sometimes they stay small but if if your
intent is to help someone and to make
the world a better place through your
idea it it shouldn't be measured in in
how big it becomes it should be measured
more in the intent and I think that you
know uh as I look back I had no idea
that Toms would become what it's become
today and I'm super thankful and I feel
very blessed and I love what we get to
do but I I often like to state that it
the idea itself was uh you know would
have been fine if it stayed
small cuz not everyone's going to have
an idea that becomes massive you know
but everyone can have an idea that can
make a small difference in their
community and take great joy in that and
and and have that be a big part of their
life and like you said if you if you
kind of ascertain a need and you can
fulfill that need it doesn't matter
whether that's to one person or a
million yes you're still helping in some
way cuz the most important thing is the
one person you know and that's why I
really like to focus on the the the
concept of one for one and this will go
to some of the other products that we
are in now is it's about one person
purchasing something uh and helping
another one person around the world and
that's the one for one so we started
with shoes and today we've actually
given away 38 million pairs of shoes so
really 38 million amazing a little bit
more than the 250 we started with but
we've also expanded into eyewear so we
do uh sunglasses and optical frames and
when you buy a pair of our frames uh we
help provide someone a site so we pay
for cataract surgeries for people who
are blind we give prescription glasses
to children who need them to see the
chalkboard and can't afford the eye exam
and the glasses right because as we know
in the in the in the developed world
it's a very very obvious and simple
thing that we go to the optioning
glasses many people can't afford that
and actually classes them as disabled I
mean if you're you can't Farm you can't
learn you can't do anything if you can't
see it's one of the one of the saddest
things is when you're in a place uh you
know I actually uh was in Nepal uh many
years ago and and and seeing kids in the
classroom that were being treated as if
they were disabled but all they were was
they just couldn't see the chalkboard
and so just a simple pair of glasses
literally changed someone's life and we
work with this amazing uh eye doctor
named chundu who works with this
organization called SAA who we do a lot
of work with I will just say on that I
taught at a school in kandu for three
months when I left school oh you did and
all we all we are then we we lived with
the Headmaster for three months in c v
do but all we said is that anything we
can do anything we can bring he said
please bring spectacles get any old
spectacles you can please bring
spectacles and that's how important it
was to that country and I don't think I
then even realized how blessed I was
that at whatever age age 10 I just went
to an optician and was able to see it's
a huge it's huge I mean it's it's
everything I mean if you can't see and
you don't have a way to to improve upon
that then your your life Prospect is so
limited and so um so we work with these
organizations you know to be able to do
that through the sale of our glasses and
I love the fact on on the glasses side
point is that you know obviously
something you wear every day and so it
becomes a part of your identity but it
also becomes a part of your identity
that you chose a very specific pair of
glasses a specific pair of TOMS because
you know that you AV able to help
someone see that wouldn't be able to so
we've used the one for one to move into
that um how do you how do you choose
which countries you work with how that
must be very hard because everybody
needs that well you know our whole model
is really dependent on the NG Community
globally so the non-government
organizations and nonprofits that are
serving in countries whether it's
helping with vaccinations uh malaria
Nets um helping build education you know
schools uh Clean Water Systems these NOS
are kind of addressing the biggest
Global needs and we partner with them to
help distribute our shoes because what
we learned very early on was it was
really important that our shoes were
integrated into the other work that the
community is doing it does it's it's
really not good just to just to give
stuff you know that's really important
when you really learn about the way to
do proper Aid and do it in a sustainable
and responsible way it's all about
integrating into the whole Community
efforts that UNICEF or save the children
or one of these big Global organizations
is doing so so we um we really focus a
lot on working with those partners and
they help guide us as to where we need
to give shoes or where we need to help
with glasses or you know now that we're
in maternal Health where we work in that
so it's really important that the Nos
and the nonprofits are a critical piece
to the kind of Tom's ecosystem and if
you're a Tom's customer they're a
critical piece to the delivery mechanism
that the shoes or the iare is getting to
the people that need it the most um and
the other thing that's so great about
working with them is we create thousands
of local jobs because you know they all
hire locals to help with the
distribution of our shoes and different
and different aspects and then we pay
them a fee on top of giving them the
shoes to be able to fund that so we're
actually creating thousands of local
jobs in each of these communities we
give 65 countries now through the NOS
that we work with it's amazing it's
amazing okay and then after the eyewea
you then launched Tom's Roasting Company
Co yeah which is coffee yes and so one
bag of coffee if you buy one bag of
Tom's coffee you're supplying clean
water to one person for a whole week
right absolutely and that um and that's
in you the the that's in the countries
that you grow the coffee beans in
exactly so a big big Focus for Toms over
the past few years has been to move from
an organization that is largely known
for providing aid but to also be
creating jobs um if you look at poverty
alleviation uh you know the three things
that are are critical are first and
foremost basic needs being met so that's
clean water food shelter shoes Health
needs second is education you know
getting everyone in school especially
girls very very important for any
Community Development and third is job
creation and so you know we very early
on uh only focused on Aid uh then we
actually receiv received some criticism
for that because many people were saying
you know we really think that your
organization if any organization should
be using local manufacturing to create
jobs and so we really listen to the
critics and we changed our model and now
we have Manufacturing in uh India Kenya
Ethiopia and actually last year we
opened a a factory in Haiti and we're
the only people making shoes in Haiti
today um which is really cool because um
many of these people who are working in
our Haiti Factory lost their jobs after
the earthquake and now they have
employment again and they're very proud
and they're doing a great job and and so
that's a big part of our future and the
reason I bring that up is that actually
led us into the coffee business of all
places because as I was learning about
um creating local jobs and and and and
economic development I kept hearing
about the coffee industry as being one
of the greatest Industries in places
that we're giving our shoes gu Guatemala
Honduras Malawi Rwanda Ethiopia these
places are where the greatest coffee in
the world comes from but unfortunately a
lot of times the coffee Growers the
farmers themselves they are having to
sell their beans to this export company
that makes most of the profit in the
sale of the coffee to then to all the
big Mass coffee chains but if you can go
directly to the farmers themselves or to
the co-ops and they call it direct trade
it actually allows the farmers to make a
significant amount more in in in income
therefore they can have a higher quality
of life so by us getting into the coffee
space we're able to not only help uh the
farmers make more money by trading
directly with them and their co-ops but
then also our G our one for one in
coffee is you buy our coffee we give
water because water is the number one
ingredient used in making coffee and in
places like Malawi Rwanda Guatemala
Ethiopia unfortunately
uh clean water is a scarcity and so
making sure that that we are investing
in those communities by providing Clean
Water Systems we're ensuring a better
and safer life for them and also we're
protecting the coffee industry in in the
years to come so a lot of people said
you know especially a lot of people that
you interview uh in the fashion space
okay said okay this guy did shoes now
he's doing eyewear get it get it coffee
what the hell is that all about you know
because it it it seems so Random to go
from these accessories to coffee but if
you think about it in the context of
creating jobs and economic development
having an impact in these communities it
actually makes a lot of sense I also
know with your book starts something
that matters you I said that for every
book sold you would then donate books as
well so you also in the in the literary
department and we have it's so fun
because my favorite book uh is uh this
Dr Seuss book called the places you will
go uh we actually had people in our
wedding in the audience recite different
lines we like it so much um but it was
great because the the the organization
we partnered with on the giving books
once I sold my book um they had the Dr
Seuss titles so I've been able to go to
a lot of the schools and get to read
this book and let all the kids get Dr
Seuss books your book is very cult
because if I kind of search you up on
social media it's amazing how many
people just Instagram that book that
book that book because it represents
that they're it's like everything that
they represents something that they
believe in what you're doing but that
that they're also learning and I I think
that that's what you're what is so
interesting and important about you is
that you're not just doing it you're
also sharing your experience absolutely
and I think that that's really important
not only to the people in this country
but but to the people who you're giving
shoes to it's not just giving shoes
you're actually inspiring
entrepreneurship and learning and I
think it's really important I just I
want to we're going to take a quick
quick look at what you've recently
launched which is do you want to talk
actually let's watch it first and then
we'll talk about it with the bags Tom's
bags y Tom's bags okay you know the
thing that is interesting about us
getting into the bag business is you
know going back to shoes and eyewear
both being accessories many of our
retailers said you know we we're doing
so well with your shoes and your eyewear
we think you should guys should should
do uh some casual handbags you know
totes backpacks these types of things
and I remember first hearing that from
our retailers and saying well yeah we
could probably sell lots of bags but
there's not really a clear one for one
it's not like we're going to sell a bag
give a bag like the world doesn't need
more bags and so we actually put the
idea on hold for quite a bit of time it
been a couple years since our retailers
had asked us to do bags and it wasn't
until someone in our giving group um
which we have this amazing group at Toms
that all they do is focus on you know
giving every day which is incredible to
think for a for-profit business that
there's 35 people in La that just
scrutinize how we give where we give you
know how better to give but one of the
people in the giving group you know came
to me and said you know I think I have a
way that we can really you know um
maximize the commercial opportunity in
bags because um in in in many places
around the world you know women are
giving birth in their homes and in many
developing countries are giving birth in
their homes and areas that are not very
sterile and not very safe for giving
birth and so we have heard about these
un health workers that distribute these
birth kits that come in a bag and so I
said perfect now we have our bag for bag
so will'll sell a bag but we'll give a
bag that contains a birth kit and what a
birth kit is is it's very simple uh you
know a Necessities for giving a safe
birth in your home whether you have a
midwife or you have a friend or a family
member helping you so it's a drapery
that goes on the ground so then now it's
sterile it's the uh tool to cut the
umbilical cord which is really important
because often times when they're cutting
that with something that's not sterile
they get infection which leads
unfortunately to horrible things even
death for the mom or the child uh the
you know the gloves all the different
materials um needed to give a safe birth
and these birth kits as simple as they
are they reduce maternal and infant
mortality by 80% I mean it's a huge
Lifesaver I mean and that com and in
addition to the education that comes
with it and training The Midwives uh is
a is a really big deal so someone can
buy a simple you know tote for you know
$75 and and and that birth kit could
save someone's life it's amazing it's
really amazing working with Christy I
don't know if you know her or not but I
she's an amazing woman um Every Mother
Counts the organization that she started
uh is is really a leader in maternal
health and christe and I went to Haiti
together and I really learned a lot
about maternal Health through Christie
and her organization so it was great to
partner with them for the launch of this
okay well um long may it continue when
you were first starting all of this I
just want to go and ask you about your
the because you know everyone has an
initiative but you've turned an
initiative into a brand a global brand
so when you had all these original ideas
and that you've built and you've grown
and you've grown and you've grown how
did this actually get off the ground in
the very beginning I remember hearing
something about when Anna winter called
you American called you right can you
you know if I'm a young entrepreneur and
I want to start something how important
is is it is press for you and how
important is it for you to Market
yourself well I mean the great thing
about and I didn't I wish I was I I
could say I was like smart enough to
realize this was a strategy but I wasn't
I just it turned out to in hindsight to
see this a great strategy is what we had
and what what allowed us to break
through and to really take an initiative
and turn it into a global brand and what
we still have today and what we focus
the most on is exactly what you and I
are doing today and that is the power of
story you know and I talk a lot about
this in my book but you know when I
started Toms and the and the interns and
and young people that I kind of gathered
together to help me um you know all we
really had was a pretty Amazing Story we
didn't really realize it was amazing but
it was you know this idea of like
meeting some kids that need to shoes in
Argentina and all of a sudden selling
shoes and giving shoes and and it was
this very kind of radical idea that a
fashion company would sell something and
then give something away every time they
sell it and that was a story that kind
of captivated people like Anna wintor
Vogue and other people at you know some
of the big department stores in America
because they just hadn't heard of
anything like that and I think what
fashion often is um is is is known for
and Prides itself on is very disruptive
ideas you know um so the the designers
that break out are creating something
disruptive U Radical Something New a
fresh perspective and so we did it in a
very different way not necessarily like
our design was really radical it
actually very simple uh incredibly
simple um which I think that is is is is
so surreal to be sitting here in the
Apple Store thinking about how much I
looked up to you know the design of
Apple you know creating such Elegance
out of Simplicity and so that's what the
original shoe the Tom's classic is
something I pride myself because I felt
like it was the most simple piece of
Footwear ever because it was just
literally a simple canvas draped over
you know the sole no laces no nothing
else um so I always used to think about
Apple when I was doing design in the
early days so it's very surreal to be
sitting here now N9 years later uh in a
store giving a talk so I'm just going to
take a moment now look around and enjoy
that CU if you don't do that then um
you'll go by too fast um but but I
really think that you know the the
ability to tell a story and to
communicate a story that was um very
approachable for people you know I had
no experience in Footwear no experience
in retail frankly didn't even know who
Anna was until I got the phone call um
because I had never read a Vogue
magazine and uh and and and and so it
was easy for people to say gosh this is
a guy that saw something that was you
know some kids needed help and he did
something about it he made these shoes
you know we made them in people's
garages in Argentina and and now he's
helping people and I could do that too
and I think that's that story is was
able a story that people were able to
spread through YouTube and social media
and everything and that's what allowed
the Tom's idea to be become much bigger
than just a simple initiative and
actually become this this brand that
it's become today and and the Vogue
shoot I I mean I whatever I researched
you but someone at Vogue rang you up
like yeah I'll do a shoot thinking it
will take you half an hour before you
went for lunch with your friends and
then like 7 hours later you were still
doing the shoot yeah so I I I it was it
was it was my very first photo shoot um
and it was for Vogue which is pretty
amazing and they said yeah they said uh
you know the shoot we need you to meet
you meet you in Venice on Abbot Kenny uh
at I think it was 10:30 and so I said
okay great so I said I told my buddy I
would have lunch with him at noon cuz I
thought you'll take an hour and then
I'll get to lunch and like s hours later
they given me haircuts they had changed
my clothes 10 times they had taken
pictures all over and they only used one
picture I was like man right they only
this is what I they only use one it's
fascinating it's fascinating but that
had an impact right so because because
you were an example I I was surprised to
learn that it really had an impact so
you'd had however many shoes already in
your Warehouse to go and then the Vogue
article ran and then suddenly you had
orders not only from individuals but
from stores websites so there is power
and press and you're an example of that
there is and I think what's exciting is
is that there's there's there's more
opportunities to get a story out today
than ever before back then N9 years ago
it was more the the traditional media
and and even in the traditional media
only in the print form now you know I
mean this this podcast that we're doing
now hopefully will be heard by thousands
maybe millions of people someday and
they can learn from that and and uh and
grow from that and I think that's what's
so exciting right now about being an
entrepreneur and I'm investing in a
bunch of social entrepreneurs now and
when I talked to them I said the great
thing is like there it's not just the
big companies now that can get a message
across it's really the best message the
best stories rise to the top and get
spread the most and I think that's
what's you know so exciting about the
time that we're living in right now um
but you know that that Vogue article and
and other articles led to more people
talking about it but the the the main
reason that Tom's grew the fast as it
did it I I don't believe that it was any
of the traditional media and it was that
the fact that our customers internalized
own and celebrated the giving that they
were doing and they were the ones that
would share the story so when you were
wearing your first pair of TOMS and and
I'm sure that you're one of the first
people wearing them someone said you
know uh you know they said you know you
know canar what what are those shoes you
would never just say Toms you would say
Toms have you heard about this company
when they sell a pair of shoes they give
a pair of shoes I mean this is what this
is what you would you would have done I
presume right and I and anyone in the
audience who's worn Toms I'm I'm sure
that you've shared the story so you're
not just helping one child when you buy
a pair of shoes but you're helping many
more for every time you shared the story
and and I had many experiences in the
early days of meeting people in
different places you know and and
hearing their Tom story and they would
tell me the story sometimes not even
knowing who I was and it was such a
delight and so I think that's really the
power of of of what we tapped into was
that that people people I think as human
beings want to do good they want to help
one another um sometimes it's hard so we
made it easy but then we also made it
easy for them to share what they had
done by wearing it and talking about it
okay and you as a brand and you as a Hu
an individual are very good at sharing
the story so how did you go about s of
sitting down and you thinking I think
that video is going to be really
important for me I think social media is
going to be really important for me
because you're really really good at
that as a brand the signature the
communication you have not with your
customers but with with the kind of
brand identity for me is is exceptional
and I work with companies all the time
who don't always get it right is that
your um is that up to you is that down
to you is that your vision or have you
got really smart people working for you
because they say don't employ people who
can do what you do employ people who can
do something different from what you
well a I have a lot of not just smart
people but smarter people than me
working for me so that's a given or we
would never be here right that's so
that's a real key right that is a key I
will say on the social media and the
video and that stuff it was actually the
fact that we had no money and that was
the cheapest way to get our story out or
was actually free I mean that was a
beautiful thing about YouTube and some
of the early things is you know
especially Facebook in the early days
before all the advertising you could
communicate with so many people and and
not it was really your time I mean I
remember for hours every night
responding to people's post and this and
that and it was so much a part of just
the way it was our only vehicle to do it
cuz we didn't have money for advertising
and promotion and events and these
things so so but as we've grown and as
it's become a little bit of a blend
between more of Art and Science because
you know social media is a big business
now and it is a true medium in which
your brands are building their message
you know I think we have a group of
incredibly talented young people at
Tom's that are living and breathing all
these different you know uh vehicles and
they're and they're and they're actually
helping me understand which ones make
the most sense you know which ones are
the the most authentic so for instance I
mainly use Instagram and that's because
it's authentic it's easy for me to do
now now I have a baby so most of my
Instagrams are my baby so it's probably
not as interesting to social
entrepreneurs as it is to maybe U my
parents but um so um but but I promise
I'm going to get back to in posting some
really inspiring stuff besides my
five-month-old but um but but you know I
think that was one of the great things
is for a while I was trying to kind of
use all these platforms and I really
wasn't really excited about it but then
I but I loved posting fun pictures of
places and travels and partners and
stuff and so one of the smart people on
our team said you know that's the most
authentic way for you to show up in
social media now there's other ways you
know through Linkedin and Twitter and
Facebook that as a company we really
show up but you yourself should just do
the one that you feel the most um you'll
do the most spontaneous because that's
what people really engage in when it's
real okay and how do you engage you're
traveling so much much so you have to
engage with your company how do you
engage with the recipients of your
kindness so the great thing is is that
um you know I have really never been
running the day-to-day of TOMS I've
always had amazing teams at Tom's you
know kind of in La running the you know
keeping the Train on the tracks and and
that's allowed me the freedom to be out
sharing the story visiting our giving
Partners you know I try to go on two
trips a year usually one in the fall and
one in the spring um and you know last
last before we had the baby I went to
Haiti and I got to not only meet the
factory workers but then go on a shoe
giving experience and then also travel
around and kind of explore Haiti in a in
a in a in a more intimate way than I
ever had before um the year before that
I was in Rwanda meeting our coffee
Farmers but also giving shoes um so
every every year I get to do a couple of
these trips and it's a great way for me
to reconnect with the original intent
that I spoke about before um because
there's nothing like actually being
there and placing a shoe on a kid's foot
and seeing their smile seeing their
parents being excited and playing with
them and just you you you forget about
all the stress and all the stupid stuff
we worry about in our regular lives when
you're out in the field and serving in
that way and so um those trips are
really important for me they're really
important for my wife too she comes on
many of them sometimes she goes on them
without me my parents go on them you
know all the Tom staff members we pay
for them to go on them every other year
so that's a big investment for us but
one that we see is so important so they
get to see the the the the the work
that's happening no matter if they work
in accounting or design or giving or
whatnot so that's the way that I really
stay connected uh to to the people that
we're serving okay okay well um we're
going to open up for audience questions
now if you have a question for Tom just
raise your hand and um someone from the
Apple team where lots of people we're g
we're going to start we'll just pass
along each someone's going to give you a
microphone Rosie just here will put your
hand up put your hand up again let's
start with the gentleman hello uh my
name is k I started a footwear company
last year through crowdfunding and I
wanted to ask how is it for you to in
the early stages to build a team and
obviously you had a story but like in
terms of getting people to believe in
you and to be as dedicated to you as as
you were yeah how did you manage to do
that great so good question and
congratulations on starting your
business um I think the most important
thing is as quickly as you can um take
it from being your story to our story
you know um I was very fortunate in the
very early days that I had a group of um
very passionate interns uh that you know
we're working at local un or or studying
at local universities we're looking for
a summer internship um you know they
were not going to be able to get paid
because we didn't have the budget for
that initially but they knew that they
would get to work you know directly with
with me they'd get to learn and they'd
get to really be part of the the
creation of this this this idea and I
think that you know I always say to
entrepreneurs interns are fantastic
because a you're no longer lonely
because you got a bunch of people around
you and B you know they kind of help
they they they start to own the
experience and and the initiative as
well and then they're also more
storytellers so I think the first thing
is to take it from your story to our
story and then it becomes more powerful
and there's more uh kind of momentum
around it and I think really good
internships for young companies are the
best ones because you get so much more
responsibility and you get to do so much
more absolutely that's the best bit y
good luck to you thank you okay hi um I
am not from the business part at all I'm
a I have actually a masters in
healthcare and I'm actually I just moved
here from New York and I won't be
working for the next two to three years
just enjoying and traveling is there any
way that I could volunteer help out
using my masters in healthcare because I
know I it's always nice to give back and
that's what that's why I was in the
profession anyways that's great well
it's very very nice of you to offer um
you know the the best way to volunteer
is really with our giving partners
because I as I discussed earlier the
giving partners are really the the last
mile of the process they're the ones
that are actually getting the shoes onto
the children's feet are working in the
eye camps so you know we we still go on
trips and we take you know kind of um
our our our employees or sometimes
vendors or we do contest where people
can win but but but most of the giving
happens 365 days a year with our giving
Partners so one way would be to go onto
the Tom's website and to research
different giving partners and then
depending on where you would like to
volunteer to talk to the giving partner
directly because that's the best way to
volunteer great thank you uh hi there um
I read your book about a year ago and
amazing phenomenal and um for the last
year I've been designing my own business
uh business called Rupa great um we're a
teddy bear business and every bear we
sell we're going to feed a hungry child
for a whole year school year for great
charity called Mary's Mills um and I
know you've just launched well about a
year ago a couple years ago you launched
the marketplace over in the US um saw
some really cool companies on there is
there any sort of like a couple of
really great companies that you're
really excited about and sort of Shar
that story um and if I can also be
really cheeky and who can I talk to to
get on that Marketplace yeah so uh the
lady in the green hat in The Far Side
here uh would be the person to talk to
afterwards about the marketplace so
that's great um for those of you don't
know the marketplace is this concept
that we want to as we grow we also want
to help other young social entrepreneurs
grow as well so I'm personally making a
lot of investments in Social
entrepreneurs now um but also Tom's as a
company is putting them on a digital
platform on toms.com so we can share
other people's stories and the work that
they're doing um so there's a lot of
social entrepreneurs and sounds like
your business would be a great fit for
that so you can talk to Ally on that um
and what was the first part of the
question sorry I got on the marketplace
about the other other businesses that oh
so a couple exciting ones um you know I
think one of my favorite ones is this
one called join Jo y n uh it's a a girl
from the United States that moved to
India
and she works with the most
ostracized um people in India lepers and
and people who have no uh ability to get
any gainful employment at all she takes
them and she teaches them block printing
techniques and she creates beautiful
Fabrics that then become bags we've
actually made some shoes out of her
Fabrics um but she has an amazing line
of bags and different stuff that's on
the marketplace uh her name is Melody
and she's and she's really an amazing
woman um and her company join is one to
look at in the marketplace um that I
specifically like a lot so great thank
you okay you um can you just pass the
microphone
backwards hi I'm Willa I'm from
Amsterdam and I started my own uh
communication agency in sustainable
fashion and lifestyle about four or five
years ago and I was wondering um since I
work with a lot of Brands who um feel
that it's very difficult to monitor
their production process I was wondering
how as a S I mean we know all about the
front end and of course I also read
about the the back end a little bit but
maybe you can explain a little bit how
you manage to monitor the production
process of Tom's products sure so you
know really we look at using third
parties mainly um so different firms
that we hire to do announced and
unannounced audits uh we also have an
interior internal team that has that
responsibility as their day job as well
the thing that's really challenging from
a production stand point is not
necessarily monitoring the factories
where your products are made but the
actual suppliers that's the thing that I
didn't understand when I first got in
this business I thought you know okay if
we monitor the factories we have a a
code of conduct that every Factory signs
you know that that was enough but what
we found in the in the in the most
recent years is you really have to go
all the way down to the supplier level
that is much easier for us to do now
because we're making tens of millions of
shoes a year so we have purchasing power
so we can put our leverage of purchasing
power to make sure suppliers follow our
code of conduct but as you're saying
with a lot of new brands are starting
out it's very very difficult I wish I
had like a great answer for that in
terms of what to do because it's
something we struggled with too so you
know the so it's a very thing hard thing
when you're first getting started
wouldn't it be interesting to do
something along the lines of marketplace
and then in sourcing you know opening up
those sources and becoming more
transparent for other smaller companies
to also start producing um in a good way
yeah I think it's a great idea yeah
thank you okay we have time for like one
or two more one at the front please
thank you
thanks you've achieved so much in nine
years um I just wanted to know where you
see Toms in the next 10 years how the
company will grow man um you know it's
like I was going to ask that but I was
too scared cuz I was like he's done so
much already I can't ask like what's
um we talk about Tom's years like dog
years like one year seems like so much
happens um so it's really hard to think
10 years out um I have trouble thinking
10 months out sometimes but I think that
overall I mean you know I think what
what what my vision has has has evolved
into is Tom's to not only be an
organization that is creating great
products that people love and enjoy
every day that can make a difference in
people's lives but Tom's to be a leader
and and really the movement of social
business and to be an organization that
whether it's celebrating other social
entrepreneurs through Marketplace or
creating Community outposts like we're
opening in London today where people can
come and have dialogue and discussions
about this learn about new businesses
maybe such as yourselves you know that's
I think what my kind of dream for Tom's
is is really to play a role in the
future of business and in culture as
much as in creating the products and so
that might lead us into content it might
lead us into entertainment it might lead
us into you know things like Hospitality
I mean one of the things that I've I've
often thought it would be amazing is to
have a series of Tom's hotels where
every night you stay in a room at a
Tom's hotel we take a homeless person
off the street done deal do it do it
that's a great idea it' be amazing I
think if you it doesn't have to be a
festar hotel like a for everyone I think
just a cool you know simple uh space and
how great are I always say it' be the
best night sleep you've ever had because
you know that you're helping someone
else at the same time so it's things
like that that we're talking about and
thinking about but um you know I'm young
I'm 38 I have a lot of years hopefully
to do this so uh so we'll we'll keep
going I have one thing to say I watched
a video where all these kids had just
been given Tom shoes and they were so
happy and they were playing football
yeah but the football was a plastic bag
with Earth inside and I thought that is
so sad that children don't even have
access to a ball if think what Joy
football does for a community so maybe
somehow you can incorporate footballs
into what you do with sports shoes or
something because it's broke my heart
yeah actually on the marketplace there's
a great uh football company okay good
yeah and it's buy a ball give a ball
okay buy a ball everyone seriously know
what football does for communities for
women and men it's so important it's
just a ball yeah well well play is so
important I mean you know I mean in many
of these places you know life is really
tough and and in kids being able to play
and dream and and that is such an
important thing and football is the
universal sport um and so you know
that's one of the things that we love to
do when we go on the giving trips is
after we distribute the shoes we almost
always play football so it's I'm not
very good but it's a lot of fun okay
great and I have one last question I'm
goingon to have to close um who who were
Your Heroes who do you look up to you
know there's I mean I i' I've had the
great pleasure I think and and and
privilege really through Tom's uh to get
to meet all kinds of amazing people
doing amazing things whether it's you
know you know Marketplace Founders or
it's you know different people that we
work with in some of the local factories
uh to people who maybe are know more
well known I I think that you know uh I
guess it was last year I had the
opportunity to meet a hero I had always
looked up to named Muhammad Eunice and
if you don't know who Professor Eunice
is he started the gine bank and the gine
bank was really the first of its kind to
uh give loans to the poorest of the poor
and what Muhammad UNIS Learned was if
you create a a loan structure through
Community lending to the poor of the
poor they will actually repay the loans
better than all of us repay our loans
here in this audience which is hard to
believe um but so so Muhammad Unis
showed that it could be profitable he
could actually create a for-profit
business helping the poorest of the poor
get loans they desperately need to
create businesses of their own and as an
entrepreneur myself that's one of the
most beautiful things I've ever seen and
it's it's largely women uh and and and
and it's usually loans of under $30 but
with that they can either start a candle
business or cheese business or you know
dairy or all these different things and
then sometimes they lead to bigger
Enterprises and and it's it's always
just such an exciting thing when I am in
these communities and I see a micro
credit or micro Finance program many
times you know started or inspired by
the gine bake and Professor Unice and
and I see how powerful that is is and
changing someone's life because it
allows often times many women to take
control of their Destiny and their
future and then they get more respect in
the community and then when women get
more respect in the community then more
girls go to school when more girls go to
school everything is better and so it
really uh you know there's a great video
called the girl effect I'm sure you've
seen it if you haven't you know as soon
as you're done listening to this watch
the girl effect video it's a very good
explanation of how powerful it is when
we invest in girls in developing
countries and so Muhammad Unice has done
an amazing job in that um I'm actually
working with Muhammad Unice on some
ideas that maybe we could incorporate
into Tom's for the future but he's
something I really look up to okay great
great okay we have to end there I could
go on forever and ever thank you so much
much thank you so much thank you great
thank you that was great