[Music]
hi I'm Blake Mycoskie the founder and
chief shoe giver of Tom's
and you're watching behind the brand
with Brian Elliott Pam Brian Elliott
welcome to another edition of behind the
brand today I'm here with Blake at Tom's
headquarters
Blake thanks for having me I'm so glad
you're here I usually ask my guests
how'd you get this job yeah well I had
the greatest job in the world I think
and I guess the way I got it is I
invented it so it all started 12 years
ago when I was on a farm in Argentina I
saw many children down there that didn't
have shoes and I wanted to do something
to help and so my background was not in
philanthropy or in charity my background
was as an entrepreneur and so I've
always had thought about using
entrepreneurship solve problems usually
commercial problems but in this case I
wanted to sell a societal one and
created this this idea that if we could
sell a pair of shoes today we would give
away a pair of shoes tomorrow and we
actually call them tomorrow shoes at
first but then that was too long for the
tag so like here my shoe here I tried to
put tomorrow's into there and it didn't
fit so I named it tops that's awesome
let's go back on the timeline a little
bit yeah back to young Blake yeah what
did you want to be when you grew up when
I when I was younger and I thought about
a career or like you know like in like
elementary school or whatever they ask
you you know what you want to be
I always said a fireman and it were
actually as two things it was it was a
there wouldn't be a fireman or would be
a truck driver but I like liked the idea
of driving a big truck okay interesting
yeah and I think I also like the idea of
kind of like helping people but also the
idea of traveling to new places and my
dad was a doctor my grandfather was a
doctor my aunt was a nurse every one of
my family was in the medical profession
but we'd never really spoke to me did
they try and persuade you to go a
certain direction and like like you know
take up LA go for a medicine that's one
of the things I'm really thankful for is
my parents were both thinking
probably supportive of whatever I wanted
to do I ended up you know going to you
know college on a tennis scholarship and
then I had an injury and I dropped out
of college and I started this laundry
business which was my first company and
you know most parents I think if you if
you called them and said you know I'm
dropping out of this wonderful
University to do people's laundry I
think they would have a little bit of a
pause but my parents like will thought
you want you want to do and and and you
feel it's a way to build a career then
great and so they were very supportive
that's my earlier entrepreneurial but
you hadn't you know you were playing a
maybe a pro athletic career you sure
yeah I'm in my whole life and I'm and I
and I attribute a lot of the work ethic
and the discipline and the elements that
make an entrepreneur successful to my my
my training is a young tennis player I
actually lived at a tennis academy at
age 15 moved away from home you know
started training at five every single
morning you know like not going to the
movies with friends on Friday and
Saturday nights and still training like
I was a very very disciplined I always
say that like I had my work ethic in my
tennis career is the only reason guys as
far as it did I had very little talent
but I had a lot of work ethic and so
that's how I at least got to the college
level well and maybe as I get to know
you maybe you can add heart to that yeah
it's one of the things coaches talk a
lot about like you can't teach can't
teach heart yeah you know work ethic
like that movie Rudy comes to me I love
Rudy so my favorite movies yeah it's the
only movie I've ever like really cried
in like hard like I just like that movie
hit me so hard it might be one of my
favorite movies yeah and it's because
he's all heart write plays with his
heart I think I think I self-identified
a lot of that character and and that's
why that movie was such an important I
mean literally like it's funny I think
back like early days like when we had
MySpace pages and you had like a
favorite movie mine was always Rudy so
interesting you brought that up that's
awesome
you know we could dig into that to the
the the psyche of that are the
interesting psychological implications
too about you know being an underdog and
you know being gritty and maybe having
not success along the way but I also
wanted to ask
when you got injured how did you feel
because that must have been devastating
you know you put in all that time you're
away from home you're basically you know
like David Beckham you know and in
Soccer Academy for yeah his youth and
then it all falls apart yeah I mean you
know it's I often cite that great Garth
Brooks song I thank God for unanswered
prayers because you know I I was
literally devastated and praying that my
leg would heal and I'd get back on the
court and that I would be able to resume
this career and then at a point it
became very clear that that just wasn't
gonna happen and at that same time that
led to the founding of my first business
which was the laundry business and the
reason I got in the laundry business is
I was on crutches and I literally
couldn't carry my laundry down to the
facility and this is back when we had
the Yellow Pages before Google and so I
looked in the Yellow Pages for someone
to come pick up my laundry and there was
no one to do that and so I thought you
know this should be a business like a
lot of people probably would love their
laundry to be picked up and so so this
injury that seems so tragic actually was
the impetus of my entrepreneurial career
which I am incredibly deeply grateful
for because I realized that that was
really my gift and my calling maybe all
the tennis and all the athletics and the
training was actually exactly that
training so that I would have these
these skill sets in this self this
self-reliance
tennis is an individual sport being an
entrepreneur can be very lonely so so I
think a lot of that was in training for
me to be able to you know really thrive
as an entrepreneur that's good stuff how
long did it take you to come to that
realization I mean maybe the injury
itself you figured okay my career's over
but like from the time that you realized
it's over to the day that you reinvented
yourself how long many years yeah yeah I
don't think I don't think I was able to
really look back on that with that that
that sense of gratitude that I have now
to the injury in that sense of thanking
God for unanswered prayers
until years years later you know I think
it was it was very painful to not be
able to play even after I started a
laundry business even after it became
successful it took time to really look
back on that with kind of a different
set of eyes what's your perspective on
it now as you reflect what was that a
because I'm not necessarily a everything
happens for a reason guy mmm I think I
think that sometimes I'm sure there's a
higher power and oh yeah you know I'm a
spiritual guy yeah but I also recognize
that just stuff happens because you're
at the right place or the wrong place at
the right time or the wrong time what's
your perspective though on that now like
so I'm a very much everything having
true reason yeah okay and even more so
every day now in Niger know a lot and
that's been something I've been doing
some 15 and if I go back and read
journals I can see unbelievable things
that I've written that literally come
true six months later I mean in a way
that that like freaks me out I mean this
is the craziest thing that's happened
recently okay and and I've never shared
this when this happened last week okay
so about three years ago I just randomly
was looking at a Patagonia catalog and
on the cover of the catalog was this
snowboarder making this beautiful turn
and like deep-powder
in Japan and and I love snowboarding
miss still wearing since a 13 I've never
once taken a like it tear it out a
picture from a magazine or catalog but I
had this vision board in my in my home
office where I put things that I really
want to kind of like have my life vision
be a part of and energetically like I
feel like there's everything that I put
up there somehow becomes important in my
life and so I took this thing three
years ago and I posted it on there and I
did it because I was like hey I want to
be able to snowboard like this someday
and be I would love to be able to go to
Japan and experience that weightlessness
of the powder right that was my thought
so I put it up there three years ago so
recently my wife and I are spending a
lot more time in Jackson Hole
and about two weeks ago I got introduced
to this pro snowboarder named Alex Yoder
and in someone just because you guys are
very so fully connected like he's a very
soulful guy he's creating this whole
coffee company to be producing or
promoting regenerative farming in
agriculture like you guys should ride
together and I was like wow I get to
ride at the professional snowboarder
like it's so cool and so I go Ryan he's
actually giving me some tips and like
I'm loving it and and he and and insa
then like the next day like we've come
here for dinner and his girlfriend like
he's become like my new buddy and like
and I'm really like kind of helping him
with his business now and he's helping
me with my snowboarding and it's kind of
my wife's like say this is like my total
man crush right like we're really like
kind of you know really bonding fast and
so lovely this happened a couple days
ago when I was in Jackson he said video
me doing this like turn and because I
wanted to show you on something you can
do better on your snowboarding technique
so I video him and now looking at the
video and I looked down and there was
this moment in his turn that looks so
familiar and I went to him and I said
Alex this is a crazy question but have
you ever been on a cover of a Patagonia
catalog
he said yes once three years ago and so
he has been I know right it's crazy like
it literally has been on my vision board
for three years I never know why and now
he's like my new best friend and Jackson
who I'm helping him build his business
and he's helped me snowboard so I do
feel like I have so many experiences
like that to have my life whether you
call it manifesting or everything
happens for a reason where I can look
back and say okay I learned I met that
or I learned that person so I could
learn this and this thing happened which
seemed to be a tragedy or a downturn
because it opened the door to this and
it literally I can weave my whole life
and so now like even with the most
recent stuff that's happened you know in
our and our campaign and gun violence
like it's like oh I was being prepared
for this so as you're telling me the
story about your injury there's a signal
it's obvious and physical yeah but like
you know it should get your attention
mentally like okay you need to start
shifting your focus elsewhere sure and I
guess the lesson is what I
point out and underscore for the
audience I think a lot of people like me
will try and just put that you know
square peg in the round hole until it
jams in there and maybe there there's a
better place for it to fit yeah I think
that's an interesting thing for
entrepreneurs and athletes to really be
able to think about and that is when is
it a point in time we just need to push
harder and work harder to achieve the
goal and when is at a time when you're
putting a square peg in a round hole and
what I talk to when I talk to
entrepreneurs and I speak at colleges I
say you know like when you have your
business idea if it if it doesn't pretty
quickly like find an audience and and
one that is like yes I'm in I want to be
a customer it might be a square peg in a
round hole now to make your idea
successful creates a tremendous amount
of pushing and pushing and pushing but
just the general idea like if you can't
find an audience or a customer base
pretty quickly but that's genius or I
want that or I've always needed a watch
like that or I've always you know like
then I think you know sometimes people
waste a lot of time and money trying to
market an idea that doesn't have a
natural home and so so I think that
there is a lot to being able to decide
for the difference between when it just
needs a little bit more effort or when
you're trying to do something it
probably isn't the right use of your
time or energy or skills that's a great
point and it's something I think about
all the time is how long do you give
this with quotes great idea yeah yeah
until you cut bait or yeah should you
push through let's talk about some of
the other things that we should be
measuring because I think a lot of us me
included gets stuck on the vanity
metrics mmm I think it was some of
Netflix's famous for saying when someone
asked them you know show us the
analytics for a particular show you know
how many people are downloading how many
people are watching how many hours and
they're like listen that's not a really
good measure of whether or not something
is great or not sometimes it takes a
while to develop the characters or
develop a show or do you know so they
don't share metrics as openly say is
like a Nielsen rating or yeah that for
that reason
and they've had a lot of great success
because of it but what are some of the
other things that we should be you know
think about people who have their own
businesses there yeah either starting
something causal like you're doing we'll
jump in a second but also just trying to
build a brand watch what else should we
be looking at and measuring I think
they're one of the most important things
to measure is how many people are
evangelical about your brand like he's
so passionate that they just have to
share it like like because as like Seth
Godin writes and they're in the book
tribes which I love it's like you don't
need that many people to build something
really big you just need enough people
who are just all in and so I think
that's one of the metrics that that
really made Toms grow so fast like good
one my favorite stories is like in the
first three or four months after
starting Tom's I was in New York City
and I ran into this girl in the airport
and she was wearing a red pair of Tom's
and I had never seen a stranger wearing
our shoes so imagine this like I you
know started this company I'm in my
apartment here in Venice I'm in New York
trying to get more stores to buy the
shoes actually totally struck out I was
not having a good day I go to American
Airlines I'm checking in and there's
this woman mid-30s you know wearing a
pair of red tones it's like a singer
hearing yeah exactly
awesome and so I hear this and I heard
here as I see this and I say to her I
couldn't help but noticing these awesome
red shoes you know what are they because
I'm curious to hear her story of how she
got him like where'd she get them and
and so but at the same time I don't want
to give away Who I am so she looks at me
and she says they're toms and I was like
oh cool and I'm doing the check-in you
know still and she really wanted my
attention so she literally physically
grabbed my shoulder as a stranger in the
airport and said no you don't understand
this is the most amazing company in the
world when I bought this pair of shoes
they gave a pair to a child in Argentina
and there's this guy who started the
company he lives in Los Angeles I think
he lives on a boat I mean literally she
started telling me like my life story
word for word like more passion than my
mom tells it right she was invested
investing and so I said her this is a
kind of funny brother story I said to
her I said yeah how did tell her I was
right so I said actually you know I'm
Blake
I started Tom's and she looks at me like
deer in headlights and she goes why did
you cut your hair that was her one
question because I had like long hair
and the YouTube videos as she saw me
giving shoes away and I cut it that
summer but the thing is my point in
sharing that is is I recognized at that
moment that if we had enough of those
people like who were talking telling our
story to strangers in the airport that
if we could just really focus on that
metric of having as many of those people
involved in Tom's and actually equipping
them by taking them on giving trips and
and giving them you know access to me
and and the whole thing they would build
the movement at Tom's and I think that's
you know how we scaled and you know grew
you know so fast and in such a short
period of time yeah and I think they
call that a groundswell or you know it
you know it goes viral or whatever
there's an important metric because I
think a lot of people focus on numbers
and volume but it's actually if you take
some time to build that really really
committed small base they will build it
for you and I think that's you know
that's a really really important thing
that we're constantly even now that
we've grown so much trying to still
figure out how do we do that well
staying on Tom's for a second what
mistakes did you make early on you know
corporate responsibility was not buzzy
or popular when you started I mean
you're sort of the poster child right
you know this no one yes yes it was not
it it was a very lonely place back then
for sure and I'm sure people called it
you crazy yeah believe me money to all
that stuff but like what mistakes now
here we're talking you know decades
later no I'm not that old what one
decade later the biggest mistake is it
almost sunk the company and it's a story
that I love telling because I think it's
it's it's indicative of what we were
trying to do but also what to watch out
for when you're making big change so
actually what most people don't know
about Tom's is that there are two things
that I was trying to do is start ops one
help kids get shoes and two I absolutely
was like did
tested the amount of waste that the shoe
industry created with all these
cardboard boxes
so the original Tom's had no boxes there
were just shoes they were rubber band
together and then there was an organic a
kind of recycled linen bag that they
came in and it was beautiful and it was
raw and it came from Argentina and I
loved it and that's how we started and
so when I would go into my pitch I'd say
we do two things we help kids get shoes
every time you buy beer and we create no
unnecessary waste with boxes which I was
very proud of that works great in our
d2c business because we would ship them
you know to to them in the packer but
when I got into Nordstrom's the first
time they said we love what you're doing
we're gonna carry you like we never like
come into a brand this early but we
really believe in this but we need boxes
and I looked at the Nordstrom buyer and
I was so naive and cocky and all these
things back then I said well then we
won't do business together
and there are the coolant that's like
yeah like we don't do boxes and they're
like we're Nordstrom like like like you
know we have a supply chain we have the
same two shelves and I'm like look if
you wanted to business this it's the
bags and so luckily because I think we
had this article in vogue and we were
pretty hot and there was they said okay
let's try it you know see if it works so
we went in there and they put the bags
and they had a string and then this tag
and they put them in to the shelves and
just like they predicted within a week
they were so tangled that no one could
sell a pair of shoes yeah I mean
literally like the box is so important
to how shoes get stacked and sold and so
our sales the first week were offered a
great start
the second week they went to zero I mean
like not just like a couple pairs like
zero plummeting so I would never forget
I went to this store in New Jersey and I
was August traveling then at the time
living on an Airstream like selling his
shoes out of the back of it and I went
to this Nordstrom I'm like what happened
like you sold like 30 pairs last weekend
zero he's like we can't this these bags
are tangled so literally we got kicked
out of Nordstrom's so like like we told
you like you know come back to us when
you have boxes and so it took us like
six months a to get the box right and
then B to like convince them to give us
another chance but I mean like luckily
they gave us another chance but yeah
like so what my
was the biggest mistake we made because
it almost we almost like literally sunk
the business renewer Shem and B but it
was also when the great lessons is like
there are some things in every industry
that we would all probably like to
change but just aren't worth like the
bigger picture like like I never would
have been able to give 88 million shoes
to children around the world had I stuck
with the bags and so that's that's one
of the biggest mistakes and good lessons
I learned yeah that's great I love that
story and it's all about you know upside
versus downside right yeah you can stick
to your guns stick to your you know your
values or what you think is right but
sometimes you have to be a little bit
more adaptable yeah you also have to be
I think what I didn't understand then is
I was so focused on the environmental
issue of using boxes and not doing it
and not doing things like every other
company had but I think I also was not
humble enough to really try to
understand why the box existed you know
like well it wasn't like it wasn't
responsible like throwing plastic in the
ocean or something yeah yeah yeah you
know like turtles weren't dying yeah
yeah you can recycle them yeah and it
wasn't and so I was I was willing to
fall on the sword or for something that
I really didn't understand why this
world existed so yeah yeah that is a
good lesson whenever I get really like
my dad has a saying about me he says
often wrong but never in doubt and so I
take that like the fact that he says
that a lot and other friends and I'll
say that like I think that you know it's
something that okay that is potentially
a flaw that I'm to be aware of and so
now whenever I feel really strongly
about something you know I had to ask
myself like am i doing is this a box
situation or is this worth really
putting everything into
[Music]
sidenote
I don't love guns in fact I don't think
I've fired a gun since I was 17 years
old on a camping trip with friends out
in Joshua Tree just like you're shaking
I'm gonna get on this finger off the
trigger - hand grip just like that
remember you want to take your front
sight and put it in your rear sight
it'll look something like this just
glance up yeah right there you go nice
Bend to the knees
[Music]
I've heard you tell the story but maybe
you could retell it here about why now
is the time to take a stand and as a
company as a branch or get behind trying
to eliminate gun violence yeah
I mean I don't think it was I know it
was in a case of like determining now is
a good time and more a very visceral
spontaneous response to a tragedy that
happened close to my family so you know
I remember when parkland happened and
just in and watching the Parkland Kids
on the debate on CNN and just how just
like um how strong their voices were for
needing a change and having gun
legislation really looked at in a more
sensible way and I remember watching
that and thinking good for those kids
I support they do I signed up to get the
text messages you know that was that
then I remember hearing about the next
shooting and the next shooting and I
remember feeling a feeling of like this
is this is kind of like a really
horrible thing that's going on our
country but it never was a personal
thing to me it never was something like
oh I'm gonna go get involved in that
right and then in November 8th so you
know not that long ago there was a
shooting in Thousand Oaks which is about
2015 20 minutes for my house and I
didn't know about it cuz I had happened
that night and I was on my way to work
the next morning and my wife called me
and I was in the back of the uber
working on some emails kind of pretty
focused on work and so I answered the
phone and she's like really really
emotional and she says did you see the
news and I said no and she said there
was another shooting you know this time
it happened literally just down the
street from us and I'm not taking our
son to school today and I was like why
she was like I don't think it's safe
there was been shootings in schools
there was one in yoga studio there was
one in the synagogue like how do I know
that someone's not going to come in to
his preschool which is a Jewish
preschool and pull out a gun and I was
like well babe we don't you know
know that but you can't like you know
make every decision out of fear because
of this happened close to us and then I
started really understanding like where
she was was probably where a lot of
people were at this point because it had
gotten so many shootings that their
proximity was probably minutes from a
lot of people well it's just so
pervasive so ridiculous so so we so she
gets off the phone and she says to me
she says you know someone has to do
something about it and it was one of
these moments and I didn't even have
this moment when I started Tom's a lot
of people asked me when I started Tom's
like did you have like a Tiffany was
there like a vision was there note from
God like what was it that caused you to
go from like an entrepreneur or just
starting businesses to make money to
like I want to create a company to help
people it was actually like a creative
idea it could be interesting let's make
200 pairs let's see what happens in
experiments yes an experiment but this
moment is the moment that people been
asking about my whole life if I've had
and now I can say I did have it and that
was I got off the phone I shut my laptop
and I just knew that that someone was me
I didn't know why I didn't know how but
I knew that like I had a platform and
Tom's as my business had a reach that
could make a difference in this topic I
didn't know how exactly that I knew that
we needed to do something like because
at Tom's we have given so many shoes and
so many people their eyesight through
our sunglass program but we've been like
itching for the past couple years to do
something bigger to do something
different it didn't take a stand on
something and so it was already kind of
in my head like we need to do something
that is relevant to the issues of our
time and there was just all this is like
this is it like if there's a time let's
do it now
now it was incredibly inconvenient
because it was a week before Black
Friday and Cyber week our biggest sales
week of the year and it was also very
inconvenient because you know we our
business was not in a place where we
could just afford to give up sales to
dedicate all of our attention to and
again violence sure but I just knew that
this was something we had to do so I
sent an email to our board to my
partners to our CEO
and said guys like if not us who if not
now when you know that a great Jewish
proverb and and and over about three or
four days I convinced them that this you
know by no means I was convincing that
this would be great for business but I
knew that it would be the right thing
for our staff because that mean happened
so close like I think they were feeling
very much the same way my wife was and I
knew that it would be a way that it
would reengage a lot of the people who
maybe were with us in the beginning of
Tom's because we were truly an activist
brand and I think we started as an
activist brand we were very radical as
you said no one was doing this and then
six years later we were a big brand and
everyone was doing some form of giving
everyone jumped on the back and so this
would be a way to shock the system and
be like holy [\h__\h]
like toms is really going out there now
on a limb and and and I knew that we
needed to do that like something in my
gut just said this is what we need to do
and I knew we could be impactful because
I learned about some of the things that
were happening in the in the gun
violence space specifically I learned
about universal background checks and I
learned about that on day two and when I
learned about that I recognized okay
there is a very moderate non-political
because ninety percent of Americans are
in favor of universal background checks
way to approach this I want to go back
to when you approached the board about
yes because there might be some lessons
or nuggets there are other people who
are trying to you know maybe go against
the grain or buck the system or
something different
what kind of pushback did you get and
how hard did you have to wrestle like
did you have to talk about numbers I
think we're gonna lose this much but
it's worth it because or like did you
just have to say this was the right
thing to do I know what my gut yeah yeah
and guts don't really work real well
we're boards yeah so actually Financial
Partners so unpack that a little bit so
so others can learn sure same kind of I
think the the biggest thing was the
board questioned and I think they were
they were mistaken at first in thinking
that we did not have the right or there
was the or the credibility to play in
the space
so they basically said look there are
every town and March for our lives and
mothers demand action and amazing
nonprofits that have dedicated tens of
millions of dollars in years to trying
to have sensible gun legislation yeah
you are not a political person I'm not
at all like I didn't even know who Mitch
McConnell was when this started like I
mean that's how non-political I am so
like you're not political Tom's is not a
political brand like we've never done
anything about gun violence how do we go
from giving shoes to kids to take me
instead oh no it's like I just don't
understand how the customer is gonna
understand this and and and that was
their position and so they said like
personally we totally agree on this like
actually some of our board members are
really big donors to every town and
other organizations right but I just
don't think out Tom's shows up here well
and it does sound like a fair and
logical are yeah it was a good but my
argument back was Tom's is not a shoe
company we were a movement when we are
best and we exist for a better tomorrow
it's in our name it's a reason I started
Tom's I just use shoes for the last 12
years to fund the idea that we can
create a better tomorrow through and I
believe that if we take a stand and make
a big contribution which turned out to
be the largest contribution in the
history of the United States to this
issue that we can create a better and
safer tomorrow and that's the business
that were in
and so that's ultimately what I had to
convince him that our business was
bigger and it had a and and and had
permission to engage in a topic like
this even though it wasn't obvious like
when he looked at it on paper and I
think the only reason that I ultimately
want it was going back to the gut thing
which I say is not the thing I led with
because no one only has a good argument
but ultimately we had to look each other
in the eyes and I said guys you invested
in me and you supported me up into this
point and I've never in there because
I've been these partners for four years
I've never said we have to do anything
I've actually changed some of my ideas
and strategies and philosophies based on
your guidance I said but this is the
time I might be the only time where I'm
telling you
single thing in my body says we have to
do this now not only because it's the
right thing to do but it's because it
will re-engage Andry motivate this
movement and and I think that conviction
was stronger than their conviction of I
don't know if we can play here you went
to the mat way to the mat I love it yeah
I mean the first thing I heard about it
it's it struck a chord right away for
two reasons one because I've got kids
and and that's one of the main yeah it's
been on my mind constantly sure and the
other thing is about ten years ago I had
a gun violence experience where it was
right when I was starting my production
company we were in this small little
studio space was like 8 o'clock at night
four or five of us were in the office
just sort of editing I hear this loud
crash walked out front kind of the front
lobby area to figure out what it was
three really big guys all tatted up no
masks or anything come barreling in with
guns guns a-blazing the gun was put
right to my forehead told me that you
know get her out all of us into this
room put us kind of executions down on
the ground and for a minute I thought
okay I'm gone like I just sort of made
some generalizations like no no mask or
cover-up okay these guys don't care who
sees them does that mean I'm going to
die tonight yeah and I remember we kind
of look to each other on the ground
thinking should we do something I have
been fight for our life that or he was
cool and it was it was a moment of you
know very surreal the best way to
explain it sure but also terrifying but
at that moment I sort of felt calm like
just chill out and like yeah just let
them take what they're gonna take anyway
so and it was terrifying too because
they took my ID and they read it out
loud and they said you know my name and
the red off my driver's license my
address and if you call the police we're
coming to get you all that good stuff
and it's like oh you know I was heavy
but you know so ever since you know that
was a moment every time I see one of
these shootings happen or you know I
sort of think about that and I think how
terrifying it is and how awful it is
that
this is still such a big problem in the
United States yeah and I'm so happy you
know signed up on the site I went you
know did my post card right thank you so
tell us what the vision is yes so you're
now gonna go in this sort of caravan
right yes yeah it's wrapped and I mean
so yeah so we recognized with this idea
that universal background checks was a
very simple very moderate kind of the
least political polarizing part of the
ending gun violence initiatives a good
place to start yeah because it basically
keeps felons from buying guns yeah
people who are domestic abusers and
people have mental health issues like
that's it like if you're not one of
those three then you will pass your
background check and you can buy a gun
yeah but that was three contribute to a
lot of gun violence and so especially
the the felons aspect and so one of the
things that we recognize is everything
that this was going to be legislation
that would be presented in the house in
2019 and the only way that it would get
passed in a bipartisan way which is
going to potentially allow it to become
a law is if Americans in every state and
every territory made their voices heard
hey I'm a proud gun owner but I'm also a
father to a young son and I don't want
him going to school scared so if you're
like me you're like 90% of other
Americans who want universal background
checks I just saw a statistic that said
there were 307 mass shootings in the
last 311 days in our country which is
terrifying and devastating and as a
proud gun owner myself that's a right
and a privilege that I take very very
serious as I know a lot of you guys do
too but I think we can all come together
and all agree that something has to
change it's unacceptable we shouldn't
have to walk out of the house and live
in fear anymore
so let's come together as a country
let's do our part Tom's is doing a
really cool campaign right now to raise
awareness for universal background
checks and I know there's a lot of
factors that's going to go into really
making some change but this is an easy
thing that we can all do and when I
spoke to different people because I had
no political background at all I said
what can we do what can TOMS do I'm
gonna we're gonna get five million
dollars largest contribution ever to
these nonprofits but what can we
actually do to to effect
the politics of this and one of the
people that I was speaking to he said
postcards
he says old-fashioned postcards he says
when those representatives get a lot of
postcards and they're from people in
their constituency they listen so I just
had this vision of Miracle on 34th
Street where they come in and they pour
all the envelopes
yeah from Santa is that the intention
yeah that's the intention so what we
started with was we built a simple
technology on the website on the home
page during Black Friday and Cyber week
so we gave up a lot of sales to have
this as the main real estate and in 30
seconds or less and still today for the
next couple weeks you can still do it I
did it is yeah yeah you go to the
website you put in your name and address
it's all basically turned it's super
simple so in 30 seconds you can do it so
we've had seven hundred and sixteen
thousand Americans and yourself do post
cars that's I mean phenomenal I mean
that's a massive amount of people to
speak out so clearly about something
well and so quickly yeah and so in eight
weeks yeah you mobilised yeah almost a
million people in eight weeks that's it
that we did without any marketing either
I mean this all happened virally like we
were literally I launched it on Jimmy
Fallon and he sent the first postcard
which helped because then 50,000 people
did it immediately yeah
but then from those 50,000 it just grew
and and so we'll talk about signals I
mean that's that's a signal right yeah
like the people of spoken Cantus yeah
and so now what and I'd take no
responsibility for this great idea this
was the this was the creative team at
Tom's they said you know what to send
716 thousand postcards is gonna cost us
you know like a quarter of a million
dollars what if we drove all those
postcards across the country in
hand-deliver them to the 500
representatives in Congress that would
be more impactful and it would cost us
less money yeah that's it and you create
a spectacle yeah and so that's what
we're doing so we launched it today on
the tours gonna go on for about two and
a half weeks we're gonna be in
Washington DC February 5th and so if
you're watching this right now and you
want to come join us please do we hope
that there'll be thousands of volunteers
that will help us hand-deliver these
postcards on February 5th and and we
believe because that's gonna be about
two to three weeks before the vote so we
believe that
we'll be a really important indicator
and an influence on many of the votes
that will happen for universal
background checks that's amazing it's
been fun well of course so we're going
to have support
[Music]